<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-20T16:50:12-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Split Face vs Honed – What’s the difference when it comes to Stone Veneer?</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/split-face-vs-honed-stone-veneer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Split Face vs Honed – What's the difference when it comes to Stone Veneer?" /><published>2018-07-19T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/split-face-vs-honed-what-s-the-difference-when-it-comes-to-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/split-face-vs-honed-stone-veneer/">&lt;p&gt;One of the really cool things about working in the natural stone world is that the stone itself is really just one of many elements that we get to play with when designing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt;.  Size and shape, how the product gets assembled, and how the product gets installed are just some of the variables that dictate how a product ends up looking when it gets on your wall.  One of the most noticeable ways that the look of natural stone can be changed is by how its finished, and the two most common finishes in the Stone Veneer world are split face and honed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Split Face generally refers to products that have either been quarried or mechanically split using machines to create a rough hewn surface that shows off the natural cleft of the stone.  Depending on the type of stone that is being worked, the end result can vary from a slightly smoother finished surface on  a more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/quartz-ledgestone-vs-countertop/&quot;&gt;quartz based stone&lt;/a&gt;, to a more inconsistent and cratered look on stones like limestone and sandstone.  Natural stone splits along the cleavage layers and most of the time it can end up being fairly flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/20/Split Face Stone Veneer Backsplash.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Split Face Stone Veneer in Aztec Color used on a Kitchen Backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Split face finishes might tend to be associated with more traditional looking stone applications and colors, sometimes even described as “rustic”.  Traditional stone colors that have been used in building such as greys, browns, and tans are quite common when it comes to split face stone veneers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/20/Split Face Stone Veneer Lobby.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Split Face Stacked Stone Rock Panels used on the entrance lobby reception desk of a concert hall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Norstone &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-slim-line-budget-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Slim Line Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; are the products in our current offering that have a split face finish.  You’ll find the traditional earth tone colors in these collections, but one of the things that we think allows these products to stand apart is some unique color offerings in split face like our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;White&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt; Ivory&lt;/a&gt; Panels, as well as a very design oriented approach to assembling the panels, which creates clean lines and puts a modern twist on a classic stone look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honed finishes are also an incredibly popular finish in the world of stone veneer.  Honed means that the stone itself has been cut at a gauged thickness and then polished to varying degrees of smoothness.  On the spectrum of polishing, honed normally means a very light polish, resulting in a stone surface that is smooth to the touch, but not glossy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/20/Honed Stone Veneer Modern Wall Panel in Bathroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Honed Aksent Series Modern Stone Veneer Wall Panels in Ash Grey color used on a bathroom backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honed finishes are currently most synonymous with modern design that embraces big open spaces and smooth surfaces like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;glass, concrete, and steel&lt;/a&gt;.  Since honed finishes are just cut and polished and not mechanically split the way split face veneers are, they tend to be available in pretty much any color that stone can be sourced in.  Honed finishes do require more labor and therefore often times are more expensive than split face veneers made from the same stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/20/Honed Stone Veneer Modern Wall Panel Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Honed Modern Aksent Series Stone Veneer in Ebony Color installed vertically on a two story feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Norstone’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc Series&lt;/a&gt; are all honed finishes.  Aiming right at the modern design inspired project, the colors in these series fall mainly in the black, white, and grey range.  A new color, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/beige-marble-veneer/&quot;&gt;Beige&lt;/a&gt;, was released in the Fall of 2017 in the Aksent and Lynia Series which also brings in the neutral tan colors that continue to be widely accepted in interior design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for learning more about the difference between Split Face and Honed Finishes in the world of natural stone veneer.  Probably the most important thing to remember is to keep your options open when considering projects for your next stone veneer project as you might happen upon a combination of stone color, size, pattern and most importantly finish that works just perfect for your project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">When it comes to stone veneer, the difference between split face vs honed is akin to the difference between porcelain vs ceramic tile or granite vs quartz counter tops. There are a lot more similarities than differences! Let's take a deep dive at these two surface finishes and what makes each one great!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/07/20/Split%20Face%20Stone%20Veneer%20Backsplash.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Split%20Face%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20a%20Kitchen%20Backsplash%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Light%20colored%20split%20face%20stone%20veneer%20used%20on%20a%20kitchen%20backsplash%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern Stone Outdoor Kitchen and Firepit with a Cool Blue Hue</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stone-outdoor-kitchen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern Stone Outdoor Kitchen and Firepit with a Cool Blue Hue" /><published>2018-07-17T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stone-outdoor-kitchen-and-firepit-with-a-cool-blue-hue</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stone-outdoor-kitchen/">&lt;p&gt;We’re always excited to see photos come back from our clients, and the project featured in this week’s blog is no exception.  The product used is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/ebony/&quot;&gt;Aksent Series panel in the Ebony color&lt;/a&gt;.  The Aksent panel is a newer product to our line up, and is a modern twist on the traditional split face stacked stone cladding panels that we’ve been making for close to 15 years.  With a honed face, blocky geometry, and  clean lines the Aksent panel leans toward modern design.  The Ebony color, which we also make in Lynia Interlocking Tiles and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Wall Cladding&lt;/a&gt;, is the darkest stone in our line up, and as such is a very bold combination which we were excited to see used in an outdoor application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/19/Norstone Modern Stone Panel Outdoor Kitchen Grill Island.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent Modern Stone Cladding in Ebony Color on an Outdoor Kitchen with large stainless steel grill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two distinct features on this project that received the Aksent modern stone wall cladding – an “L” shaped outdoor kitchen and a square low slung fire pit.  No expense was spared on this outdoor kitchen with the stone being used on the front face as well as on the interior wall sections.  Something that is subtle to most people, but really stands out to us is how awesome the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;finger jointed stone outside corner units&lt;/a&gt; worked in this application.  As the stone turns the outside corners as it moves from the front face to the inside face of the outdoor kitchen the look is incredibly seamless.  Kudos to the installation team on this project for a great job not only on the corners, but on the multiple cut outs along the grill, refrigerator and other stainless steel doors on the inside wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/19/Norstone Modern Stone Panel Firepit.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent Modern Stone Cladding in Ebony Color on a low slung square outdoor gas firepit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fire pit is also a really nice feature, and the use of the same Ebony Aksent stone really helps create a consistent design them in this space.  The low slung design of this fire pit and the fact that its a gas unit is more suited for creating a nice ambiance when the sun goes down versus putting out much heat, and is perfect for facilitating conversation over the flames.  The durability of the stone makes it a perfect choice to mesh in with the hardscape of the pool deck and stand up to years and years of feet leaning against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, the Ebony color is a bold choice for any project, which was flawlessly executed here.  The dark color of the stone works matches nicely with the dark colored stone counter top and is a nice complement to the stainless steel grill and other fixtures in terms of smoothness while still contrasting color wise.  From a color standpoint, the two biggest color splashes in this project, the light natural stone of the outdoor paver deck and the dark color of the Ebony modern stone wall cladding foil each other wonderfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you thought a light / dark stone color combination was a little boring, this project hits you with an unexpected dash of blue, both in the glass media of the fire pit……&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/19/Norstone Modern Stone Panel Gas Firepit.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent Modern Stone Cladding in Ebony Color on a gas firepit with bright blue glass media&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some cool LED light strips mounted to underneath the counter tops that cast a cool blue hue across the stone.  While not every space can make bold color choices like this project has, we love when someone is willing to take the leap to design and build something that speaks to them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/07/19/Norstone Modern Stone Panel Outdoor Kitchen with LED Lighting.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent Modern Stone Cladding in Ebony Color on an Outdoor Kitchen with undermounted blue LED lighting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outdoor living areas are one of the hottest growth segments in home renovation and one of a handful of spaces in your home where you can gain positive return on your investment dollars if done correctly.  Long the bastion of more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/&quot;&gt;traditional looking split face stone&lt;/a&gt;, we’re excited to see clients like this one taking a bold step and working with smooth faced materials outdoors.  Thanks to our client for sharing their super cool project with us and if this project inspired you to think about an outdoor kitchen project of your own, contact one of our design experts today to learn more about why stone is a great choice and how it can best be used for your specific project.  Until then, cheers to the last couple months of summer and catch me at this fire pit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">One of our awesome customers just finished their outdoor kitchen and firepit project earlier this month and were so excited with how it turned out they couldn't wait to get these photos to us. We share their stoke and proudly feature this project on this week's blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/07/19/Norstone%20Modern%20Stone%20Panel%20Outdoor%20Kitchen%20Grill%20Island.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Modern%20Stone%20Outdoor%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Aksent%20Ebony%20Modern%20Stone%20Paneling%20used%20on%20an%20outdoor%20kitchen%20with%20large%20Stainless%20Steel%20grill%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Stacked Stone in Outdoor Living Spaces</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-for-outdoor-living/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Stacked Stone in Outdoor Living Spaces" /><published>2018-06-26T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/using-stacked-stone-in-outdoor-living-spaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-for-outdoor-living/">&lt;p&gt;Outdoor living space is another one of the buzzwords in home design and improvement that gets thrown around a lot.  While outdoor spaces like decks and patios have been around since the post war housing boom, the key change over the last several decade or so is really focusing on creating spaces that are comfortable and that you want to spend time in, hence the term “outdoor living”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stone of all types is a great product to be used for outdoor living spaces because of its durability and natural aesthetic that fits the space.  Let’s take a look at a few ways stacked stone can be used in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;outdoor living spaces&lt;/a&gt; that will add beauty to any space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/27/Stacked Stone Fireplace in Outdoor Living Space.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Stacked Stone used as the surround on a large outdoor fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outdoor fireplaces and fire pits are a great choice for&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt; stacked stone&lt;/a&gt;.  Stacked stone looks great on fireplaces indoors and looks especially awesome on outdoor fireplaces as well where the natural stone element of the finish really shines through.  Whether you’ve got a lot of open space for a large fire pit surrounded by stacked stone, or a small corner with a wood or gas burning unit, fire places add ambiance to any setting and a great addition to an outdoor living space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/27/Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen in Outdoor Living Space.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels used in a large outdoor kitchen with pizza oven&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living outdoors wouldn’t be complete with food, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/&quot;&gt;outdoor kitchens&lt;/a&gt; make up our next option for how stacked stone can be used in outdoor living spaces.  With outdoor kitchens ranging the gamut from something as simple as a grill and a sink to kitchens that put most home kitchens to shame, complete with refrigeration, dishwashers and even fancy add ons like pizza ovens, these spaces offer many unique opportunities to use stacked stone.  Depending on the configuration, back splashes are a common use for stacked stone, as is the face or sometimes the entire base of grill islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/27/Stacked Stone Water Feature in Outdoor Living Space.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used on the spillway of a large outdoor water feature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water Features are another awesome way to use stacked stone in an exterior space.  Stacked stone water features like the one seen here are great because they not only are always very visually appealing, they also create sound which excites another sense and adds to the overall desirability of the outdoor living space.  Many years ago we actually used to make a portable water feature unit that was about two feet wide and 5 feet tall that was ideal for balconies, so no matter how small the space, there’s always a way to add some ambiance with stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/27/Stacked Stone Feature Wall in Outdoor Living Space.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used as a feature wall in a modern designed outdoor space with reflecting pond&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, a well placed stone feature wall is always a great way to enhance an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor living space&lt;/a&gt;.  Whether the stacked stone wall is being used for its color, texture, or placement, it affords the space the opportunity to create a focal point and add to or reinforce the other design elements.  We especially love the Charcoal feature wall shown here as it subtly does so many things.  From a color standpoint, the dark grey of the Charcoal contrasts nicely with the smooth stucco walls while at the same time complementing the dark teak flooring and vibrant greenery.  From a texture standpoint, the stone is designed to contrast the smooth surfaces surrounding it, including the walls, flooring, sheet glass water feature and even the smooth pebble borders around the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve already got an outdoor living space and are looking to add a cool feature like stacked stone to take it to the next level, or if you are staring at a blank space in your backyard and just starting to consider the possibilities, I urge you to spend some time looking at our photo galleries of exterior stone projects for inspiration.  The outdoors is always calling, so answer it this summer with stacked stone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Outdoor living spaces are a booming trend in home design. If you've got the space – use it, but most importantly make it useful and beautiful. Let's take a look at how stacked stone can enhance any outdoor space.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/27/Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall%20in%20Outdoor%20Living%20Space.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall%20in%20Outdoor%20Living%20Space%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall%20in%20an%20contemporary%20outdoor%20living%20space%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern White Stone in Minneapolis Condo Loft</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-white-stone-condo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern White Stone in Minneapolis Condo Loft" /><published>2018-06-25T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-25T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-white-stone-in-minneapolis-condo-loft</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-white-stone-condo/">&lt;p&gt;Several years ago our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;White Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; were used on a very cool condo loft project in Minneapolis, Minnesota.  This space has some very interesting stone design elements to it, including the vertical &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/&quot;&gt;installation of the stone panels&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a unique take on how to use stacked stone panels on a column.  Come with us on a quick tour around this unique space to see what it makes it so cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the space itself is concerned, the term “loft” when used to describe a multifamily apartment or condo building has become overused over the past several years.  The fundamental design it tries to convey is a large open space with great natural light, high ceilings, that are typically on one floor of a multi level building.  The original “loft” style buildings were re-purposed factories and industrial buildings in cities like New York, that were often in less desirable neighborhoods with lower rents that attracted artists that popularized the open concept design.  Today, many new construction buildings are designed along these same ideals, maximizing ceiling height, open space and natural light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/26/Norstone White Stacked Stone Panels Condo Loft Column Vertical Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels installed vertically on a column in a modern themed condo set against a kitchen with dark cabinets and brown concrete stained floors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things that catches our eye on this installation is the modern color pallete.  The white stone feature walls flanking the entry foyer combined with the freshly painted white walls dominate the space, adding to the already open and bright feel.  What we really like though is the English leather brown color of the stained concrete floors. While the design team opted for lots of black accents throughout the space, including the baseboards, cabinets and doors, a darker colored floor would really amp up the modern feel of the space and start to limit potential resale value.  In addition to reinforcing the light colors of the design scheme, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;White Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; also are a great contrast in texture as compared to the smoothness of the rest of the finishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/26/Norstone White Stacked Stone Panels Condo Loft Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels on two feature walls flanking the entryway in a modern designed condo loft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vertically installing the stone panels is another very unique aspect of this project.  A vertical installation, where the 24” side of our rock panels are run vertically, accentuates the height of any space and also lends itself towards a more modern look. Furniture that is low to the ground and the large art piece that is resting on the floor keep your eyes towards the ground which also helps make the ceilings feel taller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/26/Norstone White Stacked Stone Panels Condo Loft Feature Wall with Downlighting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels installed vertically with downlighting to accentuate ceiling height and the texture of the stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve talked before about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;how lighting is an important part of a stone installation&lt;/a&gt;, and were very happy to see the overheard recessed light strips on the two main stone feature walls of this space.  The White Rock Panels, because of their color, can look a fair bit different depending on the type of light being cast on them.  The ultra pure white LED down lighting used in this installation does a great job of creating a dramatic effect and highlighting the texture of the stone feature wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/26/Norstone White Stacked Stone Panels Condo Loft Feature Wall and Column Showing Texture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels installed vertically on a column leaving the long edge open on the outside corners for a modern look&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing that catches our eye on this project is the super unique way the design and installation team decided to wrap the interior column.  Our stone veneer corner units are designed to be installed with a traditional horizontal orientation, so in keeping with the vertical orientation of the feature wall, the rock panels were installed on the column leaving the long cut edge of the panel exposed at the corner.  The drawback of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-columns-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;installing stone on a column&lt;/a&gt; like this is that it doesn’t “hide” the fact that the stone used on the walls and column is a veneer as opposed to a full bed stone, however it does give the column a very modern clean lined look which does fit nicely with the rest of the design cues of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick tour of this unique condo loft space in the upper Midwest.  We hope it inspires you to take some risk with your next stacked stone project and incorporate some of the design ideas talked about today.  Speaking of design, we have in house design experts ready to talk to you about using natural stone wall coverings for your next project, so don’t hesitate to contact us today to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This project caught our eye, and not just because it was used in a rap video! Tall ceilings, vertical installation, this loft has got it all going on! Let's take a closer look in this week's project profile to see what make this space special.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/26/Norstone%20White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Panels%20Condo%20Loft%20Feature%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Walls%20in%20Condo%20Loft%20Entryway%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Walls%20with%20stone%20installed%20vertically%20and%20down%20lighting%20flanking%20entryway%20of%20condo%20loft%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Large Format Tile in a Small Kitchen Backsplash</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/large-format-tile-small-kitchen-backsplash/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Large Format Tile in a Small Kitchen Backsplash" /><published>2018-06-20T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-20T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/using-large-format-tile-in-a-small-kitchen-backsplash</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/large-format-tile-small-kitchen-backsplash/">&lt;p&gt;When most people think of large format tile the first thing that comes to mind is flooring.  In fact, throughout the 1980s, 90s, and early 2000s one of the biggest changes in the tile industry was tile sizes getting larger and larger.  12X12s gave way to 18x18s, 24x24s, 36x36s and so on.  Innovative companies are keeping the quest for bigger being better alive and well with precision manufactured porcelain products that can be sized up to 1 meter x 3 meters while only being a few millimeters thick, creating a covering that is tile but behaves almost like a skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Increasing Tile Sizes Through The Year.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo showing increasing sizes in tile throughout the years&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tile industry has now embraced shape and patterns as equal cornerstones of good design and we’re seeing rectangles and planks as well as patterns that range from traditional herringbone and parquets to intricate multi size and shape tile patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something we’re very proud of is our recently released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;PLANC large format wall tile collection&lt;/a&gt;.  As floor tile was getting bigger, wall tile was staying relatively small, with mosaics dominating the design trends on areas like kitchen backsplashes.  We set out to prove that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;large format tiles&lt;/a&gt; have a place in any wall tile project, and this cozy corner kitchen backsplash is a perfect example of how a large format tile can work nicely in a small space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone Planc Platinum  Large Format Tile Kitchen Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc tiles in platinum on a dodern kitchen with white countertops, white cabinets, and a small island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a scaling standpoint, each of the Plancs on this backsplash are 31.5” long, and come in three heights (5.5”, 3.1”, and 2.4”).  Like most &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/backsplash-tile-designs-norstone-industy-series/&quot;&gt;current kitchen backsplashes&lt;/a&gt;, this one has about 18” of wall space between the top of the countertop and bottom of the upper cabinet, which a you can see in the head on photo of the sink, allows for about six courses of the Planc stone to be set.  The courses in this installation were set in a random staggered pattern, creating a pattern that complements the different heights and creates a lot of visual interest in this small space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone Large Format Tile Planc Kitchen Backsplash Platinum Color.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Straight on look at Norstone PLANC tile used in a small kitchen backsplash showing the pattern and coursing of the tile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a color standpoint, the grey color pallete of the Platinum is extremely appealing to modern design.  This kitchen, with its white marble counter tops and white cabinets creates a great contrasting look with the neutral grey tones.  But what makes this product really appealing is the amazing surface characteristics that make it unmistakable that this is a natural stone.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/&quot;&gt;Lava Stone&lt;/a&gt; that this product is made from ranges from a smooth saw cut finish with tight graining to consistently honeycombed appearance with lots of surface divots.  What we actually love the most though is the occasional vein of honeycombing that shows up every now and then giving the product a natural stone look that just can’t be beat.  An installer with a keen eye, like the team that worked on this project, can use these veins to their advantage by lining up the veins from one course to the next for a true handcrafted look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone Planc Large Format Tile Kitchen Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cozy Corner kitchen in Florida with great natural light accentuating the look of the Norstone PLANC large format tile used on the backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing we love about this project is the great use of natural light in the space.  The open concept of the space brings in natural light from every angle, but especially the prominent window in the corner.  Natural light brings out the best in everything in the space, color, texture, and scale wise, making sure the large Planc tiles on the backsplash don’t feel too dark and big for the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this cool project with us and seeing how a large format tile like Norstone PLANC can work in even the smallest of spaces.  In addition to interiors, most colors in the PLANC collection can be used exterior and in water applications as well making this one of the most versatile &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone products&lt;/a&gt; in our line up.  Reach out to us today to learn more about how PLANC might be a good fit for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our new PLANC large format tiles are a lot more versatile than you might think. Check out this nifty kitchen backsplash installation that used our Platinum Plancs and turned out great!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Planc%20Kitchen%20Backsplash%20Platinum%20Color.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20PLANC%20tile%20on%20kitchen%20backsplash%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20PLANC%20large%20format%20tile%20in%20Platinum%20color%20used%20the%20backsplash%20of%20a%20modern%20kitchen%20with%20white%20countertops%20and%20white%20cabinets.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Interior Stacked Stone Projects to Beat the Heat this Summer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/5-stacked-stone-projects-for-summer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Interior Stacked Stone Projects to Beat the Heat this Summer" /><published>2018-06-20T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-20T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/5-interior-stacked-stone-projects-to-beat-the-heat-this-summer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/5-stacked-stone-projects-for-summer/">&lt;p&gt;For those of us who love to renovate, summer time is the perfect time of the year to tackle some small interior projects.  With the heat of the summer bearing down on us interior projects offer a respite from the heat outside and since many interior renovation projects are smaller in nature, they also can be easier to fit in while juggling holidays and vacations.  So this week we decided to pay homage to summer and compile a list of 5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/interiors/&quot;&gt;interior stacked stone projects&lt;/a&gt; you might consider to make a big impact on your space without a big commitment of time or money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone White Rock Panel Entryway.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Stacked Stone White Rock Panels used in the entryway of an upscale loft condo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to spiff up your home, a good place to start is the entryway or foyer.  It’s what you and your guests see and experience every time the threshold is crossed and is a good opportunity to set the tone for your home.  A few years ago a customer in Minnesota was working on a loft condo and used our White Rock Panels to flank the front door on both sides.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/&quot;&gt;stone was installed in a vertical orientation&lt;/a&gt; and has some great spot lighting that really accentuates the color and texture the stone provides.  The pure white color complements the modern minimalist design aesthetic of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone Ochre Stacked Stone Powder Room Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Stacked Stone Ochre Rock Panel Feature Wall in a Powder Bath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powder rooms are another great small summertime project.  Since the space is generally pretty small to begin with you can make a big impact with a small amount of stone on the wall.  A few things to consider with powder rooms is the plumbing attachments and how the vanity and mirror will be attached to the wall.  Lighting is also important in small spaces like powder rooms, so consider lighter color stones like White and Ivory if good natural light or sufficient artificial lights isn’t available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone Charcoal Stacked Stone Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Stacked Stone Charcoal Rock Panels on a modern backsplash with a glass splatter guard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;Kitchen backsplashes&lt;/a&gt; are probably the small tiling project most people think of.  As we’ve seen before, stacked stone rock panels are a unique option for an outside the box backsplash.  Whether the design scheme is mountain rustic using Ochre Blend color, or a more contemporary look like the Charcoal backsplash seen here, stacked stone not only serves as a very durable backsplash material, but also one that will have you and your guests talking about for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone White Stacked Stone Stairway Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Stacked Stone White Rock Panels run vertically on stair case&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stair Landings are usually one of the most uninspiring areas of a home, serving more as a way to get people from one place to the other and not really a place people care too much about.  The reality though is that stairs are often centrally located in homes and with the prevalence of high ceilings in today’s new construction stair landings and stair ways are more in view than ever.  The height alone makes this type of project one of the harder ones on our list, but as you can see adding stacked stone to a staircase or stair landing can make a huge impact on the space.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Lighting is probably the most important consideration&lt;/a&gt; for a tall project like a stairway – after all you want to make sure you can see what’s on the wall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone Ochre Stacked Stone Bar Project.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Stacked Stone Ochre Rock Panels used for accents on a basement bar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least is some people’s favorite spot in their entire home, that being the bar, that completes our list of interior stacked stone projects to tackle this summer.  Whether your bar has enough room for you and the rest of the football team in your basement or man cave, or just a simple wet bar in the corner of the kitchen, adding a stacked stone accent wall or mini backsplash can really elevate the space without a huge time or financial commitment to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope these projects inspire you to beat the heat this summer and look around your home for a small interior project you can tackle.  Before we know it the evenings will start to get just a little fresher, the leaves will get some color, but until then you friends at Norstone urge you to stay cool and think stone during the Summer of 2018!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">If the heat of the summer has got you dreading stepping outside the A/C these 5 interior stacked stone projects might help you beat the heat and make your house more beautiful at the same time!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/21/Norstone%20Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Powder%20Room%20Feature%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Interior%20Stacked%20Stone%20Projects%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Small%20Powder%20Room%20with%20a%20stacked%20stone%20feature%20wall%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Installing Norstone Stone Veneer with a Vertical Orientation</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing Norstone Stone Veneer with a Vertical Orientation " /><published>2018-06-04T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-stone-veneer-with-a-vertical-orientation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Traditional stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; has what we refer to as a horizontal orientation, meaning the longest dimension of any piece of stone is going to be set parallel to the ground.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Rock Panel system&lt;/a&gt; took that traditional concept one step further in that the panels themselves were designed to be 6” tall and 24” long, with all the stones that made up each of the panels also adhering to the same philosophy with the longest dimension coming along the 24” axis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we soon found out was that when you put great products in the hands of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-spec-build/&quot;&gt;amazing architects and designers&lt;/a&gt; you’ll learn things about the product that you might had never considered before, such as changing the orientation of our product from horizontal to vertical.  Specifically, that meant installing our Rock Panels with the 6” dimension running horizontally and the 24” dimension running vertically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone White Stacked Stone Rock Panels Vertical Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels installed vertically on commercial signage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first times we saw our stacked stone rock panels get used in a vertical orientation was in the photo above which is at the entrance to a law office in Charlotte, NC.  We were just getting started and had only been selling the product in the United States for less than a year and it really blew our minds that a product that we thought we knew so well could end up looking so different by simply rotating it 90 degrees during the installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond just wanting to subtly change the look of an installation by opting for a vertical orientation, there are also a handful of technical or design related reasons to adopt a vertical orientation for a specific installation.  These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vertically Oriented Rock Panels can be used on a tighter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/&quot;&gt;concave radius wall&lt;/a&gt; than a traditional horizontal orientation.  For radius work, the primary variables to consider is the measurement of the radius itself, or simply how curved the wall is, and the horizontal dimension of the wall covering that is meant to go around the radius.  By switching to a vertical orientation the 6” dimension of our panel products becomes the horizontal dimension and can easily be wrapped into tight concave radius walls like the circular stair landing shown here.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone White Stacked Stone Rock Panels Vertical Radius Wall Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels installed on a tight concave radius wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From a design standpoint, a vertical orientation of a stacked stone product provides much the	same effect as vertical stripes in accentuating the height of a space.  So if you have a space with low ceilings, like a basement man cave, vertically orienting stacked stone rock panels will help that space feel taller.  On the opposite end of the spectrum, running rock panels vertically can serve to draw attention to an already high ceiling, making it truly the focal point of a space by drawing eyes upward.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone Aksent Honed Veneer Panels Installed Vertically on Exterior.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Panels installed vertically on the exterior of a bank designed to accentuate the height of the design feature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main drawbacks to consider with a vertically oriented installation of stacked stone is how outside corners will work.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;corner units&lt;/a&gt; are designed to work along the 24” axis of the panels, so if the orientation is changed they will no longer line up against a vertical outside corner.  If a project does require corners the best option is probably a pre-fabricated corner unit designed for tile or perhaps even a simple but join as seen in the photo below.  Miter cuts could be made along the 24” axis, but would likely require a production level wet saw to make such a specialized cut along such a long dimension and it will also be difficult to keep some of the smaller stones together during the miter cut process, likely requiring some hand setting of small final pieces along a miter cut corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone Aksent Honed Veneer Panels Vertical Orientation on Columns.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Askent 3D Panels installed on short columns using a simple but join corner in lieu of a miter or pre fabricated corner unit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vertical orientation doesn’t make sense for every stacked stone veneer project, but its definitely worth considering if you have the right space, corners won’t be an issue, and the design aesthetic leans more towards modern.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Sometimes a simple change, like installing our Rock Panels with a vertical orientation can yield a big change in the overall look of a product. In this week's blog post we discuss more about this installation scheme and why it might make sense for your next project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone%20Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Rock%20Panels%20Vertical%20Curved%20Wall.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Rock%20Panels%20Installed%20on%20a%20Vertical%20Orientation%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ochre%20Blend%20Rock%20Panels%20installed%20on%20a%20vertical%20orientation%20on%20an%20exterior%20convex%20radius%20wall%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jaw Dropping Views of More than Just Norstone in the Seychelle Islands</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-views-seychelle-islands-africa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jaw Dropping Views of More than Just Norstone in the Seychelle Islands" /><published>2018-06-03T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/jaw-dropping-views-of-more-than-just-norstone-in-the-seychelle-islands</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-views-seychelle-islands-africa/">&lt;p&gt;When we first heard about our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;stacked stone rock panels&lt;/a&gt; being used for a project in the Seychelle Islands the first thing we had to do was go and look up where that even was.  It was then we first learned about this little known group of islands that sits off the Eastern Coast of Africa, north of Madagascar and a little over 900 miles off the coast of mainland Africa.  In a part of the Indian Ocean that is perhaps most synonymous with modern day piracy, the Seychelle Islands have a unique beauty unto themselves and are a place that we wouldn’t mine being marooned at for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes the Seychelle Islands incredibly unique, and in turn brought about the use of our Charcoal Stacked Stone Panel on this project, is that most of the islands in the Seychelles are actually made of granite.  This is incredibly unique and unlike most other tropical islands which tend to either be based on coral, such as the Maldives, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/&quot;&gt;basaltic lava stone&lt;/a&gt; like Hawaii and Fiji.  Turns out the Seychelles were actually part of an ancient super continent and have been separated from the rest of the continents for about 75 million years!  However it’s explained, we find it pretty remarkable that you’ll find similar granite formations in this tropical paradise as you will in the rolling hills of Wisconsin or the famous domes of Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/05/Norstone Charcoal Stacked Stone Rock Panels with Granite Domes in Background Seychelle Islands Africa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used on a resort in the Seychelle Islands in Africa with Granite Domes in the background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design team on this project was incredibly focused on blending the architecture of the buildings into the granite outcroppings, and were especially keen on using a color palette that blended with the granite formations.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; product was chosen for its dark gray tones that blend in so nicely with the granite domes that rise above the tropical fauna and are magnificent in their own right.  The darker color scheme of the stone also works incredibly well with the rich browns from the tropical hardwood beams and flooring throughout the project and is a nice accent against the lush greenscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/05/Norstone Charcoal Stacked Stone Rock Panels Seychelle Islands Africa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stunning view of a Norstone Stacked Stone Feature Wall with a unique circular cut out in the Seychelle Islands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture and view we have a hard time taking our eyes off of is this incredible balcony.  The Charcoal Rock Panels create great texture on the wall and the clean lines of our Standard Series Rock Panel works well in this modern inspired architecture, but the real award goes to the design team’s idea to put a circular cut out in this wall.  The view through the cut out frames beautiful granite formations, a smaller island off in the distance, and ocean so blue that you think you’re dreaming.  And even with absolutely breathtaking views in all directions, the uniqueness of this architectural feature undoubtedly draws everyone’s eye and frames the very essence of what makes this place special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while it doesn’t showcase any of our stacked stone panels, the view from this balcony is precisely what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;infinity edge pools&lt;/a&gt; were made for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/05/Infinity Edge Pool Seychelle Islands Africa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Infinity Edge Pool Under Construction with an incredible view in the Seychelle Islands Africa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re day dreaming with us from the confines of your cubicle or on the way to install your next stone veneer project, thanks for taking a quick mind vacation with us to the coast of Africa and seeing what makes the Seychelle Islands so special, and how the design team did a magnificent job capturing all of those things in one view of a stacked stone feature wall.  Even if you don’t have a view like this, or granite formations in your backyard, we’d love to talk with you about any of our ledge stone and smooth faced stone veneer panels and tiles.  Call today or fill out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; for more information and to request a sample or quote.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This project in the Seychelle Islands off the Eastern Coast of Africa has always been a favorite of ours. We get to see our products in a lot of truly extraordinary places all over the world, but none are as stunningly gorgeous as this one. Come take a closer look at this beautiful project and location in this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/05/Norstone%20Charcoal%20Stacked%20Stone%20Rock%20Panels%20Seychelle%20Islands%20Africa.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Rock%20Panel%20Feature%20Wall%20Seychelle%20Islands%20Africa%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Rock%20Panels%20on%20a%20Feature%20Wall%20in%20the%20Seychelles%20with%20a%20circular%20cut%20out%20showing%20granite%20formations%20and%20another%20Island%20in%20the%20distance%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Volcanoes are bad, but Lava Stone Rocks!</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Volcanoes are bad, but Lava Stone Rocks!" /><published>2018-05-21T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/volcanoes-are-bad-but-lava-stone-rocks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/">&lt;p&gt;The eruption of the Kilauea volcano on the big island of Hawaii has been front page news for several days, with captivating photos of streams of lava snaking across the countryside.  Our hearts go out to the great people of Hawaii, some of whom have had their lives turned upside down.  Seeing all the lava flow on tv reminds us of the Lava Stone that we make some of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;Planc Series large format tiles&lt;/a&gt; with, so we wanted to take a look this week at what exactly Lava Stone is and isn’t, and why it makes a great building material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/22/Kilauea Lava Flow May 2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arial View of the Lava Flowing from the Kilauea volcano in Hawaii in May 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first started considering using Lava Stone to make our natural stone tile and veneer products, one of the first questions we wanted to get answered was what makes Lava Stone different than Basalt?  Having worked with Basalt for almost a decade, starting with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt;, and more recently in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Stone Veneer&lt;/a&gt; Series, we knew that Basalt was by definition a volcanic rock in the grey to black color range.  After some research and talking to the team at our quarry we learned that Lava Stone and Basalt are actually very similar.  The main difference is that Basalt is formed when lava cools at a fast rate, or sometimes even cools under pressure, making it a very hard and dense stone.  The Lava Stone that we are sourcing and using in our products is nearly the same stone from a mineralogical make up, but the lava cooled slowly and not under pressure, forming the very veining and light honeycombing that can be seen in this stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/22/Norstone Planc Large Format Lava Stone with Honed Finish.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lava Stone Planc with a honed finish in graphite color shown from a side view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The veining and other “surface characteristics” is one of the things we really like about Lava Stone and is something that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ceramic-wall-tile-%E2%80%93-color-variation-natural-stone-vs-manmade-tile-products-norstone-classroom-s/&quot;&gt;sets natural stone apart from man made stone and tile&lt;/a&gt;.  Since we’re a company that focuses only on natural stone materials, the unique way that this stone looks is super appealing and something that can only ever be imitated, but never duplicated by man made tile production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we’ve enjoyed the most about working with Lava Stone on a few of our first installations is how with a little bit of foresight, an installer can really take advantage of the veining and other surface characteristics to create continuity from piece to piece.  As seen in the photo below, we were able to position and match up some of the veining on the two bottom rows to the left of the kitchen faucet to create an eye catching, and totally unexpected look in a tile product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/22/Norstone Lava Stone Tile Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lava Stone Planc in Platinum color used on a modern kitchen backsplash with cabinets and a marble countertop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardness and durability of Lava Stone is something else that makes it very special.  This is especially true with our Planc large format tile, which is 31.5” long and can be as narrow as 2.4”, all at just over 3/4” thick.  A relative toothpick in natural stone fabrication terms, it takes a strong stone to hold up along these dimensions for transport, cutting, and installation, a task that Lava Stone has proven to be up for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently working with Lava Stone on a couple different products in our line up.  Our Platinum color in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc Series&lt;/a&gt; is a saw cut Lava Stone and the Graphite color in that same series is the same stone but with a honed face.  While the markings and veining tend to steal the show with the Platinum product, the smooth honed finish of the Graphite is a texture that will have people wanting to reach out and touch.  We are also currently prototyping using these same two stones to add them to our existing Aksent 3D panel line in the future.  Keep checking back with our blog to see what other products we can dream up using Lava Stone and contact us today to learn more about how a Lava Stone product might be a good fit for your next natural stone project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The photos and videos of the eruptions and lava flows from the Kilauea volcano in Hawaii are incredible to look at and a good reminder of the power of mother earth. Did you know Norstone has crafted a select line of natural stone products from Lava Stone that we launched earlier this year? Let's take a look this week at Lava Stone and what makes these new products so unique to use for natural stone tile.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/05/22/Kilauea%20Lava%20Flow%20May%202018.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Lava%20Stone%20from%20Lava%20Flow%20in%20Hawaii%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Lava%20Flow%20from%20Kilauea%20volcano%20in%20Hawaii%20May%202018%20that%20will%20eventually%20become%20Lava%20Stone%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Lynia Interlocking Tiles for Outdoor Corporate Space</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Interlocking-Tiles-Outdoor-Office-Space/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Lynia Interlocking Tiles for Outdoor Corporate Space" /><published>2018-05-14T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-lynia-interlocking-tiles-for-outdoor-corporate-space</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Interlocking-Tiles-Outdoor-Office-Space/">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago we worked with an architect designing the new headquarters of a medium sized energy company in Nebraska.  One of the finishes Norstone got to be a part of was a cool outdoor space tucked away in the back of the building where our Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tiles in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/ebony/&quot;&gt;Ebony&lt;/a&gt; were used on a long landscaping wall used to define the perimeter of the space.  This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;interlocking natural tile system&lt;/a&gt; is really cool and its used really well in this project.  Let’s take a look at a few of the things we think make this project special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural Stone Interlocking Tile Landscaping Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tile on a Landscaping wall in a corporate outdoor break space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first thing that catches our eye about this project is the color pallete and commercial focused design of the building.  If you’ve been to any large office park you’ve probably seen a lot of the same color pallete of grey, brown, and white tones along with what most people will conclude as “forgettable” architecture.  The design team on this project did a great job using some interesting color and subtle yet effective design to make this building look like more than just a grey box with windows.  A variety of surfaces were used as well as muted pops of color, such as the reddish grey main panels of the building and the dark black of the Ebony interlocking natural stone tile, to help break up the commercial “office space” feel of the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural Stone Interlocking Tile Patio Seating Area.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tile on a garden wall in the seating area of a corporate ourdoor space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking specifically at the wall where the Ebony interlocking tiles were installed, one of the things we really appreciate is the design of the wall, with its straight runs, right angles, and varied heights, which matches the design style of the tile product.  Each Lynia tile consists of 9 strips of tile, staggered and mounted to a mesh backer, which creates a very linear, geometric, modern inspired look.  A product like our Lynia Interlocking natural stone tiles wouldn’t look nearly as good on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/&quot;&gt;serpentine or curved stone wall&lt;/a&gt;.  Detail like this is the hallmark of good design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How corners are addressed is a common question in almost any stone and tile installation, and we really like how the installer opted for a pre-manufactured corner trim on this project.  These trim pieces eliminate the need to miter cut the corner on site and provide a consistent, safe, and durable look to the corner.  While corner units are important to create the illusion of full bed stone veneer like our Rock Panel line, with a tile product the corner trim pieces are a good option with both a classy look and easy installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural Stone Interlocking Tile Commercial Outdoor Space.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tile on a landscape wall at a commercial office building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the last things we take away from this project is the use of stone in particular on this landscaping wall and how appropriate a building material that is for a commercial space like this where durability and a long life span with minimal maintenance is something all products are measured against.  A natural stone product like our Ebony Lynia tiles are going to require minimal maintenance in a situation like this, and are going to stand up to elements for decades.  Being in Nebraska, imagine the open grassy area behind this building with a couple feet of snow on it after a big winter storm and know that underneath that snow bank is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/freeze-thaw-and-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;freeze thaw stable stone&lt;/a&gt; that is going to be ready to go once the sun comes out and melts it all away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural stone interlocking tiles are a great product that can impart subtle design cues on a project all in an easy to install, durable and long lasting package.  Norstone’s Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tiles come in four unique colors, and we invite you to check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/basalt-il-tiles/interiors/&quot;&gt;interiors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/basalt-il-tiles/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exteriors&lt;/a&gt; galleries for inspiration on your next project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Everybody needs to get away from their cubicle every now and then, but not everyone has a great outdoor space like this at their office! Let's check out how our Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tiles were used on the landscaping walls of this week's featured project!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural%20Stone%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Landscaping%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Interlocking%20Tile%20on%20Exterior%20Landscape%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Ebony%20Lynia%20Natural%20Stone%20Interlocking%20Wall%20Tiles%20used%20on%20an%20exterior%20landscaping%20wall%20at%20an%20office%20building%20in%20Nebraska%22%7D" /></entry></feed>