<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-07T18:30:18+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Spalling on Stacked Stone Walls</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/spalling-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spalling on Stacked Stone Walls" /><published>2019-03-07T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-07T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/spalling-on-stacked-stone-walls</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/spalling-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;One thing that is both a blessing and a curse when working with natural stone products is that they are just that – natural. As such a stone installation can sometimes do things that are unexpected, especially when compared to a man or machine made product. One of the things we hear about occasionally with our stacked stone products is spalling, which is when small flakes, pieces, and sometimes even thin layers of stone fall off the face of stacked stone wall. First and foremost, this is a natural process and there’s no cause for concern! Now that we have that out of the way, let’s learn all about this unique property that some natural stones exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know if a stacked stone wall might be susceptible to spalling the first thing to consider is the type of stone itself. The majority of stones that can exhibit spalling are sedimentary in nature and have cleavage or fracture lines that result in breaks that are thin and can be of varying sizes. Mica is perhaps the most common and probably the most extreme example of a natural stone that exhibits these characteristics since it naturally comes in very thin layers that are easy to split off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/07/Mica Stone Split along Cleavage Planes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mica Stone showing significant layers that split off along cleavage planes during spalling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone installation&lt;/a&gt;, the most common time you’ll see spalling happen is right after installation. It is at this point that the stone product, whether its a loose stone or part of a panel system like our Rock Panel and XL Rock Panel products, has experienced the most movement that it will ever experience. From the time the stone is quarried, manufactured / fabricated, transported (often multiple times to distribution centers and final destination), and finally installed, it is handled, moved around, jostled and sometimes even slightly abused more in that couple weeks or couple months than it ever will be again. During all that movement, the outermost layer of a stone prone to spalling can start to become loose and sometimes it will even spall off in the packaging, during installation, or shortly thereafter as the stone gets cleaned up post install and acclimates to its new environment (temperature, humidity levels,etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/07/Spalling from Stacked Stone Wall-1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;A small piece of natural stone that has spalled off a larger stacked stone wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normal spalling should be expected to occur before, during and up to about 6 months after installation as the stacked stone settles into its new home. For exterior installations weather patterns like freeze-thaw cycles or wet-dry cycles can bring an increased amount of spalling, but the amount of debris being removed from the face of a stacked stone wall should diminish over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Sealing a natural stacked stone wall&lt;/a&gt; isn’t specifically aimed at reducing the amount of spalling that might be happening in a certain installation, but by the very nature of what a sealer is intended to do will help. A sealer, by reducing the amount of water that penetrates into a stone, reduces the amount of movement in stone layers caused by moisture absorption thus helps reduce spalling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spalling that is occurring beyond the normal range of time post installation or happening as a result of repeated triggers, such as a freeze thaw cycle, might be the forerunners of bigger problems in a stacked stone installation. If certain steps were missed, such as the application of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;water proof membrane&lt;/a&gt; in an exterior installation, or if the wrong type of stone is being used for a specific application, such as a stone that is not freeze-thaw rated / tested being used in a cold climate, there could be bigger problems afoot. Contact your stone supplier with information about what is going on and they should be able to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/07/Stacked Stone Exterior Feature Wall with Lanscape  Beds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exterior stacked stone residential project where the stone terminates into a landscaping bed to minimize the appearance of spalling stones&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughtful design consideration is another effective way to handle concerns related to stacked stone walls spalling. Installing stone on the wainscoating of a building is a beautiful look for a residential or commercial building, and if the stone selection is one that is prone to spalling, keeping landscape beds instead of hard surfaces below the stone is a great design idea. Any small pieces of stone that do spall off will end up in the landscaping and go unnoticed. Similarly, if stacked stone is designed to be installed above a pedestrian walkway, such as the entrance to a building, it’s a good idea to consider using a stone like quartz, granite, or slate that is not prone to spalling, or design in a ledge or similar shadowbox feature to catch any spalling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a few minutes to learn more about spalling in stacked stone walls. Norstone is a manufacturer of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;premium natural stone panel systems&lt;/a&gt; and tiles and we’re happy to answer any questions you have about our stone products and how they might be suitable for your next project. Contact us today to learn more!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Spalling is when layers of stone flake or pop off without direct force. This is a natural process for most sedimentary stones and we get a lot of questions about it. Let's take a few minutes this week to learn more about spalling, why it happens, and what our recommended course of action is.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/03/07/Spalling%20from%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Spalling%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Walls%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Small%20piece%20of%20stone%20has%20spalled%20or%20fallen%20off%20from%20a%20natural%20stacked%20stone%20wall%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Charcoal XL on a Modern Long Island Home Exterior</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/charcoal-xl-modern-home-exterior/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Charcoal XL on a Modern Long Island Home Exterior" /><published>2019-03-05T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/charcoal-xl-on-a-modern-long-island-home-exterior</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/charcoal-xl-modern-home-exterior/">&lt;p&gt;One of the more satisfying parts of our job here at Norstone is getting a chance to work with our clients and then see the actual results in the form of either photos they send us or actual site visits to projects where our stone was used. This modern inspired home on New York’s Long Island was one of those project as we started working with design – build firm a few months out when they came across our natural stone products. They were looking for a large format natural stone product that would fit the clean modern lines of their project and fall in the grey to dark grey color range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product ultimately selected was the Charcoal color in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt;. The XL Series features the largest individual stones in any panel system that we offer and comes in a stepped end panel format to eliminate vertical seams in the installation. As with all of our panel series products, finger jointed outside corner units and natural ends are also available to ensure all the details of an installation are checked off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/06/Norstone Charcoal XL Field Unit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XL Series Close Up of a Single Field Unit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product was used in a bump out space that extends out from the main side wall of the house. The bump out is unique in that it’s only one floor tall, creating the opportunity to have an elevated outdoor area on a flat roof above the bump out. We really like how the design team used a stainless steel cap piece and bracket to hold up the frame less smoked out glass railing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;Stainless steel and smoked out glass&lt;/a&gt; offer a very complementary color pallet to the dark grey hues of the charcoal and are a perfect fit for the modern vibe of this design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scale of the XL Series panels is also a great fit for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exterior stone veneer application&lt;/a&gt; such as this one, especially on full or multi story applications. The XL series provides just enough of dimensionality and geometry in design that the designers were looking for without being too busy like a smaller format stacked stone panel system might look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/06/Charcoal XL Residential Exterior Stacked Stone Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XL Stone Veneer Panel used on the exterior of a residential home on a bump out with an open air terrace on the flat roof above it&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the aforementioned stainless steel and glass components, some of the things that really stand out in this exterior to us are all the other complimentary surfaces and products that are part of this design. The ultra smooth stucco walls are designed to look as close as possible to a polished concrete tilt up wall to give off that industrial modern vibe and serve as a nice foil texture wise to the dimensionality of the stacked stone panels. The dark pavers walkway and patio that border the space reinforces the color scheme of this entire space while also not straying from the clean modern lines found in the stone and other surfaces. Lastly, the black granite rip rap size boulders give great contrast to the variety of smooth textures and help bring a more natural element of design set against the pavers, smooth stucco, glass and steel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/06/Charcoal XL Exterior Stacked Stone Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XL Stone Veneer Panel used on the side exterior wall of a modern designed residential home on Long Island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final thing that we wanted to point out was the interesting contrast the stone is showing off as it dries out after a rainstorm in these photos. Most of the time you wouldn’t want to photograph an installation showing it partially wet, but there’s something about the way the stone and the stucco look as they dry out, set against the glossy wet look of the pavers that really makes these photos pop. One of the great things about any installation of natural stone veneer products is that as the product gets wet and then dries out the stone almost starts to come alive on the wall as it goes from a darker wet color to a lighter dry color. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Sealing natural stone&lt;/a&gt; mitigates this effect, which is something to consider when sealing the stone is optional and not required based on the specifics of an installation. There’s not too many other durable products for exteriors that give you that kind of show!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this awesome Charcoal XL stone panel installation. Norstone has been making premium architectural grade natural stone veneer products for over 15 years. Contact us today to learn more about our products for your next stone project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We really love how our Charcoal XL product came together on the exterior of this modern designed home on Long Island in New York. Let's take a in depth look at what makes our largest format rock panel product ideal for this project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/03/06/Charcoal%20XL%20Residential%20Exterior%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20XL%20on%20Exterior%20of%20Modern%20Home%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20XL%20on%20the%20exterior%20side%20wall%20of%20a%20Modern%20Home%20in%20Long%20Island,%20NY%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Will Rising Chinese Tariffs Impact the Stacked Stone Industry</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-chinese-tariffs-impact-the-stacked-stone-industry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Will Rising Chinese Tariffs Impact the Stacked Stone Industry" /><published>2019-03-04T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-will-rising-chinese-tariffs-impact-the-stacked-stone-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-chinese-tariffs-impact-the-stacked-stone-industry/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; is not nearly as glamorous or even remotely as large as some of the other industries, like steel and agricultural products, impacted by the increased tariffs on Chinese imports that came into effect starting in the Fall of 2018 and set to possibly increase as some point in the Spring of 2019. So it’s not a big surprise to us that our industry hasn’t been on the forefront, or really even mentioned in the political crossfire that has accompanied these tariffs. But the reality of the situation is that these tariffs do impact our industry. Small increases have already taken effect and a much larger potential increase looms with uncertainty out on the horizon. Let’s unpack what has transpired already, what might yet happen in the future, and what this means for the US stacked stone consumer in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/04/US Chinese Tariffs on Stacked Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Import containers with the US and Chinese Flags showing the escalating tariffs by the US on Chinese goods&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring the reader up to speed, as of this article’s publication in March 2019, the standard import tariff on most stacked stone HTS import codes on Chinese goods increased from 6% to 10% in September of 2018. A proposed further increase to a 25% tariff was scheduled to come into effect for January 1, 2019 but was postponed in early December until March 1 with China and the US agreeing to a temporary truce. It was then later announced towards the end of February that the March 1 deadline would be extended but neither the US nor China gave a new concrete date for the new deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those not well versed in what this means, the easy to understand version of these tariffs is that currently the US government levies a tariff of 10% on the cost of the good being imported, which the importer pays to the government. It’s important to distinguish the increase in the tariff from increases in the cost of these products to the end consumer. The final end user price on an imported product almost always will include domestic transportation as well as a mark up for the US importer or distributor, hence the Fall 2018 increase from 6% to 10% hasn’t resulted in that large of an increase to the end user. Even if the full 25% tariff does come into effect, stone industry experts estimate that the increase to the end use might be between 10 and 15%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/03/04/US Chinese Tariffs on Stacked Stone Imports.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Container boats being unloaded at a US Port from China highlighting the escalating tariffs on imported Chinese goods&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many Chinese exporters have been reacting to the changes by increasing their stock holdings in the US ahead of the proposed increases. There was a serious shortage of container space on boats heading from Asia to the West Coast of the US this fall with exporters aiming to clear and enter their goods before the tariffs increases took effect. The current unknown status on a trade deal is likely keeping Chinese exporters leery of putting too much cargo on the water, not knowing what the tariff will be when the containers arrive in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the author’s opinion, the losers in this deal are both the American consumer and Chinese stone manufacturing companies. While the stacked stone industry is an almost minuscule part of the total tariff package and trade deal, the increases in tariff rates will at some point hit the American consumer in the form of higher prices on these stacked stone goods. Higher prices in construction materials might mean &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;people put off renovating their properties&lt;/a&gt;, or use other wall covering products in place of stacked stone like porcelain or ceramic tiles from Europe, South America, or made domestically. Chinese manufacturing companies are also likely feeling the squeeze with less new investment money coming their way as business people mitigate risk and opt for other places to invest their money as a result of the unknown future state of the tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner in this deal are companies that are manufacturing competing products in places besides China. Countries like Vietnam, Thailand, and India among others in Southeast Asia do not have nearly the level of manufacturing prowess as China, but with the potential for a 25% tariff on Chinese products into the world’s biggest market, opportunistic manufacturers, exporters, and importers will definitely be making plays in these countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for learning a little more about what the current and propose tariffs on Chinese imports might mean to the stacked stone industry. At &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;Norstone&lt;/a&gt;, we’re dedicated to manufacturing our products in Vietnam and delivering them to our global markets, including the United States and hope anyone interested in stacked stone products considers our products for their next vertical wall application.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The stacked stone industry is on pins and needles waiting to see how the next couple weeks play out as it relates to the proposed increase in tariffs on many of the product codes applicable to our products and industry. Let's take a closer look at what's being considered, who might lose and who might benefit from these changes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/03/04/US%20Chinese%20Tariffs%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Imports.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22How%20Chinese%20Tariffs%20Impact%20the%20Stacked%20Stone%20Industry%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Large%20Container%20boats%20from%20China%20unloading%20at%20a%20US%20Port%20-%20How%20Will%20Chinese%20Tariffs%20Impact%20the%20Stacked%20Stone%20Industry%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vertically Installed White Lynia Tile to Make a Small Space Look Bigger</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/white-lynia-tile-to-make-small-space-bigger/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vertically Installed White Lynia Tile to Make a Small Space Look Bigger" /><published>2019-02-27T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-27T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/vertically-installed-white-lynia-tile-to-make-a-small-space-look-bigger</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/white-lynia-tile-to-make-small-space-bigger/">&lt;p&gt;Powder bathrooms almost always pose a design challenge because of the relative small size of most of these spaces. This particular space had a number of outside challenges as well – no natural light and 12 foot ceilings with the only light fixture being just above head height on the mirror chief among them. The homeowners were looking to do something to break up the incredibly tall wall behind the toilet and lighten up the space in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/white-marble/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tile in White Marble&lt;/a&gt; was used in this application to meet those two primary design goals. The interlocking nature of the product makes it very appealing for a wall in need of some visual interest and the white color of the marble used in this particular color gives a nice contrast against the base grey tones of the wall and also helps brighten up this natural light deprived space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/27/White Lynia Interlocking Tile Powder Bath Feature Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Marble Lynia Tile Installed on a feature wall behind the toilet in a powder bath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homeowners decided to install the tile units with a vertical orientation for both practical and aesthetic reasons. Normally the Lynia Interlocking tile would be installed such that the 12” lengths of the individual tile strips are run horizontally along the wall. In this particular application the tile unit is turned 90 degrees and the 12” lengths run vertically up and down the wall. From a practical standpoint the homeowner told us that by installing the tile with a vertical orientation there were almost no cuts at all in this installation, except for the starting row against the floor tile and the top row against the ceiling. The feature wall here is almost three Lynia Interlocking Tile units wide, so all the homeowner had to do is use a utility knife to cut two strips off of one unit for each row of tile installed.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-pattern-impacts-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;Pattern selection can impact the complexity of a tile installation&lt;/a&gt;, and should always be considered before ordering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From an aesthetic standpoint, the vertical orientation of these tile units also helps accentuate one of the more interesting elements of the space, which is the twelve foot ceilings. A powder room with twelve ceilings is definitely something you don’t see every day to begin with, and having so much wall space in a relatively confined area of a powder room gave the space a closed off feel. The light grey color of the walls certainly didn’t help with creating more of an open feel. By bringing in the White Marble Lynia Tile a good chunk of that vertical wall space became a much brighter color and helped open the space up color wise. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/&quot;&gt;vertical orientation of the interlocking stone tiles&lt;/a&gt; creates movement up the wall, taking advantage of the height of the space. Combining a lighter color and the pattern that draws the eye up the wall helps make this small space look bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/27/White Lynia Interlocking Tile Powder Bath Feature Wall High Ceiling.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Marble Lynia Tile Installed as a feature wall in a powder bathroom with high ceilings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homeowner was incredibly happy with how this turned out and relayed that as a moderately skilled DIYer, this project was well within the range of his skill set. He spent about an hour the first day installing cement board over the existing drywall, and then installed the tile the next day with no help with about 4 hours worth of the work. He came back the next weekend and grouted which took about another two hours once everything was cleaned up. As with most DIY Homeowner projects, there are plans to paint the walls a lighter color and install a new mirror and lighting fixture, as time permits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/27/White Lynia Interlocking Tile Feature Wall Close Up.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Marble Lynia close up showing product installed in a vertical orientation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick look at this unique project with us. Being one of our newer products, it’s great to see photos of the White Marble Lynia Interlocking tile come back. This is a beautiful stone, with a great color that is applicable for many design schemes in a format that will have people admiring the wall for years to come. To learn more about this product and any of our other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone veneer panels and interlocking tiles&lt;/a&gt; please contact our friendly customer service team and they’ll be happy to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our White Marble Lynia Tiles is a new product that we released last year and it's cool to see installations like this one coming back doing interesting things like installing the tile unit with a vertical orientation. Have a look at how this interlocking tile product helps this small powder bath look bigger than it is.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/02/27/White%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Feature%20Wall%20Close%20Up.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22White%20Lynia%20Tile%20Vertical%20Installation%20Powder%20Bath%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20White%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Tile%20installed%20vertically%20on%20a%20feature%20wall%20in%20a%20powder%20bath%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Loose Stones vs Stone Panel Systems – Which One is Right for Your Stacked Stone Project?</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/loose-stone-vs-stone-panel-systems/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loose Stones vs Stone Panel Systems – Which One is Right for Your Stacked Stone Project?" /><published>2019-02-18T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-18T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/loose-stones-vs-stone-panel-systems-which-one-is-right-for-your-stacked-stone-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/loose-stone-vs-stone-panel-systems/">&lt;p&gt;There’s a healthy debate about using individual loose stones vs stone panel systems for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone veneer installation&lt;/a&gt;, and for good reason! Each product and installation method comes with its own set of pros and cons. So let’s take a closer look at each of these product types and learn the good, bad, and ugly to help you decide what’s the right product for your next stacked stone veneer installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/18/Hand Stacked Loose Stone on a Pallet.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Traditional Hand Stacked Loose Stone on a pallet ready for installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes sense to start off with loose individual stones because this method really is the original when it comes to stacked stone. Hand stacked stone has been around for centuries – just take a look at many forts, castles, city walls, etc and you’ll see examples of stonework that has been hand stacked and stood the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/18/Hand Stacked Loose Stone Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Traditional Hand Stacked Loose Stone on a garden wall with a bench in front of it&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the main advantages of using hand stacked loose stone are the breadth of stone options available to you. Pretty much any stone can be used, or modified to be used, to be stacked on a wall. Stone masons are adept at using rock hammers and chisels to strike larger stones at just the right point to break it into smaller pieces or into a certain shape to fit the installation. With the variety of stone available for an installation like this, it also opens us this category of stone veneer to almost every price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drawbacks of hand stacked loose stone is that skilled, experienced labor is a must for a great looking installation. The installation process can often be tedious and slow, and some loose stone installations also will get “mortared in”, meaning masonry mortar is “pointed” into the gaps between each stone. The combination of a skilled installer plus a lengthy installation can make the cost of installation high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/18/Stacked Stone Panel Veneer-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panel stone veneer panel system&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stone panel systems have been around for about the past 15 years or so, and are made possible by advances in stone processing equipment that allows the stone to be split and cut into thinner sections. These “thin” stones are then glued together, or sometimes mounted to a backer in a standard size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantages of a stone panel systems is in the relative easy and therefore &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/save-money-with-thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;lower labor cost to install stone panel systems&lt;/a&gt; as compared to hand stacked loose stone. The ideal installer for a stone panel system is a tile installer with some experience in setting natural stone tiles, but is also well within the range of most &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY homeowners&lt;/a&gt; as well. Because the product comes as a repeatable shape, it can be installed quickly and efficiently, sometimes 10x as fast as hand stacked loose stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/18/Stacked Stone Panel System Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panel on a large foyer feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest disadvantages of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone panel systems&lt;/a&gt; are the relative cost of the product is much higher than unprocessed loose stone, but when factoring in the lower cost of installation many times stone panel systems actually end up costing less on an installed cost per square foot basis. Another disadvantage to stone panel systems is that there are seams in the installation – whether its vertical or horizontal, wherever two panels come together a seam is formed. The extent to which this is actually a disadvantage should be considered when evaluating a stone panel system. Are the ends staggered so vertical seams are minimized? Does the product have lots of “relief” or “dimensionality” to each panel that helps hide these seams? Take a look at the product installed, whether that’s in a showroom, on their website, or a local example installation and see for yourself if you see the seams in a stone panel installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there’s no right answer for whether hand stacked loose stone or stone panel systems is the right type of product for your project, the data certainly suggests that stone panel systems are worth considering. There is more stone going up on walls now than ever before because of the advances in manufacturing that make what once might have been an ugly stucco wall a beautiful stacked stone wall. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/vetting-natural-stone-veneer-manufacturers/&quot;&gt;Norstone is a natural stone manufacturer&lt;/a&gt; at the leading edge of the stone panel system revolution, having made premium architectural grade stone panel systems for over 15 years. Check out our stone veneer products and project gallery for inspiration on your next stacked stone project today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This isn't exactly an age old debate, but for anyone considering stone for a wall project, it's a common question. Learn more in this blog about the pros and cons of both hand stacked loose stone and stone panel systems.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/02/18/Stacked%20Stone%20Panel%20Veneer.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Loose%20Stone%20vs%20Stone%20Panel%20Systems%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Comparing%20loose%20stone%20vs%20stone%20panel%20systems%20and%20which%20one%20is%20right%20for%20your%20stacked%20stone%20project%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Fun Mix of Four Planc Large Format Tiles Colors</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mix-four-planc-large-format-tile-colors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Fun Mix of Four Planc Large Format Tiles Colors" /><published>2019-02-11T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/a-fun-mix-of-four-planc-large-format-tiles-colors</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mix-four-planc-large-format-tile-colors/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we appreciate most about the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Tile&lt;/a&gt; that we debuted last Spring is the versatility of the product. We really keyed in on the ability to set the large format tiles in different patterns as being the main source of versatility. Instead of just a plain old running bond or brick set pattern, the Planc product really shows it uniqueness when installed in unique patterns like symmetrical and asymmetrical straight stacks, herringbones, diagonals, and more. Our eyes were opened yet again by this product when the first photos of this week’s featured project came across our desks. The design and installation team on this seemingly straightforward commercial exterior took four colors of the Planc and created an incredibly unique and stand out feature. Let’s take a closer look at what they did and how it was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/11/Planc Large Format Tile Mixed Color Installation - Commercial Exterior.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Commercial Exterior ADA Ramp with a large installation of Norstone Planc Large Format Tiles mixed in four colors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The largest uninterrupted section of the wall where the Planc Large Format Tile was installed is part of a incline ramp leading to the front door of this commercial space. The colors used in this installation are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/platinum/&quot;&gt;Platinum Lavastone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/grey-basalt/&quot;&gt;Grey Basalt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/ebony-basalt/&quot;&gt;Ebony Basalt&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/silver-quartz/&quot;&gt;Silver Grey Quartz&lt;/a&gt; in the Planc Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that really catches our eye about this installation is that colors selected create both a contrast and also blend together. Specifically, the dark tones of the Ebony Basalt color create a huge color contrast with the very light silvery grey tones of the Silver Grey Quartz. It’s worth noting that the Silver Grey in the bright exterior natural light comes across as almost white, whereas in interior applications and under different lighting conditions much more of the silver and grey tones show up. The Grey Basalt and Platinum &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/&quot;&gt;Lavastone&lt;/a&gt; then actually come together with very similar light to medium grey tones which gives the wall a solid base tone from which the darker Ebony and lighter Silver Grey bounce off of quite nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/11/Planc Large Format Tile Mixed Color Installation - Commercial Exterior Parking Lot-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Commercial Exterior Feature Wall with four colors of Norstone Planc Large Format Tile mixed together in a random pattern&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Platinum Lavastone was a unique selection among the four colors picked as its the only stone that has naturally occurring veining and striations in it. This is a subtle detail, but one that is actually very important to the overall look of this installation because it unequivocally lets you know that what you’re looking at is natural stone. If all the colors selected had a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/split-face-vs-honed-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;smooth honed natural stone finish&lt;/a&gt;, it would be hard to know what type of product is actually on the wall – tile, metal, even plastic exterior products would all be possibilities. But with the Lavastone comes that amazing natural veining that makes this unmistakable as natural stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent a lot of time looking at this installation and it looks like to us that the four colors are in even ratios. There is also no discernible pattern, other than that the installer laid the product horizontally and kept the same height plancs in each row. There’s also no discernible pattern to the color variation. Overall, we think the “randomness” of the pattern and color mix add to this installation, keeping it one big mash up instead of uniform, which speaks again to the inherent nature of natural stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/11/Planc Large Format Tile Mixed Color Installation - Commercial Exterior Planters.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Commercial Exterior Planter and Landscaping wall clad in a mix of four colors of Norstone's Planc Large Format Tile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact on this small planter wall at the other end of the building’s entrance is, in our opinion, less pronounced. With four colors to mix together and share the spotlight, the larger the wall the greater the effect will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years we’ve seen a handful of clients use our Rock Panels in mixed applications, most often with the contrasting colors of our White Quartz and Charcoal, but the end result never really got our hearts pumping like this project does. The Planc truly is a versatile product in both the colors it is available in and the patterns in which the tiles can be set. Learn more about our Planc product by visiting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt; page of our website or contacting us today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We've known since the start that our Planc Large Format Tile product was versatile. It comes in a bunch of colors and can be set in lots of different patterns. But,we weren't expecting it to look like this! Check out this super cool project on this week's blog that used four of our Planc colors for one unique look!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/02/11/Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Mixed%20Color%20Installation%20-%20Commercial%20Exterior%20Parking%20Lot.jpeg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Mix%20of%20Four%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Colors%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Exterior%20commercial%20wall%20clad%20in%20a%20mix%20of%20four%20colors%20of%20Norstone's%20Large%20Format%20Planc%20Tiles%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Importance of Vetting Your Natural Stone Veneer Manufacturer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/vetting-natural-stone-veneer-manufacturers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Importance of Vetting Your Natural Stone Veneer Manufacturer" /><published>2019-02-04T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-importance-of-vetting-your-natural-stone-veneer-manufacturer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/vetting-natural-stone-veneer-manufacturers/">&lt;p&gt;On any construction project, big or small, it really pays to do your homework on all the products that are being used. Each of these products will get tested in its own way on your project, so making sure the product selected meets the requirements of the project is an important step that must not be missed. Natural stone veneer and the companies that manufacture them are pretty easy to vet because the product is ultimately not that complex and a good manufacturer should have all have the information you need to verify the applicability of their product against your requirements quickly and easily. Here are a few things to consider when vetting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;natural stone veneer manufacturer&lt;/a&gt; for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are your product questions easily answered?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good natural stone veneer manufacturer should be easy to approach and answer any question you have about their product and its applicability for your specific project conditions without any hesitation. Important details, like what type of stone the veneer is made out of, can it be used exterior or is it interior only, and can the stone be used in submerged applications or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/freeze-thaw-and-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;freeze-thaw climates&lt;/a&gt; are some examples of questions that a natural stone veneer manufacturer should have no problem answering and as appropriate providing the appropriate testing documentation. Even better if those questions can be answered via online resources on the manufacturer’s website or a specific technical services phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/04/Norstone White Rock Panels - Denmark Fireplace - Vetting Natural Stone Veeneer Manufacturers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels on thin fireplace in Denmark with a large chest level staineless steel fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further investigation would be recommended if the manufacturer can’t provide concrete documentation on a specific requirement that is applicable to your project. For example, if you are installing stone veneer exterior in a freeze-thaw climate and the manufacturer can’t provide independent lab certified freeze thaw testing you might consider another natural stone veneer that has had the testing done and results available to view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do they have project photos?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good litmus test of any natural stone veneer manufacturer is the quality of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/&quot;&gt;project photos&lt;/a&gt; on their website and printed literature. An immediate red flag would be the absence of any photos, photos that look like computer renderings, or close up photos of just the product itself (normally taken on a factory floor somewhere!) and not of actual completed projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/04/Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels - Niagra House - Vetting Natural Stone Veeneer Manufacturers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used on exterior facade of ultra modern home in Niagra Falls Ontario&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, do the project photos the stone veneer manufacturer provides come up on par with the project you are working on? Whether you’re designing a feature wall on a new restaurant or a fireplace remodel on your own home, a manufacturer that can’t show they’ve worked on projects at a specific level it might be because the products simply don’t look as good as the alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, are there a lot of photos – not just one or two? A manufacturer can claim they’ve been around for a long time on an “about us” page but can they back up that claim with a large body of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are they experts in the industry?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good way to vet a natural stone veneer manufacturer is to try and understand their position in the natural stone veneer industry as a whole. Do they work with and / or have affiliations with industry associations like the Marble Institute of America and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;Tile Council of North America&lt;/a&gt;? Are they active on social media channels and share more than just information about the it products? Have the won awards, received recommendations or accolades from trusted companies and individuals in the construction and architecture &amp;amp; design community?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/02/04/Norstone Ochre Rock Panels - Rockport Concert Hall - Vetting Natural Stone Veeneer Manufacturers-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels used on award winning concert hall in Rockport, Massachusetts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selecting a natural stone veneer for any project just on price is a risky proposition, as the cost of rework on a product installed incorrectly or not suited for a specific application will almost immediately outpace any difference in the starting price difference between any two natural stone veneer options. Natural stone is a veneer option that can outlast almost any structure so Norstone encourages all consumers of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone veneer&lt;/a&gt;, for any size project, to consider who the team is behind the stone and pick the best option for each project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">With the Spring Building Season right around the corner, lots of folks are starting to think about projects involving stone veneer that will be happening over the next couple of months. If you are price shopping, know what to look for in a reputable natural stone veneer manufacturer by reading this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/02/04/Norstone%20Ochre%20Rock%20Panels%20-%20Rockport%20Concert%20Hall%20-%20Vetting%20Natural%20Stone%20Veeneer%20Manufacturers.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Vetting%20Quality%20Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Manufacturers%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Vetting%20Quality%20Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Manufacturers%20by%20evaluating%20project%20photos%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Aksent Stone Veneer Two Sided Outdoor Fireplace</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-aksent-3d-stone-two-sided-outdoor-fireplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Aksent Stone Veneer Two Sided Outdoor Fireplace" /><published>2019-01-28T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-28T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-aksent-stone-veneer-two-sided-outdoor-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-aksent-3d-stone-two-sided-outdoor-fireplace/">&lt;p&gt;Early 90s architecture by and large didn’t make that much of a lasting impression or impact on the architecture of today.  A remnant of that period that we have a special affinity for is the two sided or see through fireplace.  At Norstone, we do some of our best work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;natural stone fireplaces&lt;/a&gt;, so when you’ve got two sides a fireplace, it’s basically double the fun!  All jokes aside, the two sided fireplace has evolved from what started out as an interesting way to share a fireplace, normally between two living areas, into something that designers are using in far more interesting places and applications.  Today’s blog features a two sided fireplace that is super unique because it’s exterior and bridges the gap between two very unique spaces.  Let’s have a closer look at this really cool space done up in our Aksent modern stone veneer panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/28/Ebony Aksent Stone Veneer Two Sided Exterior Fireplace-1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Aksent 3D Panels used on an outdoor two sided fireplace with a large open air patio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand about this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/5-outdoor-stone-fireplaces/&quot;&gt;outdoor stone fireplace&lt;/a&gt; is the two spaces that it’s looking out onto.  In the above view of the fireplace you see this beautiful pillar of stacked stone with the stainless steel gas fireplace situated in an open air residential patio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come around 180 degrees on that fireplace and you’ll see that the other side (seen in the photo below) is the focal point of a unique private outdoor room, that is very much open to the elements, with just a pergola roof, but affording a lot of privacy by design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fireplace itself is a very large unit with a significant stainless steel border situated around the perimeter of the unit.  The stainless steel is a great color to pair with the dark tones of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/ebony/&quot;&gt;Ebony Aksent 3D panels&lt;/a&gt;.  The large linear format of the insert, as well as the clean lines of the stainless steel and glass paneling create a very modern vibe which is obviously right in line with the geometric design  and clean finish of the Aksent 3D stone veneer panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/28/Ebony Aksent Stone Veneer Two Sided Fireplace.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Aksent 3D Panels used on an outdoor two sided fireplace in a unique private outdoor room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surrounding products in the space offer up a nice contrast in colors and texture to the extremely modern vibe of the fireplace and stone veneer.  The private outdoor room is framed out of high quality lumber that has been either painted or stained to create a very consistent look and homogenize most of the character that might come through from the wood grain.  The patio floor actually appears to be a stamped concrete look (note the expansion joints) that introduces a rougher texture and two tone look to the space.  While the square and rectangle pattern does speak to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lynia-and-aksent-launch/&quot;&gt;geometric design of the Aksent stone veneer panels&lt;/a&gt;, the modern look of this space could definitely be kicked up a notch or two with a flooring tile or paver with a single color and linear format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting things in the two sided aspect of this fireplace is that the patio side places the fireplace at a little higher than waist level, whereas the outdoor private room has it at basically knee level.  This is perfect for each of the spaces to encourage people to linger in conversation on the seating of the exterior room and serve as a perfect backdrop for a bar height party in the outdoor space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our favorite two sided fireplaces was done on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ochre-ochre-everywhere-in-this-magnificent-austin-tx-modern-home/&quot;&gt;modern styled home in Austin, TX&lt;/a&gt; where the fireplace went from the dining room on one side to the outdoor patio on the other.  Both that two sided fireplace and the one in today’s blog are really cool examples of how you can create a bridge between two spaces with a fireplace.  Whether you’ve got a one sided or two sided fireplace, we encourage you to think outside the box and create more than just a regular boring fireplace on your next project.  And know that Norstone is here to help clad that fireplace, however many sides it has, with the best natural stone veneers for fireplaces on the market!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Once we saw this project, we knew we had to share it with on the blog. We've got a soft spot for see through fireplaces, and this one takes it a step further being outdoors. So much cool stuff to check out – have a look!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/01/28/Ebony%20Aksent%20Stone%20Veneer%20Two%20Sided%20Exterior%20Fireplace.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Outdoor%20Two%20Sided%20Fireplace%20with%20Ebony%20Aksent%203D%20Stone%20Panels%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22View%20from%20open%20air%20patio%20of%20a%20two%20sided%20fireplace%20clad%20with%20Norstone's%20Ebony%20Aksent%203D%20Stone%20Panels.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Natural Stone is a Great Choice for Indoor Air Quality</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-for-indoor-air-quality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Natural Stone is a Great Choice for Indoor Air Quality" /><published>2019-01-21T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-21T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/why-natural-stone-is-a-great-choice-for-indoor-air-quality</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-for-indoor-air-quality/">&lt;p&gt;Indoor air quality is a building industry term that several years ago very few people knew or put much thought into.  With the growing emphasis on green construction and achieving various LEED points and certifications, Indoor Air Quality, or IAQ as we’ll refer to it in the rest of this article, has gotten a lot more attention paid to it than ever before.  If you’ve ever walked into a building towards the end of construction, as the finished surfaces are nearing completion, you’ve probably caught a whiff of something that you would definitely not consider “natural”.  The initial installation of flooring materials and paints, along with the harsh chemicals that these surfaces sometimes get cleaned with post installation can create quite the odor, which sometimes isn’t being handled properly if the ventilation system is still being installed or run at lower than normal volumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The natural stone industry has known for a long time that natural stone products have tremendous advantages over other similar products in the building materials industry.  Let’s take a quick look at what some of these advantages are and specifically how our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;Norstone natural stone wall veneer products&lt;/a&gt; can help out with indoor air quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/21/Norstone Ochre Blend Rock Panel Feature Wall for Indoor Air Quality.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Natural Stone Feature Wall with TV in an Atlanta Loft for improved Indoor Air Quality&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand how natural stone can help with indoor air quality, let’s first get a handle on some of the main drivers of poor indoor air quality.  From a building material standpoint, any products that can off gas Volatile Organic Compounds (VOCs) can negatively impact indoor air quality.  The list of products that might have VOCs is long – carpeting, certain types of engineered and hardwood floors, cabinetry, furniture, adhesives, and paint to name a few.  One of the biggest culprits as far as building materials and contributing to VOCs is formaldehyde which is used in a variety of composite wood products.  Various chemical solvents can be present in adhesives and paint that will also contribute VOCs into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural Stone has such an advantage when it comes to Indoor Air Quality because quite simply – it’s natural.  A great example is the comparison between a carpeted floor and a floor set with a natural stone tile product like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/travertine-tiles-norstone-designer-series/&quot;&gt;travertine tiles&lt;/a&gt;.  The carpet, unless certified otherwise, is likely to emit a bunch of VOCs into the air, mainly from the glue used to adhere the carpet and pad to the sub floor as well as the latex binder which secures the strands of the carpet to the carpet backer itself.  Compare that with a natural stone tile which releases no VOCs, and pair it with a no VOC thinset to install the tile with and you’ve got a clear winner in the Indoor Air Quality battle.  And on a side note – the life cycle cost of replacing carpet every couple years will greatly out weight the higher up front cost of a durable hard surface like a natural stone tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/21/Norstone Natural Stone Fireplace for Indoor Air Quality-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used as the natural stone wall veneer on a fireplace project for Improved Indoor Air Quality&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A similar VOC example exists when looking at wall finishes and comparing a painted wall versus a wall with a natural stone veneer wall covering like any of our Norstone Natural Stone Products.  Paint, unless certified non VOC, is a huge contributor to poor Indoor Air Quality.  Compare that to a natural stone wall veneer product like our Standard Series Rock Panels, Aksent 3D Honed Panels, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Large Format Planc Wall Tiles&lt;/a&gt;, which have been tested and certified to emit no VOCs and you’ll not only get better Indoor Air Quality, but also a tremendously better looking wall.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-veneer-leed-credits/&quot;&gt;Natural Stone Veneer can contribute to LEED credits&lt;/a&gt;, specifically by Credit 3.2 related Indoor Air Quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/21/Norstone Ivory Rock Panel Feature Wall for Indoor Air Quality.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Natural Stone Feature Wall of Norstone Ivory Rock Panels with low slung couch and large window in a suburban NJ home for improved Indoor Air Quality&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking some time today to learn more about Indoor Air Quality and how natural stone building material products can help contribute to improving IAQ.  White still in its infancy, Indoor Air Quality is something that the general public will start to take notice of more and more and some day in the future the idea of constructing a building with materials that can potentially harm its inhabitants will sound as crazy as drinking when you’re pregnant did 50 years ago.  So jump on the bandwagon early and consider natural stone products for your next new construction or remodeling project today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Indoor Air Quality is a buzzword that gets thrown around a bunch in the building industry. This article explores more about what indoor air quality is and specifically how natural stone products can help achieve better indoor air quality.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/01/21/Norstone%20Natural%20Stone%20Fireplace%20for%20Indoor%20Air%20Quality.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Wall%20Veneer%20for%20Improved%20Indoor%20Air%20Quality%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Fireplace%20feature%20wall%20done%20in%20natural%20stone%20veneer%20to%20improve%20indoor%20air%20quality%20as%20compared%20to%20other%20building%20materials%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grey Aksent Panels in a Modern Fireplace Design</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-panels-modern-fireplace-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Aksent Panels in a Modern Fireplace Design" /><published>2019-01-14T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-panels-in-a-modern-fireplace-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-panels-modern-fireplace-design/">&lt;p&gt;We’re huge fans of modern design with its open spaces, clean lines and hard surfaces, so we instantly fell in love with this fireplace project recently finished using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; in the Ash Grey color.  There’s so much to like about this space and the way the fireplace has been designed into it that we knew right away we’d be featuring it on a blog to share with our followers.  So let’s get right into it and tell you what we love about this modern fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent Modern Fireplace in Loft Space.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Stone Panels in Ash Grey used on a modern fireplace in a large open loft style space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we even get to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;stone veneer fireplace&lt;/a&gt;, you really have to appreciate the space this unit has been designed into.  The high ceilings create a ton of volume in the space and the magnificent glass windows above the fireplace let in an amazing amount of natural light which really opens the space up.  We’re not normally big fans of seeing shadows in photos, but in this particular case it all kind of comes together to create that “lofty” modern feel that is so desirable in design these days.  The clean lines of the windows and doorways – no arches here – add to straightforward linear design this space does such a fantastic job creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent Modern Fireplace TV and Fireplace.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Stone Panels in Ash Grey used on a modern fireplace with a large tv mounted above a linear gas insert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the fireplace itself, there’s just so much detail going on in a relatively little space that its hard to see it all without really looking hard at the design.  First off, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-uk-modern-home/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Panel in Grey is a very modern designed product&lt;/a&gt;, with its horizontal linear orientation is a perfect color selection to slightly contrast against the base white color palette of this space and also tie in nicely to the color of the built in shelving, storage, and counter top spaces flanking the fireplace.  The long linear look of the Aksent 3D Panel is also a perfect fit with the long and skinny gas fireplace insert chosen for the fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a product standpoint, there are two things that shine through about the design of the Aksent 3D Panel product that worked really well in this application.  The first is the outside corners, which turn back from the face of the fireplace into the inserts on each side.  Norstone has been making &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;the best corner system on the stone veneer market&lt;/a&gt; for over a decade using our finger joint concept and building them with a high degree of calibration and a final hand test fit before they leave our factory.  It’s projects like this, where the outside corner is super prominent for both the face of the fireplace as well as the functional inserts, where a super functional and perfect looking corner unit outshines the lower level dovetail and z-style corner concepts of some of our competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent Modern Fireplace-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Stone Panels in Ash Grey used on a modern fireplace with outsider corners and where the stone extends partially towards the high ceilings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that sticks out from a design standpoint how the design of this modern fireplace opted to extend the stone partially up the wall, above the height level of the inserts but not all the way up to the ceiling.  From an application standpoint, this isn’t something you see very often, as designers tend to either keep the height of the stone at a specific level that’s tied to other features of the fireplace, such as mantel height, or take the stone veneer all the way to the ceiling.  In this instance, stopping it at the height of the built ins and doorways would make the fireplace appear small in stature, and probably wouldn’t even cover the TV mounted on it.  Taking it all the way to the ceiling isn’t an option either as the pattern of the windows would create an uneven break.  Although we’ve never seen it done before, the Aksent Modern stone panel is a perfect product to take and stop mid wall like has been done here.  The thin side profile of this modern panel doesn’t create too much bulk on the wall and the clean horizontal lines create a nice break point for the fireplace stone installation, midway between the top of the built ins and the windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got a fireplace that needs a re-do and you like modern styled products, our Aksent 3D Panels are definitely worth taking a look at.  Available in four colors ranging from dark to light, you’ll find a great fit for your next modern fireplace project.  Contact us today to learn more about our contemporary stone veneer products, as well as our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;traditional stacked stone panel products&lt;/a&gt; that are a great option for more traditional looking designs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our Grey Aksent panels are the perfect choice for this modern fireplace that a customer of ours recently completed. A big space like this “lofty” feeling great room needs a focal point, and the Aksent 3 Dimensional panels deliver!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent%20Modern%20Fireplace.jpeg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Grey%20Aksent%20Panels%20on%20a%20Modern%20Fireplace%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Grey%20Aksent%20Panels%20used%20on%20a%20modern%20designed%20fireplace%20in%20a%20large%20loft%20style%20space%20in%20the%20upper%20Midwest%22%7D" /></entry></feed>