<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-18T01:11:34+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Top 5 Stone Veneer Installations in Restaurants</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-restaurant-projects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top 5 Stone Veneer Installations in Restaurants" /><published>2020-03-17T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-17T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-veneer-installations-in-restaurants</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-restaurant-projects/">&lt;p&gt;Stone Veneer has always been a great design choice for restaurant and other hospitality projects. The durability of stone definitely is an important consideration for a highly trafficked restaurant, not to mention the timeless appeal of well designed and installed stone veneer. With the COVID-19 pandemic settling in over the United States in early 2020, we wanted to put together a top 5 list of our favorite stone veneer installations in restaurants. With “social distancing” in full effect, we might not be able to see these in person for a while, so enjoy this list of great restaurant projects virtually!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/18/Norstone Stone Veneer Restaurant - Susanna Foo's Pennsylvania.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Stone Veneer Rock Panels on a column and feature wall at Susanna Foo's restaurant in Pennsylvania&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;susanna-foos-gourmet-kitchen--pennsylvania&quot;&gt;Susanna Foo’s Gourmet Kitchen – Pennsylvania&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love this project because it as one of the first ever applications of Norstone in the United States. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend Standard Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; are used on multiple walls throughout the interior of the restaurant and also clads a central column complete with a circular cut out and an Asian inspired two way gong. This project was installed before we developed our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;outside corner units&lt;/a&gt;, so the cuts on that column are all expertly done miter cuts that look fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/18/Norstone Stone Veneer Restaurant - HDI Abu Dhabi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels on large wall at a restaurant in Abu Dhabi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hdi--abu-dhabi&quot;&gt;HDI – Abu Dhabi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bar and lounge area of this restaurant in Abu Dhabi showcases our Ivory Standard Series Rock Panels over a large wall. The color pallete is what we think is the star of the show with this project. The neutral tones of the floor tile and wall columns and beams let the warm cream to gold tones of the ivory complement each other quite nicely. The green plants give this space nice pops of contrasting color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/18/Norstone Stone Veneer Restaurant - Chipotle South Florida.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tiles in Grey Basalt surrounding the entrance to a Chipotle in South Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chipotle--south-florida&quot;&gt;Chipotle – South Florida&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long time lunch favorite of the Norstone team, this Chipotle fast casual restaurant in South Florida leveled up their exterior veneer opting for our Lynia Interlocking Tiles in the Basalt Grey color in lieu of a more normal stucco or cmu split face exterior. The clean lines and grey color tones of this product fit right along with the normal Chipotle industrial style interiors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/18/Norstone Stone Veneer Restaurant - Farradays Pompano Beach-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Stone Veneer Rock Panels at a high end steak house in Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;farradays-steak-house--south-florida&quot;&gt;Farradays Steak House – South Florida&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another South Florida favorite comes up on our list, this one being the Farraday’s Steak House at the Isle of Capri Casino in Pompano Beach. As with most casino based restaurants, you have to walk past the slot machines and gaming tables to find this place, but those that do are rewarded with a beautiful dining experience, both visually and gastronomically. Our Ochre Blend Rock Panels are used behind the bar and extensively throughout the main dining areas. We especially love the curved wall in this photo as it shows that our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/&quot;&gt;stone veneer panels can be used on radius walls&lt;/a&gt; and allows for some really intimate tables to be built right into the wall, serving to break up a large space and help control noise across the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/18/Norstone Stone Veneer Restaurant - Libbys Sarasota, FL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc large format tile in Platinum Lavastone surrounding a bench seat at a restaurant in Sarasota, FL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;libbys--sarasota&quot;&gt;Libby’s – Sarasota&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tops on our list is Libby’s restaurant in Sarasota, FL, which opened in 2019 and used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc large format tile&lt;/a&gt; product in the Platinum Lavastone product across a number of different wall sections. The photo above is our favorite area showing the beautiful stone surrounding a cozy set of tables in their outdoor dining area. The smooth texture of this product and the beautiful natural veining fit right in with the design scheme featuring clean minimalistic modern lines and muted color tones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoyed this top 5 list of our favorite stone veneer installations at restaurants. Stone veneer is an incredibly versatile product, coming in a range of colors and finishes to match design requirements for just about any project. To learn more about using Norstone natural stone products in your next commercial project, contact us today and ask for our commercial team to get started.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">With the shut down of in person dining at many restaurants stemming from the need to “social distance” as part of the strategy to contain the COVID-19 pandemic we thought it would be good to give you a top 5 list of our favorite stone veneer installations in restaurants in this week's blog. While you might not be able to visit these anytime soon, enjoy these beautiful spaces and we all look forward to dining out again in public soon!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/03/18/Norstone%20Stone%20Veneer%20Restaurant%20-%20Farradays%20Pompano%20Beach.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Veneer%20Restaurant%20Projects%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Top%205%20list%20of%20Norstone's%20favorite%20stone%20veneer%20restaurant%20projects%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">San Francisco Stone Tile Interior Courtyard</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-tile-interior-courtyard/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="San Francisco Stone Tile Interior Courtyard" /><published>2020-03-12T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-12T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/san-francisco-stone-tile-interior-courtyard</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-tile-interior-courtyard/">&lt;p&gt;In big cities like San Francisco and New York, an outdoor space, whether part of an apartment, town home or brownstone, is coveted. Some times these outdoor spaces are little more than the size of a small room, shoe-horned into the rear of a building with no view per se, but at the very least a little access to sunshine and if you’re looking straight up. It’s pretty easy for these spaces to feel drab and confined, with “hard” building materials like fencing and concrete walls forming most of the borders, and with limited sun exposure keeping grass or most plants alive sometimes isn’t possible. Such was the case with the interior courtyard we are featuring today which is at the rear of a single family residence in San Francisco that backs up on all adjoining sides against other houses and buildings. A recent renovation of the space resulted in the project we are featuring today, consisting of a beautiful wall of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/basalt/&quot;&gt;Grey Basalt Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s take a quick look around this space and see how the homeowners created a modern, functional and beautiful interior stone courtyard in the midst of a concrete jungle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/12/San Francisco Interior Stone Tile Courtyard with Synthetic Turf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Basalt Lynia Interlocking Tile Feature Wall in San Francisco Interior Courtyard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing we notice about this space is that its really quite small. For those of us that live in the suburbs, we tend to look at lot and yard size in fractions of an acre – this space is only about ten feet by fourteen feet open to the sky! Not exactly room for a pick up baseball game, but with any square footage at a premium in cities like San Francisco, utilizing this space to its full potential is the name of the game. The design and style of the space definitely leans modern, with not only the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth finish&lt;/a&gt; and pattern design of the Lynia Interlocking Natural stone tiles, but also with the predominant grey / white color scheme and sleek options selected for the railings and planter boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/12/San Francisco Interior Stone Tile Courtyard with Steps.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Basalt Lynia Interlocking Tile Feature Wall in San Francisco Interior Courtyard showing tile pattern on wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the size of space that this customer had to work with, we really like the choice of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt; for the main wall. Each of the tile strips in the Lynia units are about 12” long and vary in height from around 1” to 2.5”. There are 9 strips per unit which are staggered to create an interlocking pattern from one unit to the next. The choice on this project to use a contrasting white color on the grout accentuates the pattern and tied in nicely with the bright white steps. A grout color that is a closer match to the natural stone tile downplays the pattern slightly but is also more forgiving from an installation standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/12/San Francisco Interior Stone Tile Courtyard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Basalt Lynia Interlocking Tile Feature Wall in San Francisco Interior Courtyard with Synthetic Turf and a porch swing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-for-outdoor-living/&quot;&gt;natural stone tile is a great choice for an outdoor living space&lt;/a&gt;, the other element of this project that really catches most people’s eye is the synthetic turf. Due to limited direct sun exposure, trying to grow grass in a boxed in environment like this is difficult, not to mention the maintenance of caring for a yard, no matter how small. Synthetic turf is a great option here as it is durable, low maintenance, looks amazing, and offers a nice consistent color to contrast against the Grey Basalt color of the natural stone tiles on the wall. The planter boxes on the ledge above the wall bring actual plants into the space and round out a healthy dose of natural or at least “natural looking” materials into the space. It’s very easy to design these spaces with an abundance of hardscape products like brick pavers and knee walls, making a soft surface like synthetic turf even more appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re outdoor space is big or small, enhancing the area with natural stone can dramatically alter and improve the look of the space. To learn more about our natural stone veneer and tile products visit Norstone USA and speak with one of their design team experts and get some recommendations on natural stone ideas for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">An interior courtyard, surrounded on all sides by neighboring houses doesn't have to be all drab. This courtyard in San Francisco has the right idea with a beautiful stone tile veneer wall and some nice greenery which create a beautiful, usable, space. Let's have a quick look around this tiny but mighty stone tile courtyard.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/03/12/San%20Francisco%20Interior%20Stone%20Tile%20Courtyard%20with%20Synthetic%20Turf-1.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Tile%20Interior%20Courtyard%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Project%20profile%20of%20an%20interior%20courtyard%20in%20San%20Francisco%20featuring%20Norstone%20Grey%20Basalt%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Stone%20Tile%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone Dimension Stone Design Manual Review – Chapter 3: Dimension Stone Selection</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/dimension-stone-design-manual-review-dimension-stone-selection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone Dimension Stone Design Manual Review – Chapter 3: Dimension Stone Selection" /><published>2020-03-10T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-dimension-stone-design-manual-review-chapter-3-dimension-stone-selection</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/dimension-stone-design-manual-review-dimension-stone-selection/">&lt;p&gt;Published by the Natural Stone Institute, the Dimension Stone Design Manual, DSDM for short, is a key resource for the natural stone building industry. Over the next couple weeks we are going to explore some specific chapters of the DSDM to learn more about industry standard for dimensional building stone with specific applicability to Norstone natural stone veneer products. Today we are discussing chapter 3, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.naturalstoneinstitute.org/pub/2c34e470-d6f6-9967-5b03-11493b1b125e&quot;&gt;Dimension Stone Selection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/10/Dimension Stone Design Manual Cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover of the Natural Stone Institute's Dimension Stone Design Manual&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A high level summary of Chapter 3 of the DSDM covers the physical attributes of stone (aesthetics and appearance), considerations for designing and using natural stone in a construction project, and guidelines for stone testing, sampling, cost and maintenance. Let’s quickly run through each of these topics and get a better understanding of each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physical Attributes of Stone.&lt;/strong&gt; The physical attributes of stone are an important detail to understand when evaluating any natural stone product for use on a project. As the DSDM details out, there are a variety of different things to consider when thinking about the aesthetic and appearance. There are the obvious considerations, such as the visual attributes of the product like color, fit and finish of the stone, but as the DSDM states, just as important are the unseen attributes such as the strength and durability of the stone, which directly correlate to how appropriate a particular product is for the intended application. Furthermore, variegation and expected natural variation differ from source to source. Some of the most popular finishes we see in today’s market are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Polished. Most commonly defined by being so glossy, that you can see your reflection in the face of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Honed. Similar to Polished in that it’s smooth and silky to touch, but not glossy, more of a dull sheen where reflections are not noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Natural Cleft. Most common for wall cladding, and specifically highlighting the natural cut face of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Fine Rubbed. Newer to the market, but very popular — This is a flat finish, free of scratches, with no sheen whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Thermaled or Flamed. Planed surface, but rough textured due to the application of heat and water. Changes the look of the underlying stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/10/Dimension Stone Design Manual - Stone Finishes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dimensional stone shown in polished and saw cut finishes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Norstone’s range of products are available in a variety of colors and finishes including our traditional split face rock panel systems as well as our polished modern veneer product series like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc&lt;/a&gt; and Aksent 3D Panels. Nearly all of our products are durable enough that they are rated for both interior and exterior use, however all of our products are only rated for wall applications as they have not been designed nor tested for things like slip resistance, which are required for flooring materials for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suitability Considerations of your Selection.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the considerations that the DSDM covers regarding designing and using natural stone in various projects focuses around making sure that the stone selected is a good fit for the intended usage. From making sure that the type of product being used, whether its loose stone, a modular panel system, or a tile, is a good fit for the application, to ensuring that the product is rated for the application it is intended to be used in (for example interior vs exterior, freeze / thaw, etc), there are lots of considerations that factor in to making sure the right stone is selected for the requirements and specifics of each job. This is an area where working with a knowledgeable expert, whether its the architect or designer, stone manufacturer’s rep, or industry expert can save the project time and money by making sure the product selected is suitable avoiding future early replacement of an incorrectly specified product. Some of the most important suitability factors to consider when selecting stone are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interior Only vs Exterior Rated Products. Almost all natural stone products can be used on interior applications, but only certain natural stone should be used in exterior applications based on freeze / thaw cycling, thermal expansion and contraction, and absorption and porosity of the stone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water Resistance. Dense stone with a low absorption coefficient will produce the best results for exterior natural stone applications or interior applications subject to frequent water exposure such as fountains and showers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heavy vs Light Duty. Natural stone should be selected based on the expected traffic volume on the material. Areas with a heavy volume of traffic over or against the stone are best served by natural stone with maximum resistance such as granite and quartzite. Lower volume traffic areas where scratching and staining are less of a concern can explore less durable stone options such as highly polished finishes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/10/Dimension Stone Design Manual - Stone Suitability for Exterior Applications.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dimension Stone shown used in an exterior pool water feature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stone Testing, Sampling, &amp;amp; Maintenance.&lt;/strong&gt; Chapter 3 of the Dimension Stone Design Manual then goes onto cover guidelines for stone testing, sampling, cost and maintenance. Important considerations when it comes to testing, sampling and maintenance are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ASTM testing. ASTM International develops and publishes technical standard for a wide range of products and services including natural stone building materials. Make sure a natural stone building material being considered for a project has been tested according to the relevant ASTM standards and those results are published or readily available from the manufacturer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sampling. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-importance-of-samples-in-any-stone-or-tile-project/&quot;&gt;Natural stone manufacturers should provide samples&lt;/a&gt; for purposes of evaluation and submittal for both commercial and residential projects. Often times multiple samples are needed to show the complete range of variation in a particular stone and for large projects a temporary “mock up” installation is usually performed to show both the stone and its natural variation but also to address site specific installation conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initial and Ongoing Maintenance. It is important to recognize that natural stone might have both initial and ongoing maintenance routines that need performed to maintain the natural beauty of the product. These maintenance guidelines should be published by the manufacturer and might include recommend ways to clean the stone of installation related stains and specific types of products that can or should not be used with the specific type of stone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sealing. Many types of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;natural stone should be sealed&lt;/a&gt; dependent on the type of application where it is used. Sealers are available in a variety of different types including water and solvent based, topical and penetrating, and in a wide range of finishes such as matte or high gloss. Testing a sealer application on an off cut or sample of the stone is recommended as is setting up a maintenance schedule to reseal the stone per the sealer manufacturer’s recommended timeline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/03/10/Dimension Stone Design Manual - Stone Maintenance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Natural Stone Patio being cleaned as part of routine ongoing maintenance of natural stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Norstone we take pride in being ready to answer our client’s questions about testing which we have had completed by independent labs for all of our products and maintenance, which we publish a guidelines on and have a wealth of experience with having manufactured and sold natural stone wall veneer panels for over 15 years. We also recognized early on that having a reliable and well thought out system to effectively sample products to our clients both near and far was going to be important to getting our products out in the marketplace so we developed sample kits as well individual samples that are both mounted to a thin MDF backer to ensure durability in both mailing and handling and functional with an info packed sticker on the back covering the highlights of what is most important to know about the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dimension Stone Design Manual published by the Natural Stone Institute is a great resource for anyone working in the natural stone building materials field, whether you’re a manufacturer, specifier, or installer, the information in the DSDM is the basis for understanding natural stone building materials, selecting the right material for your project and installing it successfully. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;Norstone natural stone wall veneer products&lt;/a&gt; have been extensively tested and our knowledgeable technical support team is ready and willing to assist with questions related to the successful installation of our products per DSDM standards – contact us today to learn more and get your questions answered.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Every couple weeks we are going to highlight a chapter in the Dimension Stone Design Manual. The DSDM is published by the Natural Stone Institute and is the go to for technical information about using all types of stone in construction. This week we're deep diving into chapter 3 which covers different things to consider when selecting dimensional stone.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/03/10/Dimension%20Stone%20Design%20Manual%20-%20Stone%20Suitability%20for%20Exterior%20Applications-1.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Dimension%20Stone%20Design%20Manual%20Review%20Dimension%20Stone%20Selection%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Review%20of%20the%20Natural%20Stone%20Institute's%20Dimension%20Stone%20Design%20Manual%20Review%20Chapter%203%20dealing%20with%20dimension%20stone%20selection%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Get Ready for Spring with a Stacked Stone Pool Water Feature</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-pool-water-feature/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get Ready for Spring with a Stacked Stone Pool Water Feature" /><published>2020-02-24T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-24T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/get-ready-for-spring-with-a-stacked-stone-pool-water-feature</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-pool-water-feature/">&lt;p&gt;Whether Spring is in full swing or maybe where you are Winter is still firmly in place, there’s no better time than the first couple months of the year to start planning and executing on a backyard pool project. Getting started early makes sure that come peak summertime you’re going to be relaxing in a floating lounge instead of looking at a big hole in your backyard. This week’s featured project is a great inspiration as to how stacked stone can be used as part of a raised beam project. Let’s take a quick look at this project that used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; and see why and how it’s a great use of stacked stone for a pool water feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/02/25/Stacked Stone Pool Water Feature-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Stacked Stone Panels used on a pool raised beam water feature with three tiers and three waterfalls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that really catches our eye about this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone pool water feature&lt;/a&gt; is the design of the raised beam itself. The beam actually has three separate levels stretching almost the entire length of the back of this pool. The lowest level introduces the stacked stone above the waterline tile and then the two highest levels step up and include beautiful waterfalls that create a sheer curtain of water into the pool. This multi step design not only looks great, but it really creates more elevation contrast than you might be able to reasonably create with a single level raised beam feature. That higher elevation really accentuates the waterfalls and makes that an impressive feature of the stacked stone pool water feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A subtle but important part of the design of this stacked stone pool water feature is the decision to keep the waterline tile the same all around the entire pool and opt not to use the stacked stone all the way down to the waterline. Norstone Rock Panels can be used in submerged applications, but from a design standpoint and an ongoing maintenance standpoint it makes a lot more sense to use the same waterline tile as the rest of the pool. The tile in this application is a standard 5x5 ceramic pool tile that is nicely color matched to the brown and grey earth tones of the Ochre XL Stacked Stone Panels. The ceramic tiles will essentially be maintenance free whereas the stone would need sealed in a waterline application, and by maintaining the waterline tile consistent all the way around the pool there was not awkward vertical transition point between the much thinner ceramic tile and the thicker stacked stone panels that would have needed to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/02/25/Stacked Stone Pool Water Feature with Waterfalls-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side View of Norstone Ochre XL Stacked Stone Panels used on a pool raised beam water feature with three tiers showing miter cut outside corners&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talk a lot about our corner units and how easy they are, but are also always impressed when a contractor does a well executed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;outside corner miter cut&lt;/a&gt; we see in this project. With probably only about 3 total lineal feet of outside corners on this project, miter cutting field units into outside corner units is not particularly tedious or time consuming, and as you can see when done well, a miter cut outside corner on a stacked stone wall looks great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/02/25/Stacked Stone Pool Raised Beam Water Feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Stacked Stone Panels used on a pool raised beam with extensive landscaping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final thing we really appreciate about this project is how well the planter bed behind the stacked stone raised beam was landscaped. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/pools/&quot;&gt;Stacked stone pool projects&lt;/a&gt; definitely fall into the “hardscape” category so it’s especially important to bring in other design elements to soften the space up. This was probably a little challenging with the higher than normal elevation of this stacked stone raised beam pool project, but a combination of tropical plants and a small palm tree do a fantastic job of softening up the hard look of the stone and paver coping while adding to the relaxed vibe that most backyard pools are looking to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this quick tour around this fantastic stacked stone pool water feature has got you geared up and ready for some fun times this summer. Now is the time to get working on pool projects so that come summer you are enjoying your pool not waiting for it to be done. Contact our sales team today to learn more about how our stacked stone products can be used for all types of pool projects including raised beams and waterline tiles.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Stacked stone is a fantastic choice for a pool water feature project. In this week's blog we're featuring a multi level raised beam project clad in Norstone Ochre XL Series Rock Panels with three separate water falls. Let's take a week in this week's project profile about what makes the stacked stone look so classic and appealing for pool water features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/02/25/Stacked%20Stone%20Pool%20Water%20Feature%20with%20Waterfalls.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Pool%20Water%20Feature%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Pool%20Water%20Feature%20with%20multiple%20levels%20and%20three%20waterfalls%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Stacked Stone Panels for Landscaping</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-panels-for-landscaping/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Stacked Stone Panels for Landscaping" /><published>2020-02-18T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-18T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/using-stacked-stone-panels-for-landscaping</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-panels-for-landscaping/">&lt;p&gt;When our Australian founder first created Norstone almost 20 years ago the product was intended to be used primarily as an exterior application to clad planters, garden walls, retaining walls and other landscape based applications. Pretty early on it became clear that the product was equally suite to interior applications but we’ve never lost sight of the landscape market and have seen our product used on some great applications. In this week’s blog we’re going to explore some of the common uses of stacked stone panels for landscaping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/02/19/Stacked Stone Landscaping Planter Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Basalt Interlocking Tiles used on a multi level landscape planter wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planter walls are the most common application of stacked stone panels or natural stone veneer for landscaping. Raised planter beds, particularly those in commercial projects, are normally going to be built out of concrete block or poured in place concrete and so the stacked stone panels become an important part of the project to turn those planter bed walls from drab and dreary to something worth looking at. The photo above shows &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile&lt;/a&gt; in the Grey Basalt color used in extensively on planter walls in the common areas of a multi family housing project. We really like the multi level design of these planter walls which keeps the plants at ground level, knee height and waist height. Natural Stone is a great choice for this type of application because its durable and will stand up to the rigors of an exterior environment and since it is a natural product, creates good synergy in the design since the landscape beds are naturally abundant in vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/02/19/Stacked Stone Landscaping Fire Pit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Basalt Interlocking Tiles used on a large rectangular fire pit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire pits are a common extension of the planter wall concept in that they are designed for outdoor use and are most often going to be found in the hardscape/ landscaping part of the design. One of the interesting things about using a stacked stone panel product like Norstone is that while &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/&quot;&gt;stacked stone can be installed on radius walls&lt;/a&gt;, most fire pits are going to have too severe a radius to install a panel system product on.  Square and rectangular fire pits like the one we see here make up for that deficiency and look great particularly with gas burners that are often a long and skinny in shape. Most fire pits will be at knee level and below and should intentionally be spaced at an adequate distance from flammable material like plantings and vegetation. Most gas fire pits will come with some sort of “media” to cover up the burners, ranging from lava rock as seen in the example above to colored glass chips. The traditional look of stacked stone pairs will with the tumbled appearance of the lava rock whereas a more modern glass media will work well with a smooth face natural stone veneer product like Aksent 3D Panels or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Tile Sets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/02/19/Stacked Stone Landscaping Retaining Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XLX used on a large retaining wall seperating an upper garden area and a lower stone patio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The king of the hill when it comes to stacked stone landscaping projects are retaining walls. Retaining walls generally are going to separate out two different elevation levels in the landscaping plan and thus form an important visual element of an exterior landscaping project. The retaining wall shown above using our Ochre XLX Series Rock Panels and features an upper yard and garden that gives way below to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;hardscaped natural stone patio&lt;/a&gt;. While the stacked stone panels are merely a decorative top layer on the actual retaining wall that is doing the heavy work of keeping the upper elevation held back, natural stone is a fantastic application for a retaining wall since it conveys strength and durability – everything you’d want in a retaining wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just some examples of ways our stacked stone panels and natural stone veneer products can be used in landscaping applications. The great thing about these products is that they really allow you to think outside the box and use them in creative ways, so if you’re working on a landscaping project this Spring and want to learn more about how stacked stone panels might be a great addition to the job contact Norstone to get samples and start designing the landscaping project of your dreams!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Believe it or not, Norstone Rock Panels started out as a landscaping product almost 20 years ago. With Spring right around the corner and our focus starting to shift outside let's take a look at what makes stacked stone panels and natural stone veneer products a great fit for landscaping projects.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/02/19/Stacked%20Stone%20Landscaping%20Retaining%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Panels%20for%20Landscaping%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Introduction%20on%20using%20stacked%20stone%20panels%20for%20landscaping%20projects%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ivory Stacked Stone Fireplace Enhances a Denver area Coffee Shop</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stacked-stone-fireplace-coffee-shop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ivory Stacked Stone Fireplace Enhances a Denver area Coffee Shop" /><published>2020-01-27T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-27T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stacked-stone-fireplace-enhances-a-denver-area-coffee-shop</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stacked-stone-fireplace-coffee-shop/">&lt;p&gt;Denver’s an amazing city with a real strong connection to stone in its architecture and design. What’s really cool about Denver is that since its such a progressive and fast growing city you not only see the traditional large format and hand stacked stone look but you also see more contemporary and modern inspired natural stone all over the place. The coffee shop we are featuring as this week’s project profile is a nice mix of that old and new style – the stacked stone / ledge stone style texture of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Standard Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; is packaged in a sleek, geometric pattern that gives this fireplace a traditional texture in a modern design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/27/Ivory Stacked Stone Fireplace in Coffee Shop-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Stacked Stone Rock Panels on a fireplace installation in a coffee shop in Denver, CO&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory stone&lt;/a&gt; is one of our most favorite colors – the creamy undertones give it much more warmth than our White Quartz color and the color movement down into the deep yellow and gold tones really gives the product a lot of character. We love the light and open color pallete and feel of the Coffee Shop with large windows letting in lots of natural light, high loft style ceilings and the light pear colored base wall colors. Retail tends to shy away from color palletes like this one but when someone is bold enough to take the risk it really creates something unique and special. Pale burnt orange casual lounge furniture serves as a nice accent color in the overall scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/27/Ivory Stacked Stone Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Stacked Stone Rock Panels installed on a fireplace as part of a retail space build out&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stone installation itself on this project is something many of our customers work with quite often – where the fireplace itself is flush against the wall, so when the stacked stone panels get applied they need to figure out what to do with the exposed edges. Many fireplaces stand out from the wall, anywhere from the width of a brick to much larger, creating a return from the face of the fireplace back to the main wall that can easily be handled using one of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;stacked stone finger jointed outside corner units&lt;/a&gt;. In applications like this one where the fireplace is already flush with the main wall, a great technique to cover the exposed edge of the stacked stone panel is to trim out the edges as has been done on this installation with a stainless steel trim piece. Stainless steel trim is a great option, especially if it matches the finish of the fireplace insert or fits in well with a modern inspired décor scheme, but more simple wooden trim, particularly if painted to match either the base boards or crown molding can look just as great and serve the purpose of covering the exposed edge of the stacked stone panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/27/Ivory Stacked Stone Fireplace with Metal Trim.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Stacked Stone Rock Panels on a fireplace installation with metal trim pieces to cover the exposed edge of the panel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retail build outs are a special type of project as most retail relies on heavy traffic in and out of the space. That heavy traffic,which is critical to the success of the retail establishment, also exacts a toll on the finishes in the space. Natural stone and especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/large-stone-veneer-mall-of-america/&quot;&gt;stacked stone is a great finish option for a retail build out&lt;/a&gt; due to its durability. The fireplace in this coffee shop will no doubt see plenty of use and abuse, whether that’s people bumping furniture, bags, shoes and boots, and sometimes even themselves into the stone, the finish here will absorb the blows and outlast most of the other finishes in the space. For a wall covering option with long term durability, a natural stone wall veneer option is an excellent choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this quick look around the fireplace out there at our favorite coffee shop in Denver was useful and informative. Some of the installation details of this job, particularly the stainless steel trim piece used to hide the cut edge of the panels is really well done and is a great solution for any project, residential or commercial. Whether you’re working on a fireplace, a retail build out or any other project where stacked stone is being considered give our design experts a call to learn more about our line up of amazing natural stacked stone veneers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our Ivory Stacked Stone Rock Panels are a great finish for the fireplace in this Denver area Coffee Shop to help keep the space light and bright. We're going to have a look at this space in this week's project profile blog and see how they did a few interesting things, like metal stripping along the sides of the stone, to simplify the installation and make the end result look great!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/01/27/Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%20in%20Coffee%20Shop.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%20Coffee%20Shop%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20Rock%20Panels%20featured%20on%20a%20fireplace%20application%20in%20a%20coffee%20shop%20in%20Denver,%20CO%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New Planc Pattern Guide to Inspire your Next Project</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-large-format-tile-pattern-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Planc Pattern Guide to Inspire your Next Project" /><published>2020-01-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/new-planc-pattern-guide-to-inspire-your-next-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-large-format-tile-pattern-guide/">&lt;p&gt;When we introduced our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Tile&lt;/a&gt; product in mid 2018 one of the things that intrigued us must about the product was the design possibilities that existed with the product from a pattern standpoint. The product itself is a three piece set – each piece is 31.5” long and each set has tiles that are 5.5”, 2.4”, and 3.1” tall. The product was designed with symmetry in mind in that the height of the two smaller pieces totaled up to the height of the larger piece. One of the most rewarding things about this product has been introducing it to designers and seeing immediately where their mind goes to in terms of layout and pattern. While a designer’s mind sees all the possibilities of this product right from the start, we wanted to give our non-designer clients a tool to comprehend the pattern possibilities of this product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/27/Planc Large Format Tile Pattern Guide-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Large Format Tile Pattern Guide showing 6 popular patterns to install Planc in&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pattern guide above now lives within the brochure and specification sheet for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Tile product&lt;/a&gt;. For this pattern guide we picked 6 of the most interesting yet approachable patterns that the Planc product can be installed in. Some of our favorites from this guide are the soldier stacked pattern with grouted joints that was prominently featured in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/platinum-planc-project-revisited/&quot;&gt;Platinum Planc project&lt;/a&gt; that was completed in Hollywood, CA and that we featured in our blog project profile series last year. The dimensionalized running bond is another pattern that we really love. This pattern takes the easy and simple to install running bond pattern, but dimensionalizes certain pieces within each set to create a 3D effect. The pieces are dimensionalized by inserting tile spacers into the setting bed and can be dimensionalized at random or according to a set pattern depending on taste. The herringbone pattern is one that we haven’t seen done yet on a project, but are eager to work with a project that is willing and ready to take it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/27/Planc Large Format Tile Straight Stack Pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Large Format Tile shown installed in a straight stack with grout joints on a fireplace project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pattern guide represents a very small amount of the total number of overall patterns possible with the Planc Large Format Tile product. Symmetrical patterns where the two smaller pieces meet up with the large tile and are installed in either a straight stack or running bond pattern is another whole area of design that haven’t even been explored yet. This product really encourages you to think outside the box and has the possibility to create a truly one of a kind look for a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/27/Planc Large Format Tile Herringbone Pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Large Format Tile shown laid out in a Herringbone pattern&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing important to consider when installing Planc Large Format Tile in a pattern is that the pattern will probably be a bit more challenging than installing it in a simple running bond format. Doing your homework with the installer and making sure they know what the pattern it is and how to address areas like corners, outlets, etc is a good first step. The labor rate for installation will probably have a small premium, but will be well worth it assuming the installer knows exactly what they are doing and see the project through to a successful completion. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-pattern-impacts-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;Patterns can also impact how much waste or overage is required for a natural stone project&lt;/a&gt;, so if you are thinking about a pattern make sure to plan it out and lay it out before even ordering material so you get the order right the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you love the size and scale of Planc, take your project to the next level by using one of the patterns in our new pattern guide, or creating a pattern unique to your project. If a specific pattern or understanding how a pattern overlays on your specific project contact us today and one of our helpful team members can review your details and offer assistance. Planc Large Format Tiles are a beautiful product and will look even more amazing when installed in a pattern, so we encourage everyone to think beyond just a running bond stack and show us the amazing patterns you come up with for your next stone veneer project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We recently created a Pattern Guide for our Planc Large Format Tile Series. Planc is such a versatile product in terms of pattern, this really only scrapes the surface of what's possible. Take a look and be inspired for your next project!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/01/27/Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Pattern%20Guide.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Pattern%20Guide%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Pattern%20Guide%20for%20the%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Series%20Product%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Basalt Lynia Tiles for Large Monument Sign</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-lynia-natural-stone-tiles-monument-sign/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Basalt Lynia Tiles for Large Monument Sign" /><published>2020-01-20T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-20T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-basalt-lynia-tiles-for-large-monument-sign</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-lynia-natural-stone-tiles-monument-sign/">&lt;p&gt;First impressions matter and that’s especially true when it comes to colleges and universities. Not only do they want to appeal to both the prospective student, who might be more interested in the college being perceived as “cool”, but equally appeal to the prospective student’s parents who are probably most interested in making sure the college is going to set their child up for success during their tenure and in the future. A small college on the West Coast of Florida worked with one of our tile distributors many years ago to replace the aging signage at the main entrance to their campus. A modern look and color scheme was desired and the product selected was our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/ebony/&quot;&gt;Basalt Ebony Lynia Interlocking Tile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/20/Ebony Lynia Monument Wall Signage-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Basalt Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tiles on a large monument wall under construction for entryway signage at a college in Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sign itself, shown under construction in the photo above, is a long and linear blade wall that sits on a large elevated sill. The design of the wall really fits well with the layout and sizing of the Lynia Interlocking wall tiles which consist of nine strips that are each twelve inches long and come in three different heights, mesh mounted onto a backer system with an interlocking pattern. The Lynia Interlocking tiles create a very long linear look which was perfect for the scale and size of the sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Color also played an important part in selecting material for this project. The great contrast between the formed white concrete sill and dark black of the Ebony Basalt Lynia Interlocking tiles is a classic color combination that looks stylish and modern in the design of this monument sign.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grouting-lynia-mosaic-tile/&quot;&gt;Lynia Tiles are then grouted&lt;/a&gt;, the grout color selected here being a slightly lighter grey than the Ebony of the stone itself, which creates a nice contrast without the super precise spacing demands a white or similar light colored grout would create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/20/Ebony Lynia Monument Wall Signage Corner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Basalt Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tiles on a large monument wall featuring the outside corner detail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blade wall of the sign is essentially one CMU block wide, and since the Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tiles were meant to go on all four sides of the blade wall, the short edges needed some thought and consideration by the installation team. A couple years ago we ended up making pre-fabricated outside corner units for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking tile series&lt;/a&gt;, but this installation took place well before that and still achieved a great result using a technique where the installer “framed in” the outside corner using strips of the tile set vertically. These single vertical strips were pulled right off the backer of a regular field unit and can easily be miter cut or simply but joined into another vertical strip to form the corner. Once the vertical strips “frame” the outside corners, the Lynia Interlocking tile is installed and simply terminates into the strip in a straight cut. On the short end of the blade wall the installation team chose simply to run straight pieces across and not bother trying to show any of the pattern of the Lynia tile since the relative space with which they had to tile here was so small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/20/Ebony Lynia Monument Wall Signage College Entrance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Basalt Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tiles on a large monument wall with signage at the entryway to a college in Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result, with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-signage-on-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;signage mounted on the stone wall&lt;/a&gt; and the area re-landscaped is beautiful. This sign is big enough to easily catch your attention when driving down the road and the great design and overall beauty of it matches the spirit of the great college that it represents. One of the exceedingly cool things we get to do is see Norstone projects not just during or after they get installed, but years later, which happened to me recently with this particular project. On my way to and from a family vacation at the beach I got a chance to pass by this signage many times and can confirm it looks just as great as it did during these installation photos and also looks amazing both during the day and at a nighttime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural stone is a great choice for monument signage because it is not only incredibly durable and will likely last until the next re-design, it also creates a strong connection between the timeless style and durability of natural stone and whatever or whomever the signage represents. Whether its a prestigious college, the entrance to a neighborhood, or the reception desk at your favorite restaurant, natural stone tiles make a great first impression.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">A few years back our Ebony Basalt Lynia tiles were selected as part of a large monument sign at the entrance to a college in Florida. I drove by this sign a couple weeks ago and it looks as good today as it did when it was installed many years ago. I dug up some photos we had of the original installation and we'll cover why natural stone is a great choice fo monument signs in this week's blog</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/01/20/Ebony%20Lynia%20Monument%20Wall%20Signage.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Basalt%20Lynia%20Natural%20Stone%20Tiles%20for%20Monument%20Sign%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Basalt%20Lynia%20Natural%20Stone%20tiles%20used%20for%20a%20large%20monument%20sign%20at%20the%20entrance%20to%20a%20college%20in%20Florida%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Crossing the Threshold - Bringing the Outside In with Natural Stone Veneer Installations</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/interior-exterior-stone-veneer-installations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crossing the Threshold - Bringing the Outside In with Natural Stone Veneer Installations" /><published>2020-01-17T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-17T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/crossing-the-threshold-bringing-the-outside-in-with-natural-stone-veneer-installations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/interior-exterior-stone-veneer-installations/">&lt;p&gt;Natural Stone Veneer products are associated with both interior and exterior installations. Exterior wise natural stone veneer has a long relationship as a building cladding and interior wise projects like fireplaces have had natural stone veneer as a “go to”. We love it when a designer takes it next level and creates a visual where the stone crosses the threshold and continues a natural stone veneer installation on both the interior and exterior. Let’s take a look today at a couple examples of “crossing the threshold” and see what makes each one so special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/17/Interior and Exterior Natural Stone Veneer Entryway.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Slimline Rock Panels used on both the interior and exterior of a residential entryway&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first project features our Ochre Slimline Natural Stone Veneer Panels as part of a residential entryway. What’s cool about this project is that not only does the stone start outside as an exterior veneer, it continues on through both a large exterior door and glass entryway, and then again through a more delicate frame-less glass secondary door separating the vestibule from the foyer. The stone then continues on through the foyer using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;outside corner units&lt;/a&gt; to wrap around into the living area. We love the use of glass as part of both partitions to really help create that open feel that ties the outside to the inside in this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/17/Interior and Exterior Natural Stone Veneer Modern Home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XLX Series Rock Panels used on both the interior and exterior of a residential living room and back patio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The back of a home is ideally suite or an interior / exterior bridge of natural stone veneer as we see here in this beautifully modern home in the North Carolina mountains. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Norstone Charcoal XLX Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; are clad the main feature wall of the living space and then extend directly outside as part of an architectural detailed open archway. Collapsing glass sliding doors create a true “openness” to the space and allows for clean line of sight between the interior and exterior on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/17/Interior and Exterior Natural Stone Veneer Living Room-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Platinum Planc Large Format Tiles used on both the interior and exterior of a residential living room and pool area&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project is featuring our modern styled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc large format tiles&lt;/a&gt; in the Platinum color, which is a beautiful natural stone veneer product made from saw cut lavastone. The exterior of a home is again featured here with the stone going from an interior feature wall outside to a patio and pool area. What’s most impressive tome about this stone veneer installation is the installer’s attention to detail on the patterning of the tile installation. The installation is done in a straight stacked pattern where the tiles are given a grout joint both horizontally against the next row of tiles and vertically between the straight stacks. Not only does the pattern continue outside, the sizing doesn’t even skip a beat as it transitions over the door thresholds which is the sort of small attention to the detail that make a project like this extra special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/17/Interior and Exterior Natural Stone Veneer Bathroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Slimline Rock Panels used on both the interior and exterior of a residential master bathroom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen front entryways and back patios, so apart from looking awesome, what makes this next project super special is that it’s a bathroom! This super &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-bathrooms/&quot;&gt;modern stone bathroom&lt;/a&gt; in Dallas, TX has Norstone Grey Basalt Aksent 3D stone veneer installed as part of a feature wall which extends from the mater math outside into a private courtyard. Glass again is the common element with this installation, serving really only to keep the weather out, and minimizing the break point between the interior and exterior stone veneer installations. An open and airy bathroom like this might not be for someone who is looking for a lot of privacy, but sure is a unique look for a space that often overlooks trying to incorporate exterior elements into the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoyed this quick tour of some awesome natural stone veneer projects that “cross the threshold” and bring the outside in, or sometimes bring the inside out, in an effort to create innovative and great looking design. If you’re an architect, designer, or just a homeowner looking to create something special with a natural stone veneer installation contact us today to learn more about our award winning natural stone products.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We're focused specifically on installations this week that start the natural stone veneer on the outside and then bring it inside as an interior finish. Let's take a look today at a couple projects that do a great job bringing the outside in with their natural stone veneer installations.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/01/17/Interior%20and%20Exterior%20Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Living%20Room.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Interior%20&amp;%20Exterior%20Stone%20Veneer%20Installations%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Stone%20Veneer%20Installations%20where%20the%20stone%20is%20installed%20in%20a%20continuous%20manner%20between%20the%20interior%20and%20exterior%20of%20a%20project%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Basalt Grey Aksent 3D Modern Stone Veneer Fireplace</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-grey-modern-stone-veneer-fireplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basalt Grey Aksent 3D Modern Stone Veneer Fireplace" /><published>2020-01-16T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-16T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-grey-aksent-3d-modern-stone-veneer-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-grey-modern-stone-veneer-fireplace/">&lt;p&gt;When most people think about using stone on a fireplace project the traditional looks where the stone is in its naturally cleft or split face state is probably what comes to mind. At Norstone we’ve spent a lot of time developing not only beautiful split face products for that traditional look and feel, but also amazing product lines using smooth faced stone veneer to give your walls that modern vibe that’s so popular right now. One of those product lines is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Natural Stone Panel&lt;/a&gt;, which is product which takes beautifully polished natural stones, such as Basalt, Quartzite, and Marble and assembles them into a multi dimensional mosaic panel that is installed as a groutless wall tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/16/Basalt Grey Aksent 3D Modern Stone Veneer Fireplace-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Basalt Grey Aksent 3D Modern Stone Veneer Panels used on a modern styled fireplace in Tampa,FL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project we are featuring in this week’s blog is a stunning modern styled fireplace that used our Aksent 3D Panels in the Grey Basalt color on a floor to ceiling installation. This isn’t a huge project, but it’s got some really cool elements that you just don’t see everyday. The first thing that really stands out is the use of the Aksent 3D Panels in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/&quot;&gt;vertical orientation&lt;/a&gt;. The traditional orientation on natural stone panel system products is for the long axis of the panel to be run horizontally, but we always love it when someone thinks outside the box and turns the product 90 degrees and installs them vertically. The vertical orientation makes the already tall ceilings in this room look even taller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that does happen when a product like Aksent 3D Panels get installed in a vertical orientation is that our pre-assembled finger joint outside corner units no longer can be used for vertical outside corners like we see on both sides of this fireplace application. With a product like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/grey/&quot;&gt;Grey Basalt in Aksent 3D&lt;/a&gt;, the saw cut edge of the panel is going to look a little lighter in color than the polished face, but as you can see here the installer positioned the panels so that stone on the face extends a little out beyond the corner and the stone on the short returns back to the main wall tuck in right behind the face panels. A more complex method would have been to miter cut a panel along the long axis, but I think most would agree the results here look great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2020/01/16/Basalt Grey Aksent 3D Modern Stone Veneer Glass Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Basalt Grey Aksent 3D Modern Stone Veneer Panels used on a modern styled fireplace with a linear gas fireplace insert and built in flat screen tv&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really also like the fireplace unit itself. The long linear style of this gas fireplace insert is definitely trending in terms of modern design, but there are a few details like the partial glass partition and the super thin stainless steel border that make it more special than most.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;Glass is a great modern design element&lt;/a&gt;, and we love how the glass is there in this fireplace for safety reasons but in such a minimalistic way it doesn’t detract at all.  The author personally really likes the back wall of this fireplace which is painted the same color as the rest of the room. Having never seen that done before, it really hits the point home about how clean a gas fireplace unit like this really is. Situated in Tampa, FL, this fireplace is a lot more about great looking design than required heat output and is basically a beautiful art piece in this home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last detail that goes almost unnoticed on most folks is the cleverly disguised surround sound speakers that are deftly cut out and installed right into the stone installation on either side and below the television. If the center channel below the speaker had been oriented vertically we might not even have seen these since they blend in so well with stone not only from a color but also from a sizing standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a fireplace is on your project list for 2020 we hope this project gave you a little inspiration to consider a modern stone veneer option. With a variety of sizes, styles, and colors to pick from, and an installation that is as simple as laying tile, reach out to us at Norstone to learn more about which one of our modern stone veneer products might be a great fit for your fireplace project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">If you love natural stone, but prefer a more modern smooth aesthetic for the veneer selection, this week's project is right in your wheelhouse. Let's have a quick look around this amazing Basalt Grey Aksent 3D fireplace project done a couple years ago in Tampa, FL.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2020/01/16/Basalt%20Grey%20Aksent%203D%20Modern%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Basalt%20Grey%20Modern%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Project%20profile%20review%20of%20a%20fireplace%20project%20in%20Tampa,%20FL%20that%20used%20Norstone%20Basalt%20Grey%20Aksent%203D%20stone%20veneer%20panels%20on%20a%20modern%20styled%20fireplace%22%7D" /></entry></feed>