<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-24T07:25:17-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Is Drywall A Suitable Substrate for Stone Veneer?</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/is-drywall-good-for-stone-veneer-installations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Drywall A Suitable Substrate for Stone Veneer?" /><published>2018-10-22T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/is-drywall-a-suitable-substrate-for-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/is-drywall-good-for-stone-veneer-installations/">&lt;p&gt;Most people, the author included, that have ever swung a hammer in the name of home improvement have experienced the temptation to want to cut a corner every now and again.  Maybe it’s something as simple as working with your thinset to lay stone or tile right after you get done mixing it instead of letting it set for a few minutes, or possibly even something with a greater risk for danger, like changing out a light fixture but only turning the power off at the switch and not the breaker.  Working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt;, especially the ones that get used on a lot of renovations and remodel projects, we hear from customers frequently about cutting one corner in particular on the installation – whether or not the product can be installed over drywall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, the answer to that question is no, without any exceptions or conditions.  There are a number of suitable substrates for installing stone veneer, all of which are cementious based, such as cement board, brick, block, or a wooden substrate that has been prepared with a metal lath and masonry scratch coat.  Now that we got that out of the way, let’s take a look at why drywall isn’t a suitable substrate for stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/24/Side Profile View of Drywall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side profile view of a piece of drywall showing the paper outer layers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weight is the primary reason that drywall does not make a suitable substrate for a stone veneer installation.  Our stone veneers can weigh anywhere from about 7 to 13 lbs per square foot.  If you take a few minutes to study the composition of drywall, you’ll find a pretty basic product – essentially its gypsum between two heavy pieces of paper.  Drywall is a perfect product for interior walls and ceilings as its relatively lightweight, easy to install and work with, and can accept a variety of textures, paints, and lightweight veneer applications such as wall paper.  However, the physics don’t work when you start to think about hanging a heavy stone tile or panel that’s being bonded to the outer paper layer of the drywall with a wet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;cement based thinset setting material&lt;/a&gt;.  Not only is the paper layer not designed to hold that weight up, the moisture in the thinset is going to start off by compromising the integrity of that paper layer right from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/24/Norstone Stacked Stone Veneer Backsplash Installed over Cement Board.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels installed on cement board over existing drywall on a modern kitchen backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get the question so frequently about installing our stone veneer products over drywall because of its prevalence in the building industry and also that many of the products that our product is ideally suited for are likely going to have existing drywall already in place as the wall system.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;Back splashes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplaces&lt;/a&gt; are great examples of this.  Both are fantastic applications for stone veneer, but if the space is being remodeled, or even in the case of most new construction projects, drywall will likely be what’s currently in place because it’s inexpensive, easy, and prevalent in all other areas of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/24/Installing Cement Board over Drywall for a Stone Veneer Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cement board being installed over drywall in preparation for a stone veneer installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear not if the drywall has got your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY stone veneer project&lt;/a&gt; at a standstill!  Beyond the obvious solution of ripping out the existing drywall, getting back to the studs or furring strips, and rebuilding the wall for your stone veneer using cement board, there is another alternative.  Many of our customers end up leaving the drywall in place and simply covering it with .25” thick cement board.  The thinner cement board will have plenty of structural rigidity for most stone veneer projects seeing as though its gaining flexural strength from the existing drywall behind it.  Probably the most important part of a cover up installation like this is to make sure that you’re using screws that are long enough to go through both your cement board, existing drywall and still sink at least half way into your studs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a few minutes to learn why installing stone veneer over drywall is not a good idea.  We have a great team of knowledgeable reps with industry experience that are ready and willing to answer your stone veneer installation questions, so don’t hesitate to contact Norstone today to learn more and get your hard to answer questions answered.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We get this question a lot, and the answer every time is NO! Let's take a quick look at why installing a heavy product like stone veneer on drywall is not a good idea.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/24/Norstone%20Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20Backsplash%20Installed%20over%20Cement%20Board.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Veneer%20Backsplash%20Installed%20On%20Cement%20Board%20Over%20Drywall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Stone%20Veneer%20Backsplash%20installed%20on%20cement%20board%20over%20existing%20drywall%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Before and After – A Charcoal Stacked Stone Entryway Feature Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-feature-wall-before-and-after/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before and After – A Charcoal Stacked Stone Entryway Feature Wall" /><published>2018-10-16T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-a-charcoal-stacked-stone-entryway-feature-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-feature-wall-before-and-after/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we always tell clients before starting any project is to take a “before” picture of what their space looks like so they can have a great visual reference point to compare against what the finished project yields.  The author readily admits that sometimes even I forget to do this!  In the excitement of starting a new project most of us are so focused on wanting to see actual results that its easy to dive right into tearing out a wall, or ripping up a floor and forget to take that “before” picture.  We’re lucky that a client we recently worked with shared with us some awesome “before” and “after” pictures of their stacked stone entryway feature wall project where our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Charcoal Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; were used that we’ll be diving into on this week’s project profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/18/Entry Way Wall - Before.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Entry Way Wall - Before Stacked Stone Installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a “before” standpoint, the thing we really notice about this space is that the wall this client ends up cladding in stone veneer is actually less of a traditional entryway wall – it’s almost a reverse entryway in that the stone isn’t really going to be something you see when walking through the door, but instead becomes a focal point of that space of the larger room that the entryway opens up to.  Perhaps the most prominent feature of the “before” wall is the 90 degree outside corner that undoubtedly made selecting a product with a good corner solution a priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/18/Stacked Stone Entry Way Wall - After.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Entryway feature wall project with Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels and a recessed shelf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting onto the good stuff, the “after” picture of the space reveals an amazing transformation focused around the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt; stacked stone entryway feature wall&lt;/a&gt;.  The two big things that catch our eye is the recessed shelf that was added along the short wall and the prominent outside corner that looks absolutely fantastic with our corner units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recessed shelf is a really great idea in this application because it would have been fairly easy to add during the construction process when the existing drywall was either torn out and replaced with cement board, or covered up with cement board.  Built ins always up the level of sophistication of any home, so whether this ends up getting used to display a nice art piece or even just a convenient spot to drop your keys when walking in the door, this small add makes a big difference in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Norstone we really take our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;stacked stone corner units&lt;/a&gt; seriously.  And while that level of sophistication might get lost on some people, or might not be applicable for certain projects, it’s a project like this that really allows our unique finger jointed corner design to shine through.  This corner is not just an integral part of the installation, its at an extremely prominent part of this space.  The corner is the natural focal point of the larger room this area expands out to and is something everyone will be looking at as they walk down the stairs or out the door.  The interlocking stone fingers of each corner unit create the most seamless looking corner on the stone veneer market and ensure that no matter which angle you look at the corner you’ll always see the natural cleft face of the stone and never a saw cut or finished edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/18/Charcoal Stacked Stone Entry Way Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Entryway Feature Wall using Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels with recessed overhead lighting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, this next view of the stacked stone entryway feature wall shows off some awesome lighting that was added into the ceiling to face downward over the stone.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Good lighting is important for a stacked stone installation&lt;/a&gt; and we’re glad this project took that into consideration.  The other thing that really catches our eye from this angle is the nice color blend between the brown hardwood floors and the dark grey of the Charcoal Standard Series Rock Panel.  This classic combination of not only brown and grey but also wood and stone ensures this project won’t ever look like a trend that has since passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick “before” and “after” look at this project with us.  If you have your own “before” and “after” photos of a Norstone project, please share them with us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sales@norstoneusa.com&quot;&gt;sales@norstoneusa.com&lt;/a&gt; and we’ll use them on a future article.  And if you’re looking for help on your next stacked stone veneer project &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;give us a call&lt;/a&gt; and our experts will help make your “before” the “after” you’re dreaming of!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We love the before and after of this client's entryway project where they took a space with good bones and layout and really created a focal point for the space. Let's have a closer look at the before and afters and see what makes this stacked stone veneer project a winner!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/18/Stacked%20Stone%20Entry%20Way%20Wall%20-%20After.jpeg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Entryway%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Entryway%20Feature%20Wall%20project%20using%20Norstone%20Charcoal%20Standard%20Series%20Rock%20Panels%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Installing Stone Veneer over a Metal Substrate</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-on-metal-substrate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing Stone Veneer over a Metal Substrate" /><published>2018-10-10T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stone-veneer-over-a-metal-substrate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-on-metal-substrate/">&lt;p&gt;In just the past couple days we’ve heard from a handful of our clients and some of the installers that are working with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt; about how the product can be installed over a metal substrate.  There is actually a couple different ways to approach this type of installation, and metal actually shows up more often than you’d think as a substrate.  So let’s take a look at how stone veneer can be installed over metal substrates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the types of projects that you see metal projects on, almost all of the folks we’ve talked to recently have been working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplaces&lt;/a&gt;, which is a popular project at this time of the year as we’re all getting ready for winter and to start cranking up those fireplaces for heat very soon.  Most often the fireplace insert is going to have a metal flange, similar to a window,  that extends out along the wall that the fireplace is mounted on and that provides vertical anchoring points for the unit.  These flanges can vary in how far they extend out from barely two or three inches, to several inches.  Fireplace units with larger flanges are the ones where a different form of adhesive needs to be considered.  If the flange only sticks out an inch or two, and the overwhelming bulk of a stone veneer unit or natural stone tile is going to be adhered directly to the masonry wall substrate (block, brick, cement board, etc), then extra consideration about adhering stone to the metal substrate is probably not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/11/Fireplace Insert with Large Metal Flange.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fireplace Insert with a large metal flange to be installed and covered with stone veneer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other metal applications that we tend to see natural stone being used on are exterior applications of prefab buildings which often have exterior steel shells.  Our natural stone products have been used as a decorative top layer on prefab buildings of all kinds, including marinas, warehouse/industrial space, and even prefab railway sheds that sit along train lines in remote areas to house control and safety equipment.  More often than not, the metal building is in place for a very practical reason, especially since metal buildings can be cost effective to construct, and then the stone comes along later in an effort to spruce up the overall look of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another very common application is prefabricated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/&quot;&gt;outdoor kitchens and grills islands&lt;/a&gt;, which often can ship straight from the manufacturer preassembled with a  metal outer layer that can be clad with stone, or a variety of other materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/11/Stacked Stone Veneer on PreFab Outdoor Kitchen.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Veneer installed on a prefab outdoor kitchen with metal substrate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the actual installation of stone veneer over metal substrates, we recommend two different methods.  With either method, the first step is making sure the surface is clean of any contamination, such as dirt, rust, paint, etc.  Pressure washing and sand blasting are effective techniques to get a clean metal substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the metal substrate is clean your two options for installing stone veneer are to either tack weld a wire lathe to the steel and then build out that layer with thick bed mortar mix, which will set and then the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;stone veneer can be applied to using a traditional cementious based thinset&lt;/a&gt;.  An alternative option that eliminates the metal lathe and scratch coat  is apply the stone veneer directly to the metal substrate using an epoxy based tile adhesive.  Be sure to talk to the manufacturer of the stone, or a sales rep with good knowledge of tile setting materials for a specific recommendation on the epoxy adhesive to use.  Set the stone veneer using the epoxy adhesive according to the instructions of the adhesive manufacturer, and if you have any of the epoxy adhesive left over, you can likely use it up over other more standard substrates since epoxy adhesives adhere to almost any type of substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/11/Stacked Stone Veneer on Exterior of Metal Building.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Metal Building with stacked stone veneer accents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been fortunate enough to work on a lot of unique and different installation processes with our clients having operated Norstone over the past decade plus and seeing millions of square feet of stone veneer get sold and installed.  Installations over metal substrates is just one example of a unique condition that a product like stone veneer can easily adapt to.  If you have a unique installation condition you are considering stone veneer for, please don’t hesitate to contact our sales and technical teams for more information on how stone veneer can be successfully used on just about any project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Did you know that stone veneer can be installed over metal substrates? We've gotten this question a couple times from clients in the past couple days so figured it'd be a good topic to tackle in this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/11/Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20PreFab%20Outdoor%20Kitchen.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20prefab%20outdoor%20grill%20island%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Prefab%20outdoor%20grill%20island%20and%20summer%20kitchen%20with%20a%20metal%20substrate%20that%20has%20been%20clad%20with%20a%20stone%20veneer%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A One of A Kind Stone Bathroom</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/one-of-a-kind-stone-bathroom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A One of A Kind Stone Bathroom" /><published>2018-10-03T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/a-one-of-a-kind-stone-bathroom</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/one-of-a-kind-stone-bathroom/">&lt;p&gt;Natural stone is a great choice for bathroom projects because it helps evoke that spa like feel that really elevates a space.  This master bath renovation project took the natural stone design scheme and ran with it all the way to the goal line.  Beautiful flooring and an amazing textured wall of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Norstone Ochre XL Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; all lead up to the real show stopper, which is the amazing free standing one-piece natural stone tub.  Let’s take a look at all of those things and the awesome details that make this space noteworthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/04/Stacked Stone Bathroom Feature Wall with Freestanding Tub.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Feature Wall in a bathroom feauturing a freestanding one piece natural stone tub&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flooring has always been a primary use for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-bathrooms-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;natural stone in high end bathrooms&lt;/a&gt;.  We don’t have a ton of detail about the flooring used in this project, but visually we can tell its a large format tile that is either natural stone, or a high end porcelain version that uses HD printing and other technologies to very closely mimic the look of natural stone.  In recent years, porcelain tile manufacturing has gotten so good that its almost impossible to tell from pictures alone whether a product is natural stone or manufactured tile.  Regardless, the floor tile in this bathroom sets the color tone for the entire space which the tub, accent wall, and all other design elements work off of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stacked stone feature wall stands out from both a color and texture standpoint.  While still working within the base “earth tones” of the space, the Ochre XL Rock Panels also bring in a nice blend of accent colors, including some darker charcoals that work with the storage unit and inside of the tub, as well as some lighter brown and orange accents that complement the exposed wood beam on the ceiling.  The texture the wall creates is super important to the overall feel of the space, complementing the freestanding natural hewn tub.  The height of the room and the decision to go floor to ceiling with the stone helps give this feature wall an added visual impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/04/Stacked Stone Bathroom Feature Wall with Vintage Tub Hardware.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Stacked Stone on a bathroom feature wall showing a close up of vintage tub hardware&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small detail not to be missed is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;light fixture on the stone wall&lt;/a&gt;.  Positioned to illuminate the tub hardware and provide some low level ambient lighting to enjoy both a soak and a good book, this light fixture also does a great job of blending into the wall and not detracting from the stone feature wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving the best for last, the tub itself is really the focus of the space and in and of itself an incredibly unique design element.  One piece stone stubs are kind of like the Rolls Royce of bathrooms and you most often see them made from marble.  What is really cool about this particular tub is that the stone its made from has a very unique looking natural cleft to the outside of it as well as the overall shape of the tub.  To truly appreciate natural stone, you have to learn to appreciate the imperfections in nature and how those manifest themselves in finished products.  The asymmetrical nature of this tub really hits home that the beauty is in the imperfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the box design ideas aren’t for everyone when it comes to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/showers/&quot;&gt;bathroom design&lt;/a&gt; or remodel project, but they sure are fun to look and dream about for your own space.  If you are considering using stone in your next bathroom project give any of our product experts a call and we’d be happy to walk you through our line of veneers that can help take your project to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We see a lot of bathroom project photos come across our desk, but this one definitely stands out! There's amazing stone and natural details everywhere you look – come take a peek with us and get inspired for your next bathroom remodel.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/04/Stacked%20Stone%20Bathroom%20Feature%20Wall%20with%20Freestanding%20Tub.jpeg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22One%20of%20a%20Kind%20Stone%20Bathroom%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22A%20super%20unique%20stone%20bathroom%20featuring%20a%20floor%20to%20ceiling%20stacked%20stone%20feature%20wall%20and%20a%20freestanding%20one%20piece%20natural%20stone%20tub.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Installing Stone Veneer in Cold Weather</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stone-veneer-cold-weather/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing Stone Veneer in Cold Weather" /><published>2018-09-24T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Installing-Stone-Veneer-in-Cold-Weather</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stone-veneer-cold-weather/">&lt;p&gt;As summer gives way to Fall and then Winter, one of the things we work with a lot of our clients on is understanding how stone veneer can be installed in cold weather climates.  For the sake of defining what cold weather is, we’ll peg it as the ambient temperate of the installation being below 40 degrees Fahrenheit.  Let’s dig into this topic and learn more about why it’s important to know about the cold weather installation procedures and what your options are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/26/Stacked Stone Veneer Cold Weather Install in the Fall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Installed on Columns in a Lake House in Wisconsin in the Fall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand more about why stone can’t be set below 40 degrees Fahrenheit you actually need to understand the properties of the mortar or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;thin set that’s being used to install the stone veneer&lt;/a&gt;, not the stone itself.  The mortar is critically important because of the water content – which in an average / room temperature installation allows the setting material to cure along a prescribed time line, slowly drying out while allowing the other natural and chemical agents to fully cure and create a very strong bond with the stone.  A cold weather installation, particularly one where the temperature can drop below 40 degrees Fahrenheit at any point, night or day, during a 7 day window after installation, risks freezing the moisture content in the setting material and stalling / stopping the curing process, resulting in a bond strength between stone and wall that might not be sufficient to hold the stone over the long run of an average installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, and maybe even the reason why you’re reading this article, construction time lines don’t always work out the way they were originally planned.  Sometimes you might find yourself staring down the barrel of a project that needs to be completed, but has complicating factors like an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;outdoor installation of stone veneer&lt;/a&gt; in the Fall or Winter.  As is the case with many things in life, prevention is the best solution in this situation.  Often times a project manager can get creative and have weather sensitive materials installed out of the traditional sequence, but before the cold weather sets in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/26/Stone Veneer Installed in Cold Weather Climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Installed in a cold weather climate with snow on the ground&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a creative solution to get the stone veneer installed before the cold weather hits isn’t in the cards, the two main options we advise our clients on is first to see if there’s any possibility they can find a 7 day period to get this material installed and cured without dipping below that 40 degree mark.  While this requires a little more flexibility, this is an effective technique which ends up requiring a lot less work than other alternatives, and can be good for areas that only on occasion get cold weather, or in the early or late parts of the cold weather season where they might be able to find a good 7 day window to work in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the project is in an area, or a time of year, where the 40 degree mark is going to be consistently broken, then tenting the installation and using an artificial heat source to maintain temperature is the option of choice.  The main thing to be aware and mindful of with a tented installation is the safe and continuous operation of the heat source.  Safety should always be the highest priority on any job site, so the proper precautions should definitely be taken to ensure the heat source creates no other problems on the job site including ventilation.  And seeing as though the heat source will most often need run at night, when the temperate is the lowest and coincidentally when nobody is there, it also makes sense to have the proper monitoring system in place to ensure the heat source is working.  A wifi enabled thermometer that can be checked remotely or send out alerts if the temperature falls below a certain point is a good investment for a stone veneer installation that needs tented because of cold weather.  When interviewing or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/hiring-a-contractor-for-your-next-stone-project/&quot;&gt;hiring a contractor to install stone veneer&lt;/a&gt;, be sure to ask them for a detailed cold weather plan if it’s that time of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/26/Stacked Stone Installation Tented for Cold Weather.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Installation that has been tented using scaffolding and a heat source to allow for a cold weather installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking to yourself that having to tent a stone veneer installation to install in weather under 40 degrees sounds like a pain in the but – you’re absolutely right, it is!  But rest assured that it is important – several years ago we worked with a contractor that installed our stone veneer panels on the exterior of a home in Northern New Jersey in January, literally while there was still snow on the ground!  Fast forward to the end of the next summer, the stone literally started to fall off the wall and ended up getting torn down and replaced.  So while it might not be fun, tenting and maintaining temperatures above 40 degrees is important for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;successful stone veneer installation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any technical questions, whether its about installing stone veneer in cold weather, or anything else, please give us a call or email us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sales@norstoneusa.com&quot;&gt;sales@norstoneusa.com&lt;/a&gt; and we’d be happy to share our extensive knowledge of stone veneer installation with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This past weekend it officially became Fall, and with the change in seasons one of the things we start to hear more about is cold weather installations of stone veneer. So let's dive into that topic in this week's blog and learn the do's and don't s of installing stone veneer in cold weather.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/09/26/Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20Cold%20Weather%20Install%20in%20the%20Fall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Veneer%20Installation%20in%20Cold%20Weather%20Climates%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Installation%20Techniques%20for%20stone%20veneer%20in%20cold%20weather%20climates%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ochre Rock Panels for a Rustic Kitchen Backsplash</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/rock-panels-rustic-kitchen-backsplash/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ochre Rock Panels for a Rustic Kitchen Backsplash" /><published>2018-09-17T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-17T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Ochre-Rock-Panels-for-a-Rustic-Kitchen-Backsplash</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/rock-panels-rustic-kitchen-backsplash/">&lt;p&gt;Rustic is probably one of the most confusing words in design terminology.  To the uninitiated, rustic brings up the idea that something is old and worn down, still functional, but clearly lacking that brand new feeling.  Most designers these days are throwing the term “rustic” around these days to describe a space that mainly chooses finishes and materials that are representative of finishes and materials of yesteryear, but in reality are all brand new, high quality stuff that’s just designed to capture the plain and sometimes partially unfinished feel of something “rustic”.  Some designers have even gone so far to start calling it “modern rustic”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This beautiful project in the woods of Wisconsin, not too far from Milwaukee, is a great example of the “modern rustic” look.  This is a new build that has been meticulously designed and curated with materials and finishes that evoke the true look and sense of a old cabin, including our personal favorite, a knockout &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;stacked stone backsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/19/Norstone Ochre Rock Panels on Rustic Kitchen Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Rock Panels on a Rustic Kitchen Backsplash with a large butcher block island and a ceiling with exposed natural log beams&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;stacked stone rock panels in the Ochre Blend color&lt;/a&gt; have been installed on the backsplash of this rustic kitchen and do an amazing job of complementing the design scheme of the space.  The color palette, and how well the Ochre color fits in with the rest of the materials,  is one of the first things that sticks out the most to me on this project.  The space is dominated by the medium brown tones of the cabinetry and the exposed natural log beams on the ceiling.  The dark stone counter top and the drop dead gorgeous dark brown butcher block island give some dimension to the brown tones as well.  The Ochre Blend color, which is generally made up of about 40% brown tones, 40% charcoal or gray tones, and about 20% accent colors, including the oranges, blues, greens, pinks,etc does a great job of fitting within the palette while still creating some noticeable contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/19/Norstone Ochre Rock Panels on Rustic Kitchen Backsplash With Exposed Natural Log Beam Ceiling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Rock Panels on a Rustic Kitchen Backsplash featuring prominent exposed natural log beams on the ceiling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/backsplash-tile-designs-norstone-industy-series/&quot;&gt;trend of using a stacked stone backsplash&lt;/a&gt; on this rustic inspired kitchen is really cool, there’s no doubt in our minds that most people when entering this space for the first time are going to have their eyes immediately drawn upward by the amazing ceiling.  The base ceiling is beautiful tongue and groove pine slats that form a nice backdrop for the real stars of the space, which are the exposed natural log beams.  The natural log beams and the stacked stone on the backsplash form a unique texture bridge, being really the only finishes in the space which show the natural texture of the products they are made from – whether that’s the natural split face of the stone, or the knot holes, branch nodes, or any other imperfections shown in the beams.  In the whole “rustic” design theme, this is incredibly important because it gives the space credibility and an inherent “naturalness” that’s a key component of the desired look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/19/Norstone Ochre Rock Panels on Rustic Kitchen Backsplash with Island.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Rock Panels on a Rustic Kitchen Backsplash with a large butcher block island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, kitchen islands are a dime a dozen, so it’s not too often that one stands out like this one.  In the above photo, our eyes are immediately drawn to the thickness of the butcher block style counter top, giving the space a very bold, and you guessed it, rustic look.  Everything else in this space, whether it’s the ceiling, the cabinetry, or the rustic stacked stone backsplash gets put up against this island and helps complete the design theme.  Specifically as it relates to the rustic backsplash, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/large-format-tile-small-kitchen-backsplash/&quot;&gt;the larger format of the stacked stone panel on the backsplash&lt;/a&gt;, especially as compared to more standard backsplash tiles like sheet mosaics, proves to be a good choice for a kitchen design where the clients haven’t backed down anywhere from going full scale, whether that’s with the exposed natural log beams or the thick butcher block island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a tour of this awesome cabin with us and learning a little more about rustic and modern rustic design.  Our stacked stone panels offer a rustic look with their split face or naturally cleft finish with a modern twist created by the geometry of the panel system.  If a rustic kitchen backsplash or any rustic designed theme project is in your future and stacked stone might be a finish option worth considering, contact us today to learn more about our products, get a sample, and get your questions answered.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This cabin in the woods of Wisconsin really delivers on the rustic look with some fantastic material selections, including our Ochre Stacked Stone Rock Panel on the backsplash. Let's take a look at this project and how the Ochre product fit right in with the rustic design theme.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/09/19/Norstone%20Ochre%20Rock%20Panels%20on%20Rustic%20Kitchen%20Backsplash.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ochre%20Rock%20Panels%20on%20a%20Rustic%20Kitchen%20Backsplash%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ochre%20Blend%20Rock%20Panels%20used%20on%20a%20modern%20rustic%20kitchen%20backsplash%20with%20a%20large%20island%20and%20exposed%20natural%20log%20ceiling%20beams%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Basalt or Lava Stone – What’s the difference?</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-difference-between-basalt-and-lavastone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basalt or Lava Stone – What's the difference?" /><published>2018-09-11T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-11T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-or-lava-stone-what-s-the-difference</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-difference-between-basalt-and-lavastone/">&lt;p&gt;The natural stone world is full of words that are different, but describe the same thing.  You might call a product field stone in Tennessee and flag stone in California, or stacked stone in Florida and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/split-face-stone-norstone-industry-series/&quot;&gt;split face&lt;/a&gt; in New York.  One such grouping of terms that is generally misunderstood is Basalt and Lava Stone, when used to refer to the same stone.  Here at Norstone we’ve been working with Basalt for about 10 years, and even with all that knowledge, we’ll readily admit that we didn’t really know what the difference was until about 18 months ago when we first started prototyping new products made from what our quarry was calling &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/&quot;&gt;Lava Stone&lt;/a&gt;.  The old saying that you learn something new every day rang true for us that day when we learned what the difference is between Basalt and Lava Stone.  Let’s take a deep dive into these two stones and learn how they are both similar and different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/12/Basalt Interlocking Tile on a Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of Norstone Grey Basalt Interlocking Tile used on an outdoor wall with an outside corner and a stainless steel light fixture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll go ahead and start with Basalt, since this is a stone that we’ve worked with for many years, and define it, at a very high level, as an igneous rock that is formed from the rapid cooling of lava at or very near the surface.  One of the key things to know about basalt is that it has a fine grained mineral texture which is formed because the molten lava is cooling so quickly that it doesn’t have time to form for large mineral crystals to grow.  Basalt is generally going to be in the grey to dark grey to black color range since its formed from molten lava.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/12/Norstone Aksent 3D Stone Panel Made from Basalt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Field Unit of Norstone Aksent Series 3D Panel shown in Ebony Basalt color&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basalt is a very workable stone that can be cut thin, has suitable hardness and durability for a variety of commercial applications, and can be honed, polished, or finished in a variety of other ways to create interesting products.  Norstone makes a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;medium format interlocking wall tile&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;3D smooth faced stone panel&lt;/a&gt;, and our large format loose veneer Planc product with basalt in two different colors, Grey and Ebony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/12/Lavastone Large Format Tile on Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large format tiles of Lava Stone used for a kitchen backsplash with modern white cabinets and a marble countertop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lava Stone is a more generic term than Basalt from a geological standpoint.  Most of the time it’s used in the stone industry to describe any stone that is a volcanic rock, which in reality can vary widely based on the mineral content of the volcanic rock itself.  The Lava Stone that we are using in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;wall veneer products&lt;/a&gt; has a very similar make up to basalt from a mineral composition standpoint, the main difference is that the Lava Stone has varying degrees of vesicles, or what we simply refer to as “holes”.  These vesicles form when gases that were dissolved in the molten magma come out of the solution during eruption, creating bubbles in the molten rock, some of which get frozen in place as the rock cools and becomes solid, creating the unique veining and natural stone “marking” that we see in our lava stone products.  This stone generally cools less rapidly than basalt, making the grain not quite as fine and not as dense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/12/Norstone Planc Large Format Tile Made From Lavastone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full set of Norstone Planc Series Large Format Loose Veneer Tile shown in Platinum Lava Stone color&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lava Stone is also a great product for commercial applications and has a distinct advantage of being more cost effective than basalt since it is more prevalent and the natural features, such as heavy vesicle patterns or veining, are considered part of the natural beauty of the stone and not an imperfection as it would be for basalt.  Norstone currently only makes two products with Lava Stone, our Platinum and Graphite colors of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;large format loose veneer Planc tile&lt;/a&gt;.  Platinum has a basic saw cut finish while Graphite has a light honing to create a smoother texture and slightly darker color.  We see a lot of possibility with Lava Stone and are testing it for other products including our Lynia Interlocking Tiles and Aksent 3D Stone Panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to natural stone, it’s super important to know what kind of stone you are working with, as it can impact where it can be used (interior / exterior / water applications, etc), and how the product should be maintained.  If the manufacturer of a stone product can be specific with the details of a stone being used it’s a red flag that they don’t really know what they’re working with and that might mean potential pit falls for you down the road if the information they provide turns out to be incompatible with the actual stone being used.  Contact any of our natural stone experts today to learn more about not just basalt and lava stone, but any of our natural stone products and how they might be a good fit for your next wall cladding project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">In the natural stone world, the terms basalt and lava stone are sometimes used interchangeably. There's no doubt these two stones are similar, but let's learn more about each one to really understand the difference between the two and what makes both basalt and lava stone unique.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/09/12/Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20on%20a%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Lava%20Stone%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20on%20a%20feature%20wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Lava%20Stone%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20medium%20format%20tile%20used%20on%20a%20wall%20showing%20an%20outside%20corner%20and%20a%20stainless%20steel%20light%20fixture%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One Last Peek at Summertime with this Awesome Ivory Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen and Pool</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Ivory-stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen-pool/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Last Peek at Summertime with this Awesome Ivory Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen and Pool" /><published>2018-09-04T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-04T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/test-blogone-last-peek-at-summertime-with-this-awesome-ivory-stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen-and-pool</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Ivory-stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen-pool/">&lt;p&gt;Labor day is one of our favorite holidays because it’s always enjoyable to have a day off work, but it also falls in a really great time of the year.  In most places the weather is still perfect for spending time outdoors and really enjoying it since the days start to get shorter quickly and depending on where you live, the tell tale signs of Fall show up before you know it.  For many of us, the backyard &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/pools/&quot;&gt;pool&lt;/a&gt; is top choice for a relaxing Labor Day weekend, so in this week’s project profile we’re taking a look at a really cool installation a customer of ours did a few years ago in Southern California where the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; was used prominently on a number of features on the pool, spa, and outdoor kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/05/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Stacked Stone Raised Beam Pool Feature.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Veneer used on a raised beam feature in a modern styled pool&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first up close photo taken from one side of the pool and looking out towards the mountain view of this hillside home shows the Ivory Rock Panel used as stone cladding on a raised beam water feature on two sides of the pool.  Raised beams are incredibly popular in current pool design as they allow you to incorporate a wider variety of products into the installation, such as the stacked stone we see here, can be used to create privacy, and also are perfect for housing water falls and scuppers, as well as providing a place to position fire bowls and other exciting pool features.  One of the cool things about our Ivory Rock Panel is that since its made from hard &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/quartz-ledgestone-vs-countertop/&quot;&gt;natural quartz stone&lt;/a&gt;, it can not only be used in and around water, but it can even be used as a waterline tile and be submerged, as its shown here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/05/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Stacked Stone Outside Corner Unit.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Finger Joint Corner Units shown in Ivory covering two outside corners on an exterior landscape wall with Travertine Cap&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what type of outside corner you have, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;Norstone Interlocking Finger Joint Corner&lt;/a&gt; is going to deliver a fantastic looking corner that’s super easy to install.  This particular area shows two outside corners and how two separate corner units can be used relatively close together and still produce a wonderful looking corner situation without noticeable seams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that catches our eye on this last photo is the travertine cap used on the raised beam of the pool.  Travertine is a very versatile product and, as you can see here, blends remarkably well with the light cream, yellow and gold tones of the Ivory Rock Panel, making travertine a great product to complement the stone with in all sorts of applications including hearths, sills, treads, and caps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/05/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Stacked Stone Curved Spa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Veneer panels used on the curved walls of a raised spa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the common misconceptions about stone veneer panel systems is that they can’t be used on curved walls.  The truth is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/&quot;&gt;stone panel systems can be used on curved walls&lt;/a&gt;, you just have to work within certain limitations on the radius, or “curve” of the wall, or you might need to alter the panel itself to make it more adaptable to a tighter radius application.  This beautiful installation on both the convex and concave sides of a spa is so well done it’s even hard for our team to pick out the panel seams in this photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/05/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Veneer used on an outdoor kitchen with pizza kitchen and low profile stone backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This beautiful outdoor kitchen is the crowning achievement of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-for-outdoor-living/&quot;&gt;stacked stone backyard oasis&lt;/a&gt;, complete with a stacked stone pizza oven and low profile stacked stone backsplash.  Upping the “livability” of this outdoor space to include a small refrigerator, prep sink, and multiple cooking apparatuses, this space offers everything you need in an outdoor kitchen and is done in a very stylish way that creates continuity through the stacked stone and other materials used throughout the pool and backyard areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this really cool project with us today – hopefully it brings back great memories of a summer spent with family and friends enjoying each others company in welcoming and inspiring spaces.  If you have a pool or outdoor kitchen project and are interested in learning more about the different ways stacked stone can be incorporated in the design call us to learn more about our wide range of natural stone wall veneer products.  Until then, say a quick good bye to summer – we’ll be ready for it again next year!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Fresh off a relaxing Labor Day weekend, we wanted to share one last summertime project with everyone to celebrate a great summer. This stacked stone outdoor kitchen and pool project is just the place we'd want to spend the last bit of summer!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/09/05/Norstone%20Ivory%20Rock%20Panels%20Stacked%20Stone%20Outdoor%20Kitchen-1.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20Stone%20Outdoor%20Kitchen%20with%20Pizza%20Oven%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20Stone%20Outdoor%20Kitchen%20with%20Pizza%20Oven%20in%20Southern%20California%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Save Money Installing Stacked Stone with Thin Stone Veneer Panel Systems</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/save-money-with-thin-stone-veneer-panels/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Save Money Installing Stacked Stone with Thin Stone Veneer Panel Systems" /><published>2018-08-27T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-save-money-installing-stacked-stone-with-thin-stone-veneer-panel-systems</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/save-money-with-thin-stone-veneer-panels/">&lt;p&gt;Stacked stone is a timeless look that bridges from ancient to modern times and everything in between.  From the original stone walls that were made out of stones collected from clearing fields for farming to modern applications where we see stacked stone used to enhance the design of commercial and residential spaces alike, stacked stone is both practical and beautiful.  Installing this look has been the trade of stone masons across the world for centuries until recently when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;thin stone veneer panel systems&lt;/a&gt; came onto the scene as an alternative that offered a simpler installation.  These thin stone veneer panel systems can be installed more cost effectively for a variety of reasons making the look of stacked stone available to a much wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/29/Hand Stacked Loose Stone Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loose stone hand stacked in a traditional technique to create a stone property dividing wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental difference between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;traditional hand stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; and a panel system comes down to one key difference – how each product is installed.  Hand stacked stone is generally thicker and comes as loose material, requiring the skill of a stone mason to select, hand fit, and then set each individual stone in place.  This process is time consuming and takes a specialized skill, which ultimately means hand stacking loose stone is an expensive endeavor.  Panel systems came onto the scene approximately 10-15 years ago offering a product where the stones were cut thin  and then adhered together into a uniform “tile-like” shape.  These products could be installed at high rates of speed, more similar to tile than stone, and give the wall a unique modern looking stacked stone look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/29/Thin Stone Veneer Panel System Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Thin stone veneer panel system units being installed on a wall using thinset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of saving money by using thin stone veneer panel systems vs traditional hand stacked stone, the biggest area of savings is in the installation.  In all likelihood, the cost of a stone panel system is going to be significantly more than the cost of loose stone – after all the stone in a panel system has been cut thin, glued and assembled into panels, and then packaged.  However, the ability to use a lower cost tile setter for the installation vs a skilled stone mason should result in a much lower installed cost per sq ft.  In fact, many homeowners have even taken on installing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;thin stone veneer panel systems as a DIY project&lt;/a&gt; and had great success doing it, dramatically decreasing the cost of a project and making this look possible for all levels of material budgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/29/Thin Stone Veneer Panel System Unit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Detail photo of Norstone's White Rock Panel Field Unit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thin stone veneer panel systems also affords the consumer a variety of options that simply aren’t available with traditional hand stacked stone.  Because the panel systems are made from stone that has been split or cut at a very thin dimension, nearly any natural stone can be used so long as it can be cut down to size.  Traditional hand stacked stone generally relies on stone that comes direct from quarries in certain sizes and with certain dimensions, reducing the overall variety, including color selection, of stone available.  Thin stone veneer panel systems can even introduce completely different product types to the mix, such as faux stone made from a variety of materials, or natural stone that is finished in other ways besides the traditional split face look.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Norstone’s Aksent Series Smooth Stone Veneer Panels&lt;/a&gt; are a great example of a panel system product that uses stone with a honed finish to create a tight, dry stack look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/29/Thin Stone Veneer Panel System Exterior Feature Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panel thin stone veneer system used on a two story exterior feature wall in Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One word of caution on thin stone veneer panel systems is that not all of them are created equal.  Not only should the raw stone be evaluated, but the manufacturing of the panel also plays a big role in the overall performance of the product.  The two biggest factors in manufacturing are calibration, which ensures that the panels can be dry stacked and fit together tightly.  The tighter the panels fit without gapping, the more realistic the panel system looks.  Component parts of the panel system such as the glue or epoxy that is used to keep the individual stones together is also important as it helps stabilize and keep the panel intact during transit, cutting, and installation.  The old adage of getting what you pay for is certainly true when dealing with any sort of tile or stone product – look for higher quality products that are calibrated and manufactured well that will be easier to install and look better on your project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for learning more about thin stone veneer panel systems with us today.  Norstone has been making these products for close to 15 years globally and has been selling them to the US market for close to 13 years.  If you are considering stacked stone for your next project, contact any of our team members to learn more about how thin stone veneer panel systems can help save you money, time, and get a great looking wall of stone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Almost every new construction or remodel project I've been a part of, at a certain point, comes down to budget. If a stacked stone look is something you are considering for your next project, here are some great ways you can get the look, but save a bunch of money by using easy to install thin stone veneer panel system instead of traditional hand stacked stone.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/08/29/Thin%20Stone%20Veneer%20Panel%20System%20Exterior%20Feature%20Wall.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Thin%20Stone%20Veneer%20Panel%20System%20on%20Exterior%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Standard%20thine%20stone%20veneer%20panels%20on%20an%20exterior%20feature%20wall%20project%20in%20Florida%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone XL Large Stone Veneer at the Mall of America</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/large-stone-veneer-mall-of-america/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone XL Large Stone Veneer at the Mall of America" /><published>2018-08-20T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/xl-larage-stone-veneer-at-the-mall-of-america</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/large-stone-veneer-mall-of-america/">&lt;p&gt;Our natural stone products have always been a favorite of architects and designers working on commercial retail  and hospitality spaces since they are so durable and require little upkeep.  A couple years ago we were excited to hear about a project in Minnesota at the iconic Mall of America that was planning on on using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;.  Working through our long time partner and distributor in the Midwest, we supplied this project with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/xlx-rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal XL color&lt;/a&gt;.  Recently, a few members of our team got a chance to see the finished project in person which we’d like to share with our readers today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/21/Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer Mall of America JW Marriott.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer used on Ground Floor of JW Marriott at Mall of America in Minnesota&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mall of America is obviously pretty massive, but our stone is easy to find as it was part of the recent expansion which included the construction of a new J.W. Marriott luxury hotel.  All of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal XL Stone Panels&lt;/a&gt; are used on the exterior of the building and the bulk of the stone is used on the ground level exterior around the hotel and a connected parking garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/21/Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer Mall of America Parking Garage-1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer used at Parking Garage entrance at Mall of America in Minnesota&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing we love about this project the most is that it’s a great fit for the XL Series Panel.  In fact, this is exactly the kind of project we had in mind when designing the XL Series – a project where the scale is so large that our Standard Series Rock Panels would create a very “busy” stone look.  The super-sized nature of the individual stones in the XL Series work well to create a clean, modern look that’s not overly complicated.  Malls in general are over-sized, but especially the Mall of America, which at one time was the largest mall in the country.  The attached photo shows some of that scale on a wall bordering the entrance / exit to the parking garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/21/Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer Mall of America Outside Corner.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer with interlocking finger joint outside corners used at Mall of America in Minnesota&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;interlocking finger jointed outside corner units&lt;/a&gt; are another reason that Architects and Designers love our products – it makes their jobs a lot easier!  The outside corner in this photo is the perfect example of what makes our corner units special, which come as a two piece set and interlock together to form a 90 degree outside corner.  The interlocking finger joint concept creates a relatively smooth transition from one side of the corner to the other and gives the corner a great finished look.  The Architect or Designer doesn’t have to worry about the quality of workmanship the on site contractor might deliver if they instead had chosen to specify a miter cut, and they don’t have to bring in a third party product, such as a metal tile edge or similar to finish off the corner.  Our line of accessories which includes the corners and our recently added natural end panels help solve problems for architects, designers, contractors, and homeowners that are designing, working with and installing our products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/08/21/Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer Drying.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal XL Large Stone Veneer used for a modern look at Mall of America in Minnesota&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also really liking the fact that the design team on this project opted to go with natural stone.  Even though its limited to the ground floor, the inherent beauty of a natural stone product goes a long way in establishing the brand identity of this luxury hotel.  The photo above offers a nice contrast showing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;luxurious finishes of glass, steel, and dark colored stone&lt;/a&gt; in the foreground compared to a dated building the background of beige toned brick and stucco.  The stone, shown here after some precipitation, really comes alive as it dries out going from almost black when fully wet to its native Charcoal color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this cool project with us today and learning more about how our natural stone products are a great fit for commercial retail and hospitality projects.  If you’re an Architect or Designer, or just playing one on your own home project, contact us today to learn more about using any of our natural stone veneer products on your project.  And if you’re ever at the Mall of America, tag us in a photo of the stone and we’ll send you an Amazon Gift Card – we’d love to see it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">How appropriate that our largest format stone veneer panel product is now being featured at the Mall of America in Minnesota, one of the largest malls in America. Let's take a look at how the Charcoal XL was used and why this is a great project for this product!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/08/21/Norstone%20Charcoal%20XL%20Large%20Stone%20Veneer%20Mall%20of%20America%20Parking%20Garage.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20XL%20Large%20Stone%20Veneer%20Mall%20of%20America%20Hotel%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20XL%20Large%20Stone%20Veneer%20used%20at%20Mall%20of%20America%20in%20Minnesota%22%7D" /></entry></feed>