<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-27T22:25:17-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Introducing Norstone Slim Line Rock Panel Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-slim-line-budget-stone-veneer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Norstone Slim Line Rock Panel Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/introducing-norstone-slim-line-rock-panel-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-slim-line-budget-stone-veneer/">&lt;p&gt;While Norstone has spent the past 15 years making &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer products &lt;/a&gt;of exceptional quality and durability for the high end of the market, we’ve always wanted to broaden that scope and deliver a price point stone veneer product that can make a run at competing with the veneer panels found at the big box home improvement stores and discount flooring centers.  Enter our new Slim Line Series, which is still packed with features, and every bit deserving of the Norstone name, but with a lower entry level price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Ochre Slim Line Outside Corner Low Cost Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Slim Line Outside Corner Unit shown on a column in the Ochre color&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difference between Slim Line Rock Panels and our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; is the thickness of each panel, with the Slim Line Panels checking in between 5/8” and 1 1/4” thick, compared with the Standard Series which ranges from 3/4” to 1 ¾”.  The panel sizes are the same, with each field unit clocking in at 6” tall x 24” wide and each corner unit consisting of a short side that is appx 8” long and a long side appx 16” long, that come together in an interlocking fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Slim Line Field Units Ochre Charcoal-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Slim Line Collage showing Ochre and Charcoal Field Units&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a practical standpoint, the thinner panels weigh less and can be packed 5 panels, or 5 square feet, per box .  This also means we can fit more square footage onto each crate we ship, allowing us to deliver more material for a lower cost to our customers.  From a visual standpoint, the smaller range of thicknesses creates a slightly less dimensional look on the wall as compared to our Standard and XL Panels, however Norstone Slim Line Panels still have more depth variation and thus create a more complex and visually interesting look on the wall and than the ultra cheap stone veneer panel products available at the big box home improvement centers and discount flooring centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Slim Line Charcoal Feature Wall Detail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Feature Wall of Norstone Slim Line Charcoal Color&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes Norstone Slim Line panels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;unique from other budget stone veneer panels&lt;/a&gt; is not just the Norstone name, but the areas of our production process that we refuse to cut in the name of creating a price point product.  Currently available in our ever popular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal&lt;/a&gt; colors, the stone we use for SlimLine is the exact same stone we use in our Standard and XL Panels.  We also use the same high grade two part epoxy to join the individual stones together in making the panels to ensure a much stronger bond as compared to poly based glues commonly seen on budget stone veneer panels.  Lastly, we have the best in house team of Norstone production managers, stone pickers, saw men, assemblers and packers that bring to the table a decade and half of knowledge making quality stone veneer products and bring that knowledge and expertise to the production line every day no matter what product is being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Ochre Slim Line Budget Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Residential project that used Norstone Slim Line in Ochre surrounding entryway&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim Line was originally developed for large commercial projects that demanded the merits of a natural stone product but had the financial constraints often associated with large projects.  Starting Spring 2018, Norstone USA will be stocking Slim Line in both Ochre and Charcoal Colors at both our East Coast and West Coast Distribution Centers and selling to all customers for jobs of all sizes.  With prices in the range of a 25% discount from our Standard Series Rock Panels, Slim Line might be a good fit for your next project, or speed up and make the project you’ve been thinking about doing a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;Contact the Norstone Team&lt;/a&gt; today to learn more about Slim Line, request samples, get a quote and see how this product might be a great fit for your project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">If you've always loved Norstone's Standard Series Rock Panels, but the price hasn't worked for your project, we're happy to introduce our new Slim Line Series Rock Panels, a thinner and lower cost product that we're debuting this Spring.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone%20Slim%20Line%20Field%20Units%20Ochre%20Charcoal.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Slim%20Line%20Rock%20Panel%20Series%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Slim%20Line%20Rock%20Panel%20Field%20Units%20in%20Ochre%20and%20Charcoal%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grey Lynia Tiles Make this Pool Cool!</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-lynia-tile-pool/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Lynia Tiles Make this Pool Cool!" /><published>2018-03-25T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-25T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-lynia-tiles-make-this-pool-cool</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-lynia-tile-pool/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we really like about our natural stone tile products is that you can use almost all of them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/pools/&quot;&gt;pool environments&lt;/a&gt;.  Pools are typically a really harsh environment for any type of material.  Having to deal with moisture, lots of sunlight, and chemicals really narrows down the type of materials you can use and especially so in the natural stone world.  A lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Norstone products are perfect for pools&lt;/a&gt; because we make them from quartz or quartz based stones, or in the case of this project, Basalt, which are much more durable stones than cheaper slates and sandstones which won’t stand up to the rigors of a pool environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really like the look of this pool project in Texas that one of our customers finished last year.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/basalt/&quot;&gt;Lynia IL Tile in Ash Grey&lt;/a&gt; was used as part of a raised beam feature flanking the entire back side of the pool.  There’s some great design hidden in plain sight with this project, so let’s take a closer look at what stands out to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/26/Grey Lynia Stone Tile in Pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tile Ash Grey Basalt color used in pool raised beam feature wall in Texas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things we notice about this pool is the modern angular layout.  While curves are still popular in pool design, clean line pools like this one are increasingly popular as well.  From a product pairing standpoint, the clean lined staggered format of the Lynia natural stone tiles is a complimentary to this design scheme and definitely adds to the modern vibe this pool exudes through the smooth finishes and sheer descent waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another really unique thing about the Lynia Interlocking is that it is relatively large for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-mesh-backed-tile/&quot;&gt;mesh mounted tile product&lt;/a&gt;.  Each strip in the Lynia Tiles is 12” long and is going to range between about 1” to 2.4” tall.  The medium format nature of this product is a nice compliment to the much smaller format of the square glass tile used on the waterline, spa spillover and large water feature.  If too small a tile was used in place of the Lynia, the overall look would start to get really busy, but as it stands the two prominent tile finishes of the pool work quite nicely with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/26/Grey Interlocking Natural Stone Tile in Pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Mesh Mounted Tile used in swimming pool raised beam feature wall in Texas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that grey is a currently a very popular color in the design world right now, and this pool and patio area is no exception.  The darker tones of the Ash Grey Lynia Tile used here match up nicely with the furniture and trim color of the patio, while also serving as a nice contrast against the lighter grey of the smooth faced stucco retention wall that is the primary backdrop of this backyard.  The movement of color within the Lynia tile, which is pronounced in these photos as they show some of the tile being wet and other parts being dry, is another nice contrast against the uniformity of the stucco wall behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have always been big fans of combining grey and blue tones in design, which has been done here with the stone tiles, the glass tile and the color of the pool surface itself.  Most grey tones have a lot of blue undertone, so when paired together the two colors tend to look great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With summer right around the corner we hope this article inspires some great design ideas for upcoming pool projects using natural stone.  Using the right types of natural stone tiles and veneers in the right applications is the key for a great pool project.  Call one of our knowledgeable design reps for a free consult on using Norstone Natural Stone Veneers and Tiles on your next pool project today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">It's hard not to like this pool that was completed last year which used our Lynia Interlocking Tiles in grey as part of an extensive raised beam feature. Let's take a look at what makes a product like the Lynia IL tiles a great fit for this type of project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/26/Grey%20Interlocking%20Natural%20Stone%20Tile%20in%20Pool.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Natural%20Stone%20Tile%20on%20Pool%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocling%20Natural%20Stone%20Tile%20in%20Ash%20Grey%20Basalt%20used%20on%20a%20pool%20raised%20beam%20feature%20wall%20in%20Texas%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mechanical Fastening vs Direct Adhesion for Stacked Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mechanical-fastening-stacked-stone-veneer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mechanical Fastening vs Direct Adhesion for Stacked Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-03-11T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mechanical-fastening-vs-direct-adhesion-for-stacked-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mechanical-fastening-stacked-stone-veneer/">&lt;p&gt;Most large format stone veneers, such as the granite and limestone slabs that you see on the facades of many commercial buildings, are installed using a clip system to mechanically fasten or anchor the stone to the substrate.  In the mid 2000s when Norstone was getting started bringing our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; to the US market, we were often asked if our panels needed to be installed with mechanical fasteners as well.  The quick answer to that question is no – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;thin stone veneer is made specifically to be installed like a tile using thinse&lt;/a&gt;t, directly adhered to the substrate, which is commonly referred to as direct adhesion.  Both mechanical fastening and direct adhesion can be used to install stacked stone, so let’s learn a little more about each method and what types of installations they are best suited for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mechanical fastening of stone facade work is mainly born out of necessity.  As architects and designers sought out larger format stone products to use, the building industry needed to find a way to safely secure these products to the outside of buildings.  Capable of weighing far in excess of 15 lbs a square foot, and often much heavier than that, a mechanical solution was needed.  The varieties and styles of stone clips and mechanical fasteners is far ranging, but they all work on the same basic concept that they get attached to the stone itself and then also are attached back to the substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/13/Mechanical Fastening of Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Format Limestone Veneer nstalled using stone clips&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pros and cons of mechanical fastening for stone veneer are pretty straightforward.  This installation method allows for larger format pieces to be used yet still installed safely and effectively.  The disadvantages are that the installation process itself can be time consuming and require a lot of precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct adhesion, which is how we recommend all of our Norstone Natural Stone Products be installed, has a few key components – the substrate, the setting material, and the stone.  The substrate is probably the most important as it needs to be made a of a material that can effectively bond with the setting material, and also represents the outer layer of the wall system which should be engineered to meet the weight requirements of the new material being adhered to the wall.  Setting materials should be selected based on the product being installed and the substrate being used.  In most cases, stacked stone veneer like our Rock Panels or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Stone Panels&lt;/a&gt; should be installed over a cementious substrate, like CMU, cement board, or a lathe + scratch coat using a polymer modified tile thinset designed to support the heavier weight load of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;large format tiles&lt;/a&gt; or stacked stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/13/Installed Stacked Stone using Direct Adhesion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Panels installed using tile thinset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages and disadvantages of direct adhesion for stacked stone veneer is that stone and tile is installed relatively easily in a thinset setting bed and doesn’t require the exacting precision needed for mechanical fastening.  The main disadvantage of direct adhesion is that the building industry sets maximum unit sizes, weight per sq ft limits, and height restrictions for directly adhered veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re asking yourself if mechanically fixed or directly adhesion is the best option for your project, the answer is almost always going to be direct adhesion is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;best installation practice for stacked stone veneer&lt;/a&gt;.  Provided the products are less than 36” in any one dimension, less than 15 lbs per sq ft, and not to be installed more than 15’ above the finished floor, direct adhesion will provide you with a faster and easier install.  If the specifics of your project exceed any of the limits notated above, work with the construction and engineering team on your project to determine what the best combination of installation techniques will be best for your project.  Most stacked stone panel products are made with these upper limits in mind and are therefore suitable to be installed using a direct adhesion method.  Traditional loose veneer, that a mason artfully stacks by hand on site can sometimes require mechanical fasteners depending on the relative thickness and weight of the stone being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/13/Large Format Stone Tile Installed Using Direct Adhesion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Format Lavastone Tiles installed using thinset in a direct adhesion method&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Norstone we enjoy the more technical aspects of our industry and design our products with them in mind, to create beautiful products while still maximize installation output.  Never hesitate to contact us about any of our products or to ask a question and learn more about their recommended installation techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">A lot of stone facades, particularly large format, are installed using a variety of clip systems for a mechanical bond with the substrates. If you've ever wondered if this type of mechanical fastening can be used for a stacked stone panel installation, this article is for you!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/13/Mechanical%20Fastening%20of%20Stone%20Veneer.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Mechanical%20Fastening%20of%20Stone%20Veneer%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Large%20limestone%20veneer%20slabs%20directly%20attached%20to%20a%20concrete%20substrate%20using%20mechanical%20fasteners%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Natural Stone Veneer at a New High End Assisted Living Facility</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-accent-walls-assisted-living/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Natural Stone Veneer at a New High End Assisted Living Facility" /><published>2018-03-04T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-veneer-at-a-new-high-end-assisted-living-facility</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-accent-walls-assisted-living/">&lt;p&gt;Assisted living facilities are one of the fastest growing industries in the country, and might likely see explosive growth over the next decade plus as the baby boom segment of the population becomes more and more likely to engage these services.  The health care segment has always embraced natural stone in their design, and we’ve had the opportunity to have our natural stone veneers placed on dozens of doctors offices, hospitals, and clinics throughout the country.  This particular project slipped under our radar until we saw pictures of the finished installations and wow, were we impressed when they came across our desk.  Let’s take a quick tour and see how our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; are a great addition to the space for the residents and caregivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Stacked Stone Veneer Floor to Ceiling Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Rock Panels used on a floor to ceiling fireplace with long linear gas fireplace insert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main community room is the breathing heart of a facility like this one, and the magnificent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-fireplaces-2017/&quot;&gt;floor to ceiling stone fireplace&lt;/a&gt; with its modern linear gas fireplace is the main attraction in this space.  The incredible durability of natural stone means this wall surface will be maintenance free for years to come, and the sensible brown / grey blend of the Ochre Rock Panels works great with the neutral pallete the design teams of these facilities must work between.  While the fireplace is slightly more form than function in terms of heat output, the visual it creates in the space is exceptional and again will be very easy for the staff to maintain without the hassle of a more cumbersome fuel source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Stacked Stone Feature Wall in Hair Salon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Natural Stacked Stone Panels used on the feature wall in a small hair salon with two chairs and two large mirrors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An onsite hair salon is a really unique feature of this facility that comes with an exceptional look.  The big feature wall of Ochre stone veneer adds a high end spa like feeling to the space and is infinitely nicer to look at while getting a trim or color than painted drywall.  The big floor mounted leaning mirrors, colorful chairs and minimalist design is plucked right from any high end big city hair salon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Commercial Buffet Station with Stone Veneer Backdrop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone panels used behind a commercial buffet station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next area the rock panel are featured on is as an accent wall over a serving station in the breakfast area.  This stone wall serves as almost a pseudo backsplash, offering up a much more durable wall covering option than painted drywall.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Sealing the stone for a backsplash&lt;/a&gt; application is a good idea as it will allow for any stains that find their way onto the face of the stone to be easily wiped off.  The neutral color pallet of the Ochre Blend stone works in nicely with the light colored wood cabinets and furniture of the space and the cream colored solid surface countertop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Ochre Blend Feature Wall in Treatment Room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Veneer Panels on a feature wall in a spa like treatment room at an assisted living facility&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the last areas the stone was used on is a series of treatment rooms where the residents can receive a variety of services, from massages to physical therapy / rehab, to hydrotherapy.  Just even having facilities like this in house is a major selling point for an assisted living facility, however this facility takes it to the next level with high end finishes.  The main wall is a beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt;floor to ceiling stacked stone feature wall&lt;/a&gt; of our rock panels in Ochre Blend, while other design features like vessel sinks, flat euro-styled cabinetry, and luxe bath towels make this space feel a lot more like a spa than your typical medical treatment room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With projects like this under our belt, we look forward to continue to provide the health care industry with new and exciting wall veneer options that serve the dual purpose of meeting the unique needs of the industry while still looking amazing.  Whether its health care, hospitality, retail, office, or high end residential, our team of design experts is here to help plan your next project – call us today to get started!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Assisted Living Facilities aren't in general one of our favorite places, but this one that just opened recently in New Jersey might help us change our mind. With many of the same amenities as a spa mixed with a country club, like a sweet stone veneer feature wall and fireplace that used our Ochre Rock Panels, getting old is starting to look more appealing!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/06/Ochre%20Blend%20Feature%20Wall%20in%20Treatment%20Room.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Accent%20Wall%20Assisted%20Living%20Facility%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Accent%20Wall%20in%20the%20treatment%20room%20of%20a%20new%20assisted%20living%20facility%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Install Stacked Stone in a Shower</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stacked-stone-shower/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install Stacked Stone in a Shower" /><published>2018-02-27T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-27T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-in-a-shower</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stacked-stone-shower/">&lt;p&gt;Open up any architectural or design magazine or tour a new construction model home and one of the trends you’ll notice is master bathrooms getting bigger and bigger.  With the middle to high end homebuyer seeking out both spacious tubs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/showers/&quot;&gt;showers fitted out with spa like finishes&lt;/a&gt;, the master bath, and in particular the shower stall, is an area we find our stacked stone veneer products showing up in more and more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Stone Veneer Accent Wall in Modern Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charcoal Rock Panels used on an accent wall in a large walk in doorless shower&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the early adopters of this trend, there were some fairly basic questions that needed answered about how stacked stone could be used in a shower.  After all, our stacked stone panels are created and installed on a dry stack concept, where the stone is neatly cut and but up against the surrounding stones, but in no way does that form a watertight seal to keep moisture out.  And since we’re working with natural stone to begin with, which tends to be very porous, the big question people had was how do we prevent water from getting behind the stone and into the wall cavity, possibly destabilizing the installation and causing moisture problems in surrounding rooms, and even creating health problems related to mold and mildew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution to the problem is a multi pronged approach starting with substrate preparation, using the right bedding and setting materials, and then simple ongoing maintenance steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real key to the moisture problem a stacked stone wall in a shower presents is using the correct substrate.  Cement board, or similar anti microbial tiling board designed for vertical tile installations is the perfect starting point to cover the framing.  The next, and possibly most important step in the entire installation is the application of a waterproofing membrane.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Waterproofing membranes are important for many tile installations&lt;/a&gt; and can be either sheet membranes or fluid applied membranes that roll on like thick paint.  This layer serves a vital step of ensuring that water that does pass through the stone does not get past the membrane and into the wall cavity where it can cause problems.  The membrane should overlap the shower pan to allow gravity to take its course and manage the flow of moisture away from the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Norstone Ochre Rock Panels in a Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone on a shower wall with a pebble floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stacked stone veneer should be applied to the prepared substrate using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;polymer modified thinset&lt;/a&gt;, and since moisture is a concern in shower installations, an anti-microbial thinset is recommended.  Anti-microbial thinsets are designed by setting material manufacturers to help prevent the growth of mold and mildew and as part of a whole installation system are effective at doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Charcoal Stone Veneer Walk In Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Walk In Shower with a Frameless Glass Enclosure and Stacked Stone used on the walls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the stacked stone is successfully installed, a quality &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;natural stone sealer &lt;/a&gt;should be applied to the wall prior to putting the shower to use.  One thing important to understand with sealers is that a sealer doesn’t form a waterproof layer or barrier of protection.  The main function of the sealer is to treat the stone and make it harder for any staining, or in the case of a shower, mold or mildew to form on the surface of the stone.  Natural stacked stone veneer should be periodically resealed according to the timeline provided by the seal manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final, and often overlooked ongoing maintenance tip for a stacked stone shower wall is to always run the exhaust vent in the bathroom during and after a shower.  The exhaust vent is an effective tool at evacuating the steamy/ moisture rich air created during a shower.  By removing this warm and moist air from the space you greatly inhibit mold and mildew growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Walk in Shower with Vertical Stacked Stone Accents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Shower with vertical stacked stone accent strips set in porcelain tile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stacked stone shower walls are a statement piece in any master bathroom, but one of the things we tell all of our clients that are considering this type of application is that they should understand that this is not a maintenance free installation.  From remembering to run the exhaust fan, to regular cleanings, to periodic re-sealings, the maintenance of a stacked stone shower wall isn’t terribly hard or time consuming, but definitely necessary to keep an installation looking great.  Thanks for taking the time to learn more about using stacked stone veneer in a shower application.  Contact any of our in house design experts to discuss how stacked stone, or any of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone wall tile products&lt;/a&gt; can be a good fit for you next shower project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">As the trend of turning master bathrooms into mini spa like retreats continues, we're seeing more and more customers thinking about using stacked stone products in their showers. So how does a product with loads of texture and small tinygaps between each stone work in a wet environment? Learn all about how to use stacked stone in a shower in this week's blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/01/Walk%20in%20Shower%20with%20Vertical%20Stacked%20Stone%20Accents.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Used%20in%20a%20Shower%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ochre%20Rock%20Panels%20used%20in%20a%20shower%20application%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stone to the Ceiling at Boston Airport Area Hotel</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/three-story-stacked-stone-feature-wall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stone to the Ceiling at Boston Airport Area Hotel" /><published>2018-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-to-the-ceiling-at-boston-airport-area-hotel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/three-story-stacked-stone-feature-wall/">&lt;p&gt;One of the really cool things about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;thin stone veneer like Norstone Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; is that they can be used in applications not traditionally associated with traditional stone masonry.  A great example is this amazing lobby feature wall completed several years ago at a Boston Airport area hotel.  Soaring the equivalent of about three traditional stories, or over 30 feet into the air, this is an amazing large scale installation of our White Rock Panel product.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/aztec-stone-veneer-hotel/&quot;&gt;Hotels often use stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; and other hard surfaces for their commercial durability, and while extra large in size, this project has a lot of great detail and thought put into the space by the design team which we’ll dive into in this week’s blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/White Quartz Stacked Stone Hotel Lobby Atrium Feature Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Three Story Hotel Lobby Atrium Stacked Stone Feature Wal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing catches everyone that looks at this wall is the sheer size of it.  It’s actually hard to do it justice with the camera angles that the space provides!  One of the best views in our opinion is this angle looking back towards the entrance and reception desk on the first floor and mezzanine level on the second.  As is common in hotels, the first couple “public” floors tend to have higher ceilings to accommodate scaled up lobbies, restaurants, and meeting spaces, so when you actually put a measurement on this wall, the stone is going just over 30 feet floor to ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the cool things about stacked stone veneer is that it’s lightweight and can therefore be installed using a direct bond thinset method instead of mechanical fastening which is more common with traditional full thickness stone masonry.  Norstone Standard Series Rock Panels weight about 12.5 lbs per sq ft, below the threshold of 15 lbs per sq ft allowing them to be installed using the direct bond thinset method, making an installation like this hotel lobby possible.  The engineering team did make sure the wall was designed and built to accommodate the extra weight load, but apart from that this product was installed just like a our Rock Panels would be installed on one of our client’s fireplaces, backsplashes, or feature walls – just super sized!  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Installing stacked stone is easy&lt;/a&gt; when you’ve got a great product to work with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/Stone Veneer Hotel Lobby Atrium Wall with Skylights.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Quartz on large feature wall in Boston area hotel with skylights&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural light makes almost any space better, and this one is no exception.  Significant glass along the back wall of this lobby atrium adds a lot of natural light, as does the unique domed glass ceiling right above the stone feature wall.  While the glass doesn’t extend across the entire ceiling of the atrium space it hits the mark as far as bringing in beautiful natural light and maintaining an open feeling in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/Art Installation over White Stacked Stone Veneer.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Art installed over white stacked stone in boston area hotel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art pieces located on each expanse of the stone feature wall are unique and grand enough in size to not get overpowered by the overall scale of the wall and atrium.  We really liked this four segmented modern piece.  The black color and curved lines contrast nicely against the white blank canvas of the stone and the linear geometry of the rock panel system.  The installer expertly used metal stand offs to position the pieces in front of the stone, which not only makes it possible to get the art pieces to be flat against the variable face of the stone, but also adds an extra little bit of dimensionality to the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/Lighting Fixture in White Stacked Stone Feature Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Large scale lighting fixtures installed on top of white stacked stone veneer panels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Light fixtures are an important accent to any stacked stone installation&lt;/a&gt;, and this one is no exception.  The scale of these fixtures, being almost 4 feet from tip to tip, and the brushed stainless finish which creates a great modern color scheme with the starkness of the White Rock Panels, makes them excellent choices for the space.  The installation team again has done an amazing job to get these fixtures sitting flat against the dimensional face of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While lobby atriums like this one will always pose design and material selection challenges due to the wall heights involved, so too will many of the “great rooms” of homes built in the last decade or so.  If you have a great room of your own at home with high ceilings and tall walls, stone veneer is a great product to consider since its classic in style and not the latest fad you’ll want to change out in two years, and lightweight enough to not warrant much, if any, structural work prior to installation.  We have a great team knowledgeable in the intricacies of installing stone veneer at height, so come to us with your questions and we’ll be happy to help.  And if you’re checking into a hotel in Boston anytime soon, be sure to look up and you might just have a view worth enjoying for a while!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">If you travel in and out of Boston a lot you might have seen this amazing lobby atrium wall featuring our White Quartz Rock Panels at one of the airport area hotels. This project was several years ago, but one we still go back to frequently to show customers how stacked stone veneer can be used in applications that go beyond normal ceiling height, which we'll explain in great detail in this week's blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/19/White%20Quartz%20Stacked%20Stone%20Hotel%20Lobby%20Atrium%20Feature%20Wall.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Three%20Story%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20White%20Rock%20Panels%20used%20on%20three%20story%20atrium%20lobby%20feature%20wall%20in%20Boston,%20MA%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Seal Stacked Stone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Seal Stacked Stone" /><published>2018-02-11T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-11T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Stacked stone is a one of the most durable building materials on the planet, but even with that accolade there are still a variety of reasons why &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;stacked stone should be sealed post installation&lt;/a&gt;.  This can range from the type of installation such as exterior vs interior or wet vs dry, what kind of stone it is, and sometimes sealing the stone can just be used to create a specific visual effect desired.  Most sealers for natural stone are penetrating, meaning they soak into the stone and don’t exist just topically, and form a protective barrier that helps prevent any build up on or deterioration of the stone face.  Let’s dive a little deeper into the reasons why to seal stacked stone and then learn how to apply the sealer as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Stacked Stone on a Pool Feature.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone that has been sealed used on a pool feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exterior installations and installations where the stone is going to be in or around water, such as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone pool wall&lt;/a&gt;, fountain, or other water feature, should all be sealed after installation.  The sealer forms a protective barrier against the elements, especially water, which have the potential to damage a stacked stone installation, especially over time and in areas subject to freeze – thaw cycling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Stacked Stone on a Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vertical Strips of stacked stone used in a large walk in shower that have been sealed with a natural stone sealer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also always a good idea to seal certain types of stone.  Some stone, like limestone and travertine is more porous and sealing it helps prevent staining.  Other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/slate-tile-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;types of stone including slate&lt;/a&gt; can be high in iron content so a good quality seal prevents rust spotting when exposed to moisture.  The manufacturer of the stone product, or the local outlet where the stone is purchased from should be able to tell you if a certain type of stone absolutely needs sealed, and in general there’s really no harm in sealing stone even if it’s not a required step in the installation process for your project.  For Norstone products, we recommend that all colors of our Standard Series and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; be sealed for exterior and water applications.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Norstone’s Lynia IL Tile&lt;/a&gt; and Aksent 3D Panels should be sealed in all applications, both interior and exterior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the protective value of a sealer, they can also be used to create certain visual effects desirable in many installations.  Good examples of this are color enhancing sealers which darken up natural stone and high gloss sealers which leave behind a semi reflective sheen on the stone surface.  Since these sealers are designed for a specific effect we always recommend making sure they are compatible with your stone and to test the sealer on a sample piece to see that it achieves the desired effect before committing it to an entire wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Sealed Stacked Stone Garden Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Curved Stacked Stone garden wall that has been sealed with an enhancing sealer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might expect, there are a lot of different natural stone sealer options to choose from.  Some of the key differences in sealers is if they are water based or oil based and if they are penetrating or topical.  Always check with the manufacturer of the stone product you are working with to determine what’s right for your stone.  For all Norstone products we recommend sealers that are water based and penetrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Sealed Interior Stacked Stone Water Feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interior stacked stone water feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the actual application of the natural stone sealer goes, the best and easiest way we’ve found to apply sealer is with a hand held pump sprayer.  This handy tool is readily available in the garden center of any home improvement store and most come with an adjustable tip to allow for a wider spray pattern to be used.  The key to applying sealer to stacked stone is to do multiple light coats versus fewer, heavier coats.  Allow the sealer time to soak into the stone before making another pass.  When you start to see the sealer sit on the surface of the stone and not soak in any more dab the excess sealer off with a cloth so it won’t dry and leave a haze.  Sealers will need to be re-applied every so often, based on the sealer manufacturer’s recommendation and in field testing of how strong the original seal is holding up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sealing is a relatively easy and inexpensive maintenance item that will protect and enhance the investment you’ve made in a stacked stone wall.  Here at Norstone we’re happy to share our expertise and answer technical questions about sealing and stacked stone in general, so contact us today and thanks for learning all about sealing stacked veneer with us today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Sealing stacked stone is an important finishing step for many projects, especially exterior installations, or where the stone is in or around water. Let's take a look at how and why stacked stone should be sealed in this week's blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/12/Stacked%20Stone%20on%20a%20Pool%20Feature.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20that%20should%20be%20sealed%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22A%20pool%20feature%20wall%20of%20stacked%20stone%20that%20should%20be%20sealed%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Aksent 3D Panels Commercial Storefront Project</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-3d-panels-commercial-storefront/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Aksent 3D Panels Commercial Storefront Project" /><published>2018-02-05T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-05T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-aksent-3d-panels-commercial-storefront-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-3d-panels-commercial-storefront/">&lt;p&gt;Commercial storefronts are all about durability while still meeting the style and design demands of the developer and tenants.  Norstone has been fortunate enough to work with many higher end developers on commercial build outs where a natural stone veneer or facade was required as a way to distinguish a particular development compared to lower cost exterior veneers such as stucco, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/real-stone-vs-faux-norstone-industry-series/&quot;&gt;faux stone&lt;/a&gt;, and split face block.  The storefront featured in this week’s project profile is no exception featuring both our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/ebony/&quot;&gt;Ebony Aksent 3D Panel&lt;/a&gt; set among a modern designed facade of steel paneling and glass.  Let’s take a closer look at the Ebony Aksent 3D Panels and see what makes them so special on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/07/Ebony Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Commercial Facade Under Construction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Commercial Entryway under construction where Norstone Ebony Aksent 3D Panels and Ochre XL Series Rock Panels were used&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that really catches our eye with the Ebony Aksent 3D stone veneer panels on this project is the height that they were installed.  Flanking two sets of doors on both sides, the stone veneer goes from finished floor height all the way to above the facade of building, where the vertical features connect with a horizontal bridge section.  At easily 20 feet in the air, the thin veneer format of the Aksent 3D Panels allows for the product to be set using an adhesive method in lieu of mechanical fastening (in accordance with the building codes of most areas).  Weighing in at around 8.5 lbs per foot, this stone veneer easily is below the 15 lb per square foot requirement where mechanical fastening becomes the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/07/Ebony Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Commercial Facade-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smooth stone veneer used on commercial entryway feature with prominent outside corners&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that we really liked about this project was the use of our finger jointed outside corner units for the Aksent 3D series.  We take a lot of pride in making what we feel like is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;most realistic and best looking outside corner unit&lt;/a&gt; in the stone veneer industry and projects like this, which features prominent outside corners the entire length up the wall is a great example of how great a stone veneer panel system corner can look like.  Just like the corner units in our Standard Series and XL Series Rock Panels, every piece of the corner unit that faces outward is finished the same as the face of the panel, which for the Aksent 3D panels is a smooth honed surface.  If you ever want to know how good of a stone veneer product you’re looking at, always look for a corner and see if some of the outward facing edges aren’t finished, or  if a more basic dovetail style interlocking pattern is used and you’ll understand more about why we’re so proud of the corner unit we created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/07/Norstone 3D Aksent and Standard Rock Panels on Commercial Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smooth and naturally textured stone veneer used as part of a modern inspired commercial facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing that stands out to us about this project is cool color combinations used on the facade.  The Ebony Aksent 3D product is stylistically geared towards a more modern look and as such, works really well with the commercial black framed windows and doors as well as the brushed steel facade panels.  The Ebony color, which is a handful of shades darker than the more popular Ash Grey color in the Aksent 3D panel line, is a better pick for this project as it is very close in color to the window frames and has great contrast against the steel facade.  The great geometric shape and texture the Aksent 3D Panels create also works nicely with the clean lines and architectural accents on the facade as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we know for sure is that our natural stone veneer products will stand the test of time, even in the harsh realities of a commercial setting like this one, which make them an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;ideal choice for commercial developers and residential designers and homeowners alike looking for stylish modern products&lt;/a&gt; that are easy to install and maintain.  Call and speak with one of our in house design experts or drop us a line via email and let us show you how a cool product like Ebony Aksent 3D panels can be a great fit for your next modern stone veneer project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Even though this project is still under construction, we liked how our Ebony Aksent stone veneer panels were looking so much we wanted to share some photos we snapped during a recent site visit. Enjoy!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/07/Ebony%20Aksent%203D%20Stone%20Veneer%20Commercial%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Commercial%20Storefront%20with%20Ebony%20Aksent%203D%20Stone%20Panels%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Aksent%20Stone%20Panels%20surrounding%20large%20glass%20and%20metal%20entryway%20of%20a%20commercial%20shopping%20center%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Cut Stacked Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-cut-stacked-stone-veneer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Cut Stacked Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-01-28T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-cut-stacked-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-cut-stacked-stone-veneer/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Installing stacked stone veneer&lt;/a&gt; is a challenging, but achievable project for most DIY’ers.  One of the first questions we get when talking with potential customers is “How do I cut it?”.  Stone is a new building product for most people, unlike more traditional mediums like wood, metal, concrete, and tile, so bridging that gap with easy to understand knowledge is something we know our customers appreciate.  The short answer is that stacked stone veneer panels are best cut using a combination of two tools – a wet saw designed to cut tile and stone, and a angle grinder for more precision and unique cuts.  Let’s take a look at each of these tools and some things a first time &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;stone veneer DIY installer&lt;/a&gt; will want to know about each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Tile Wet Saw with a continuous rim diamond blade is going to be your primary cutting tool for a stack stone veneer panel installation.  A wet saw works on the concept of water being applied to the blade and to the tile or stone to provide lubrication as the blade cuts through.  The water is typically recycled through a close loop system which allows for it to drain off the tile and into a reservoir where a small pump is located which cycles it back up to blade.  One of the most important things to remember when working with a wet saw is to constantly be refreshing the water, especially when cutting stone since the heavy sediment the saw creates when cutting the stone will start to diminish the water’s ability to lubricate the saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/29/Wet Saw Cutting Stacked Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tile Wet Saw being used to cut a stacked stone veneer panel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A continuous rim diamond blade sounds fancy, but its actually a fairly prevalent type of blade available at most hardware stores and certainly any tile and stone shop.  Diamonds are one of the hardest naturally occurring materials on earth and are exceptionally good with cutting through tile and stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tile wet saw will typically either have a stationary blade and a movable tray where the stacked stone veneer can be placed and then pushed through the blade.  Alternatively some saws have a fixed tray and a movable blade set up.  Depending on the complexity of the cuts you need to make, tile saws can also have a blade that can be tilted, or a mount that can be fixed to the tray to allow for inside and outside &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;miter cuts on stone veneer&lt;/a&gt;.  Either way, stone should cut nice and easy on a wet saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/29/Norstone Installation with Tile Wet Saw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tile Wet saw being used to cut Norstone Stacked Stone panels for a fireplace project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most important thing to remember when cutting stacked stone veneer on a tile wet saw is safety.  Eye protection is a must, and ear protection is a good idea as most units can get loud.  Working with electricity and power in the same tool requires extra diligence as well, so be sure to read the instruction manual and plug the the saw into a grounded outlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a tile wet saw will account for probably 95% or more of the cuts on most stacked stone veneer jobs, a hand held angle grinder is the tool of choice for everything else.  Whether you’re cutting a curve to fit around a pipe, or cutting a rectangle out of the panel to go around a light switch or outlet, an angle grinder is the tool for the job.  Since angle grinders don’t use water as a lubricant like a wet saw, cutting stacked stone veneer takes a little bit longer, can be ear screechingly loud, and create a lot of dust.  Blades also will need replaced much more frequently as compared to the wet saw.  Besides wearing eye and ear protection, heavy gloves are a great idea to protect hands and fingers from  stone chunks and the blade itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/29/Angle Grinder Cutting Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Angle grinder used for off angle and specialty cuts on stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tile wet saws are very commonly available to rent at local hardware equipment rental locations at a reasonable charge.  Unless you’re getting ready to do a bunch of tile and stone work, it’s generally worth renting this equipment, where you’ll typically get a higher grade saw, than purchasing a lower end one.  Quality angle grinders are available at reasonable price points if you can’t borrow one from a neighbor or friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for learning more about the best ways to cut stacked stone veneer with us today!  We enjoy sharing the knowledge and passion we have about our products and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;how to install stacked stone correctly&lt;/a&gt; with our customers and anyone interested in knowing more.  Please don’t hesitate to contact any of our reps who are well versed in technical knowledge of the product with any questions that you might have about stacked stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Calling all you DIY'ers out there – ever wondered how to best cut stacked stone under different conditions? Ask and you shall receive with this week's blog focusing on how to cut stacked stone veneer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/29/Norstone%20Installation%20with%20Tile%20Wet%20Saw.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Tile%20Wet%20Saw%20for%20Cutting%20Stacked%20Stone%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22In%20process%20installation%20of%20stacked%20stone%20on%20a%20fireplace%20where%20a%20tile%20wet%20saw%20is%20being%20used%20to%20make%20the%20cuts%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Glass, Steel, and Stone Make a Very Modern Home</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glass, Steel, and Stone Make a Very Modern Home" /><published>2018-01-22T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-and-stone-make-a-very-modern-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to modern residential architecture and design, three of the most prominent surfaces that you’ll see on the exterior envelope is glass, steel, and stone.  We’re ecstatic that the design team of this week’s featured project choose to use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL stone veneer rock panels&lt;/a&gt; as part of the stone package on this amazing home.  Let’s take a walk around the exterior of this project and have a look at how glass, steel, and stone blend together nicely in this modern beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Stone Glass and Steel Residential Modern Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street View of a Modern Designed Home featuring lots of glass, steel, and stone on its exterior surfaces&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The street facing elevation of the home makes an immediate impact with an enormous amount of glass windows, doors, and multi partition sliders, as well as a safety glass railing for the forward facing second story patio.  The steel elements are a little more subtle and are mainly used as accents on the soffits, hand rail, and house numbers.  Our stacked stone panels bring a major dose of contrasting texture to the columns, second story facade, and even along the privacy wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Modern Architecture Stone and Glass Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front Elevation of Modern Designed Home with a prominent stacked stone and glass facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As viewed from inside the privacy wall, two separate outdoor seating / lounging areas are revealed.  While viewing the house head on, the glass tends to dominate our attention, especially the mammoth single fixed window on the upper right hand side.  However, subtle details abound like the use of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;stone veneer on the risers separating the patio areas&lt;/a&gt; which bring a sophisticated cohesiveness to the design and helps this project stand out from the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Modern Architecture Stone and Glass Corner Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side View of the corner of a home with a glass corner on the first floor and stone veneer on the second story&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One side view of the home again shows the commitment to glass with a super unique corner on the first floor made entirely of glass.  Other types of stone are introduced with the large format paver walkway set in pebbles, as well as the continuation of the stone veneer along the second story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Two Story Outdoor Stone Veneer Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A large two story outdoor fireplace clad with stone veneer and a stainless steel firebox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stone take center stage on the opposite side of the home which has a tucked away outdoor fireplace.  This large feature is clad entirely in our large format XL Series stone veneer, appropriate for this two story fireplace with the stone going all the way up.  A sleek stainless steel firebox keeps with the modern theme and ties this space together with the other metallic elements in the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Norstone XL Series Outside Corner Unit Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Detail showing Norstone XL Series Corner Units used in a real life application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we’ve learned having worked on projects with our natural stone veneers and natural stone tile lines for over a dozen years is that details matter, which is why this last photo is a great example of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;what makes Norstone different than other stone veneer panels on the market&lt;/a&gt;.  This exceptional photo of our corner units used on the band between the first and second stories of the house shows just how great an outside corner of stone veneer should look.  Every piece of stone visible shows the natural cleft, there’s not discernible pattern as to how the pieces come together, and above all it looks natural and not fabricated.  This attention to detail, not just on our corner units but on all our products and our customer experience from start to finish, is what makes Norstone different than a panel you can pick up at your local big box home improvement or discount tile store, or order off a website with no pictures to back it up or consultation to answer your questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about working on a modern project in the future, glass, steel, and stone are great design materials to look to incorporate into the design.  Our more traditional stone veneer panels like the XL Series and Standard Series are a great way to incorporate a contrasting texture to the smoothness of glass and steel, while some of our other products like the smooth faced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Series&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tile Series&lt;/a&gt; are decidedly modern right out the box.  Contact our team today and speak with one of our in house designers to learn more about what natural stone veneer and tile products might be a great fit for your next project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We love the architecture of this modern home with its abundance of glass, steel, and stone throughout its design. Let's take a closer look in this week's blog on what makes this house so special.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/23/Stone%20Glass%20and%20Steel%20Residential%20Modern%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Glass,%20Steel%20and%20Stacked%20Stone%20for%20a%20Modern%20Residential%20Facade%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Exterior%20of%20a%20residential%20home%20with%20a%20modern%20design%20scheme%20prominently%20featuring%20glass,%20steel,%20and%20stone%22%7D" /></entry></feed>