<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-23T16:59:21-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Glass, Steel, and Stone Make a Very Modern Home</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glass, Steel, and Stone Make a Very Modern Home" /><published>2018-01-22T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-and-stone-make-a-very-modern-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to modern residential architecture and design, three of the most prominent surfaces that you’ll see on the exterior envelope is glass, steel, and stone.  We’re ecstatic that the design team of this week’s featured project choose to use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL stone veneer rock panels&lt;/a&gt; as part of the stone package on this amazing home.  Let’s take a walk around the exterior of this project and have a look at how glass, steel, and stone blend together nicely in this modern beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Stone Glass and Steel Residential Modern Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street View of a Modern Designed Home featuring lots of glass, steel, and stone on its exterior surfaces&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The street facing elevation of the home makes an immediate impact with an enormous amount of glass windows, doors, and multi partition sliders, as well as a safety glass railing for the forward facing second story patio.  The steel elements are a little more subtle and are mainly used as accents on the soffits, hand rail, and house numbers.  Our stacked stone panels bring a major dose of contrasting texture to the columns, second story facade, and even along the privacy wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Modern Architecture Stone and Glass Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front Elevation of Modern Designed Home with a prominent stacked stone and glass facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As viewed from inside the privacy wall, two separate outdoor seating / lounging areas are revealed.  While viewing the house head on, the glass tends to dominate our attention, especially the mammoth single fixed window on the upper right hand side.  However, subtle details abound like the use of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;stone veneer on the risers separating the patio areas&lt;/a&gt; which bring a sophisticated cohesiveness to the design and helps this project stand out from the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Modern Architecture Stone and Glass Corner Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side View of the corner of a home with a glass corner on the first floor and stone veneer on the second story&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One side view of the home again shows the commitment to glass with a super unique corner on the first floor made entirely of glass.  Other types of stone are introduced with the large format paver walkway set in pebbles, as well as the continuation of the stone veneer along the second story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Two Story Outdoor Stone Veneer Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A large two story outdoor fireplace clad with stone veneer and a stainless steel firebox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stone take center stage on the opposite side of the home which has a tucked away outdoor fireplace.  This large feature is clad entirely in our large format XL Series stone veneer, appropriate for this two story fireplace with the stone going all the way up.  A sleek stainless steel firebox keeps with the modern theme and ties this space together with the other metallic elements in the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Norstone XL Series Outside Corner Unit Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Detail showing Norstone XL Series Corner Units used in a real life application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we’ve learned having worked on projects with our natural stone veneers and natural stone tile lines for over a dozen years is that details matter, which is why this last photo is a great example of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;what makes Norstone different than other stone veneer panels on the market&lt;/a&gt;.  This exceptional photo of our corner units used on the band between the first and second stories of the house shows just how great an outside corner of stone veneer should look.  Every piece of stone visible shows the natural cleft, there’s not discernible pattern as to how the pieces come together, and above all it looks natural and not fabricated.  This attention to detail, not just on our corner units but on all our products and our customer experience from start to finish, is what makes Norstone different than a panel you can pick up at your local big box home improvement or discount tile store, or order off a website with no pictures to back it up or consultation to answer your questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about working on a modern project in the future, glass, steel, and stone are great design materials to look to incorporate into the design.  Our more traditional stone veneer panels like the XL Series and Standard Series are a great way to incorporate a contrasting texture to the smoothness of glass and steel, while some of our other products like the smooth faced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Series&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tile Series&lt;/a&gt; are decidedly modern right out the box.  Contact our team today and speak with one of our in house designers to learn more about what natural stone veneer and tile products might be a great fit for your next project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We love the architecture of this modern home with its abundance of glass, steel, and stone throughout its design. Let's take a closer look in this week's blog on what makes this house so special.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/23/Stone%20Glass%20and%20Steel%20Residential%20Modern%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Glass,%20Steel%20and%20Stacked%20Stone%20for%20a%20Modern%20Residential%20Facade%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Exterior%20of%20a%20residential%20home%20with%20a%20modern%20design%20scheme%20prominently%20featuring%20glass,%20steel,%20and%20stone%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Freeze – Thaw Cycles Can Impact Stacked Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/freeze-thaw-and-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Freeze – Thaw Cycles Can Impact Stacked Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-01-17T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-17T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-freeze-thaw-cycles-can-impact-stacked-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/freeze-thaw-and-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Looking outside our office window in sunny Florida its definitely a rare event to see a hard freeze covering the grass, plants, and roofs with frost, but that’s just what we’re dealing with on this cold January morning.  And while it doesn’t happen but maybe once or twice a winter here in Florida, freeze – thaw cycling is a daily occurrence for many parts of the country for most winter.  The impacts of freeze – thaw cycling can be huge on all sorts of building materials, but for purposes of this blog, we’re going to look at how freeze – thaw cycling can impact a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stone veneer installation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first questions we get when we present our stone veneer panels or natural stone tile products to architects and designers is whether or not they can be used for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exterior stone installations&lt;/a&gt;, and if they can be used outside, what about freeze – thaw areas?  It’s an on point question because any residual moisture in a stone installation will expand when frozen, with the big risk being that the expansion and contraction caused by freeze – thaw cycling ends up destabilizing the install, and maybe even going so far as to crack a stone or pop it off the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/18/Exterior Stone Vener Columns in Freeze Thaw Climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exterior Stacked Stone Veneer Columns lakeside in Wisconsin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a particularly valid question with our stone veneer panels.  Since these veneers are installed in a “dry stack” fashion, meaning no mortar goes in between the individual pieces of stone, there is clearly ample cracks, crevices and fissures for water and moisture to travel through, water log the substrate and create significant expansion during a freeze cycle.  More traditional stone veneers, specifically applications where mortar is “pointed” after the stone is set to fill in all the gaps between stones in an installation are seemingly much closer to being “water tight” and preventing much, if any water from getting through the stone and into the substrate.  So what’s the answer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/18/Stacked Stone Veneer in Freeze Thaw Climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Rock Panels in Snowy New England Climate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to this freeze – thaw conundrum for dry stacked stone veneer lies in both the substrate and the stone itself.  From a substrate standpoint, installers should plan for water to pass through stone veneer and into the substrate, there’s simply no way to prevent that in a dry stacked stone installation.  However, by using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;waterproofing and crack isolation membrane&lt;/a&gt; over the substrate and a freeze – thaw stable thinset, not only can you install dry stacked stone veneer panels, but you can even install natural stone tiles requiring grout, like our Lynia IL tiles.  The crack isolation membrane is specifically designed to absorb the small stresses created by freeze – thaw cycling without destabilizing an installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a stone standpoint, you also have to make sure the stone itself is freeze thaw tested.  Even if the substrate its stuck to is stable in these changing conditions, the stone itself might still show signs of freeze – thaw cycling.  Part of the process we go through when evaluating new products is to have them tested according to the ASTM C67 test, which soaks the stone samples for 4.5 hours in room temperature water, then freezes them for 20 hours, and then repeats this cycle 50 times.  The samples are examined every 5 cycles under magnification to look for any signs of cracking or fissuring.  A stone type that can crack or fissure under this type of testing would not be suited for exterior use as a building material in a freeze – thaw climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/18/Exterior Stacked Stone in Freeze Thaw Climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dry stack stone veneer used exterior on a North Carolina Lake in a freeze thaw climate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these products and techniques are still fairly new, maybe 10-15 years old, so in an industry like stone masonry where knowledge has been accumulating for centuries, there can be a knowledge gap between an experienced installer who might be doing things the same way as they were taught 30 years ago, versus an installer that might be more up to date on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;latest products, tools, and techniques that are coming into the tile and stone industry&lt;/a&gt; and making their jobs easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you found this article informative, especially if you have questions about how stacked stone veneer can be used in freeze – thaw locations.  Feel free to speak with any of our reps who are very knowledgeable in the technical aspects of installing our products and find out how a Norstone natural stone veneer or tile product can be a great fit for your next project.  And for those of us experiencing this winter cold snap – stay warm!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Freeze – thaw cycles have the potential to really impact an exterior stacked stone installation if not done correctly. In this week's blog we learn why freeze – thaw is such a big deal and the best way to address it in on a stacked stone project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/18/Exterior%20Stacked%20Stone%20in%20Freeze%20Thaw%20Climate.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Dry%20Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20in%20Freeze%20Thaw%20Climate%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20XL%20Series%20Charcoal%20Rock%20Panels%20used%20in%20an%20exterior%20freeze%20thaw%20installation%20in%20North%20Carolina%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Contemporary Texas Kitchen with Stone Veneer Fireplace</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/texas-kitchen-stone-veneer-fireplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contemporary Texas Kitchen with Stone Veneer Fireplace" /><published>2018-01-15T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/contemporary-texas-kitchen-with-stone-veneer-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/texas-kitchen-stone-veneer-fireplace/">&lt;p&gt;Austin, TX is a beautiful city with a rich culture of locally sourced stone used for building materials.  Texas limestone is a beautiful stone that is primarily a very light cream color, but can occasionally dip into some of the darker yellow and gold tones as well, where it can start to sometimes resemble our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Quartz Stone Veneer&lt;/a&gt;.  Anyone that has gotten the opportunity to visit this city has certainly seen the stone, as it is used prominently on facade work throughout the area, and if you pay attention to stone veneer, you’ll likely have even seen some of this in your local area as its popularity has spread far and wide.  The popularity of Texas limestone is one of the things that make this week’s project profile so compelling, since right in the heart of limestone country, this homeowner decided to flip the script and go with a bold black and white color scheme and an accent wall of our quartz stone veneer.  Let’s take a closer look at some of the things which make this project so unique!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that sticks out to us in the space is the bold use of a black and white color scheme.  Starting wit the floors and ceiling and then continuing on through the cabinets, counter tops and lighting fixtures, the design of this space knew what it was going for from a color standpoint and executed on it.  While we really love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/two-toned-modern-fireplace-in-ft-collins-co/&quot;&gt;two tone color scheme&lt;/a&gt; of the kitchen island, especially the texture side of the cabinetry, the gorgeous stacked stone wall created using our charcoal rock panels stands out and introduces more of a texture element to the overall smooth aesthetic the other surfaces create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/16/Stone Veneer Accent Wall with Ventless Fireplace - Austin,TX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charcoal Stone Veneer Wall in Kitchen with a ventless gas fireplace and tree branch art&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the stone accent wall really special is the ventless gas fireplace.  These units are relatively easy to install making them a good option for a smaller scale remodel where they can make a big impact visually, but not over complicate a project like a traditional vented fireplace requiring exhaust.  Beyond the stunning visual impact of the long linear unit, what we really like about the fireplace is what it says about the space.  A flat screen television could easily have been hung in the same space on this stone accent wall, but by choosing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;stone veneer fireplace&lt;/a&gt; for this location the area encourages conversation or quite reflection, and provides a sense of calmness to the kitchen, which is often the central hub of a home before, during, and after meal times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really couldn’t get past talking about this wall without bringing up the unique tree branch art piece that gracefully sits atop the stone accent wall.  What exactly is it?  We’re not sure but its defiantly a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/&quot;&gt;unique pairing for a stone wal&lt;/a&gt;l, and we love the conversation starter aspect of it, the unique texture and natural feel that it brings the space.  Kudos to the installer for keeping us, and everyone else, guessing as to how it stays in place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/16/Kitchen Stone Veneer Accent Wall - Austin,TX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Window seat nook at the end of a long kitchen with a stone veneer accent wall in Austin, TX&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functional spaces and attention to detail are the hallmarks of good design, and this tiny space in the corner on the short end of a long kitchen is very well done.  Continuing the stone veneer accent wall over the hallway and into this little bench seat area creates continuity with the rest of the space, and the attention to detail as shown through the adjustable reading lamp and light switch add little bits of character to the stone accent wall and help break it up in much the same way the fireplace does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bold black and white design with varied textures and lots of things to look at is certain to make this Texas kitchen project standout, and while a big stone wall doesn’t work for every kitchen,  it certainly does for this space.  If you’re considering stone for your next kitchen project, talk to us today about how Norstone natural stone veneer and tile products can easily transform your space into something you love!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">There's so much to love about this kitchen recently completed in a re-developing area area of Texas' Capitol city of Austin, especially the super cool stone wall with a low maintenance but stylishly designed ventless fireplace. Let's take a look at all the things that make this project cool in this week's project profile!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/16/Stone%20Veneer%20Accent%20Wall%20with%20Ventless%20Fireplace%20-%20Austin,TX.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Veneer%20Accent%20Wall%20in%20Austin,%20TX%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20Stone%20Veneer%20Accent%20wall%20in%20modern%20black%20and%20white%20themed%20kitchen%20in%20Austin,%20TX%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2018 Resolutions in Stacked Stone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-resolutions-in-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 Resolutions in Stacked Stone" /><published>2018-01-02T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-02T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-resolutions-in-stacked-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-resolutions-in-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Whether individually, or as a collective group like the team here at Norstone, the beginning of the year is always a great time to reflect back on the past year and put together some resolutions for the upcoming one.  We see a lot of great things on the horizon for Norstone and the decorative stone and tile industry as a whole, and look forward to turning this list of resolutions into reality for 2018 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #1 - Continue to Launch New and Exciting Stone Veneer Products&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the heels of our highly successful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lynia-and-aksent-launch/&quot;&gt;launch of the White Marble and Beige Marble products in the Lynia and Aksent series&lt;/a&gt; this past Fall, we are already preparing a slate of  new stone veneer products for the Spring and Summer of 2018.  Of all the new products which are being market tested by some of our global distributors right now, we are most excited about a new large format (up to 30+ inches) single unit smooth face stone planks made from both basalt and lavastone.  Being firmly planted in the light grey to black color palette, these products should be priced similarly to our stacked stone panel products and offer a very modern and architecturally bold look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone Planc Lavastone Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Format Stone Veneer Strips made of Lavastone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, a planned trip in the Spring to our production facility in Asia promises to set the course for the Fall and Winter of 2018 with products that are currently in the R&amp;amp;D process by our creative team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #2 – Continue to Improve our Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the addition of more product lines to show to our customers, we plan to make our website more user friendly and easier to navigate.  When we first laid down the architecture and theme for the current site we had three product series and eight total products.  With products now well into the 20s with the potential addition of many more in 2018, we’ll look to make navigating between products and galleries easier and more intuitive.  We also are hard at work beta testing a new order process which will allow customers to purchase samples directly from the website 24 hours a day / 7 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone Website Nav.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Norstone's website showing product navigation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #3 – Continue to blog every week and produce content valuable to our customers and the industry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January 20th of this year will mark one year where we’ve been producing, on average, one blog post per week.  We look forward to continuing to produce content for the Norstone line of stacked stone, stone veneer, and stone tile products and for the broader stone, tile, and wall coverings industry as a whole.  We’ll focus even more on our popular “how to” guides, which answer common questions people have about working with stone products, like our very popular post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/&quot;&gt;“How to Install a Flat Screen TV on a Stacked Stone Wall”&lt;/a&gt; as well as our technical posts, which cover a variety of important topics in the stone industry from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;“The Importance of Sealing Natural Stone Veneer&lt;/a&gt;” to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;“Using Waterpoofing Membranes in Exterior Stacked Stone Installations”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone Ivory Stacked Stone Residential Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Stacked Stone Veneer used on Residential Facade project in SW Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #4 - Get feedback and show appreciation to our customers and supporters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to hear from our customers, through email, social media, or any other way we can communicate to get feedback about our stone veneer products and their experiences and interactions with our company and reward loyal customers with return incentives, perks, and bonuses.  Be on the look out here and in our social media channels for updates, flash sales, and give aways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to making 2018 a special year and thank you for being a part of the Norstone stone veneer community!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The team at Norstone and the New Dimensions in Natural Stone blog hope you and yours had an amazing holiday season and very happy new year. In this week's blog we wanted to outline resolutions we've put together to make 2018 the best year for natural stone yet!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Basalt%20Tile%20Rooftop%20Terrace.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Rooftop%20Lounge%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20used%20on%20a%20focal%20wall%20in%20an%20upscale%20rooftop%20lounge%20in%20Washington,%20D.C.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grey Aksent 3D Stone on a UK Modern Masterpiece</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-uk-modern-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Aksent 3D Stone on a UK Modern Masterpiece" /><published>2017-12-25T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-25T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-stone-on-a-uk-modern-masterpiece</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-uk-modern-home/">&lt;p&gt;One of the really amazing things about Norstone is our &lt;a href=&quot;http://norstone.global/&quot;&gt;worldwide distribution network&lt;/a&gt;.  With distributors in Australia, Asia, Europe, and the Middle East, we get to see and share the projects we are working on.  It’s cool to see the same stone veneer products get used in a vast range of projects and styles across the globe.  In certain instances, our preconceived notions about what architecture and design look like in a certain area are blown away, which was certainly the case with this project from Southern England.  Situated in an outer suburb of Poole, England, a major shipping lane across the English Channel from the UK to France, this fantastically modern design home which used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lynia-and-aksent-launch/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Panels&lt;/a&gt; on the exterior looks like it could have been plucked from a California hillside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer - UK House Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer used on the exterior of a modern home in the UK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major things that stands about this project is the contrasting yet natural color range the design team employed throughout. White pavers and knee walls contrast the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/grey/&quot;&gt;Grey Stone of the Aksent 3D Panels&lt;/a&gt;, which flow neatly into metal doors and accents, large sections of glass, and wood look large format composite siding.  Set in a heavily wooded area, all of the major colors in the design scheme can be found within a few feet of the buildings themselves.  The great contrast in colors keeps the buildings themselves clean and modern looking, but we’re glad the design team choose to a natural color pallet which will allow this project and design to age gracefully for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The side building in the photo above is a garage that is separated from the home.  What a detached garage might lack for in convenience, this particular one makes up for in design.  With a generous amount of the smooth stone veneer around the garage doors, this outer building compliments the architecture of the main building nicely.  Detaching the garage in this instance also allows for a more uninterrupted use of the property, which sits on a hillside with the rear of the property sitting lower than the front.  While a bunch of fill dirt could have undoubtedly been brought in to level off the lot and leave the rear of the property unusable, we applaud the designer’s choice of separating the buildings and working more within the confines of the lot.  The result – buildings that look amazing and fit nicely within the nicely wooded property and not another McMansion built after a developer knocks all the trees down and levels the ground for fast and easy construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer - UK House Patio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer creating lots of texture on a patio wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are a lot of great materials and products being used on the outer envelope of this home, we think the grey stone veneer has the most powerful impact owing to the abundance of texture the product creates.  With everything else smooth and flat, the Aksent 3D Panel allows for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;clean lined, smooth faced look&lt;/a&gt; to match the other materials, but also gives the walls that dimensional “pop” that comes with stone veneer.  The Aksent 3D panels come with about 1/2” of variation in depth, which is an important dimension to consider when trying to create a dimensional look on a vertical surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer - UK House Garden.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer used on two buildings seperated by modern landscaping and hardscaping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another really cool design feature of this project is the landscaping / hardscaping.  We really love the large format smooth pebbles used around the house.  Color wise they do a great job tying together the pavers and other elements of the large driveway and create a nice contrast against the grey stone veneer panels.  Texture wise, the smoothness of the rocks parlays nicely with the overall smooth textures found throughout the rest of the exterior, while the semi circular / round shape is a nice foil to the block geometry of the Aksent 3D Panel they but up against.  Large format rectangular smooth concrete pavers form a nice outer ring to the pebble hardscape, reasserting a more traditional shape associated with modern design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking the time to tour this really cool project with us in Southern England.  We love how great our Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Panels look and that our products get to be used on cool projects like this one.  We have a worldwide team of experts ready to answer your stone questions and show you how Norstone natural stone veneer products can work on your next project – rustic or modern, we have the stone to fit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Norstone Aksent 3D panels in Grey are a perfect fit for this modern home in the South of England. Let's take a look at some of what makes this project so special and a great use of this stone veneer project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent%203D%20Grey%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20UK%20House%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Aksent%203D%20Grey%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20UK%20Modern%20Home%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Aksent%203D%20Grey%20Stone%20used%20on%20exterior%20of%20modern%20home%20in%20Southern%20England%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone’s Top 5 Stone Fireplaces of 2017</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-fireplaces-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone's Top 5 Stone Fireplaces of 2017" /><published>2017-12-18T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-s-top-5-stone-fireplaces-of-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-fireplaces-2017/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a great year for the Norstone team and we hope it has been for you too.  In honor of the Christmas season, where the fireplace plays a critical conduit in getting Santa and his presents into our homes, we took a look back at the stone fireplaces we featured on our blog this year, voted on them and present to you Norstone’s top 5 stone fireplaces of 2017!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Two Tone Stacked Stone Fireplace Fort Collins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone fireplace with two types of stone used in an ornate living room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming in at number five on list is this super unique&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/two-toned-modern-fireplace-in-ft-collins-co/&quot;&gt; two toned stone fireplace&lt;/a&gt; in Fort Collins, Colorado.  We’ve seen a ton of stone fireplaces in our time and this is one of the few ones we’ve seen incorporate two different types of surfaces, both stone in this instance, and make it look good.  The blocky geometric look of our Aksent 3D Panels in Ash Grey flanks a vertical stripe of lighter greyish creamy colored stone.  The colors work well with the décor of this beautifully decorated space and the vertical nature of the stripe accentuates the already high ceiling in the room.  Bravo to the team at Springhaus Interiors out of Fort Collins on this great job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Grey Basalt Aksent Ledge Stone Fireplace Kansas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey used on a fireplace with lots of detail including recessed tv, fireplace, and built in shelves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number four fireplace on our list is another cool &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/3d-ledge-stone-kansas/&quot;&gt;fireplace application of the Aksent 3D panels in Ash Grey&lt;/a&gt;, that just exudes detail.  With stone going wall to wall in the application, the recessed linear gas fireplace is almost lost a midst a recessed flat screen tv and built in shelves with under-mount lighting.  The one thing that really sets this project apart is actually the extensive use of our outside corner units which give a seamless look as the fireplace projects out from the wall and then turns back towards the recessed fireplace insert and tv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Modern Living Room with Lynia Tile Fireplace in Chicago.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large stone tile fireplace in modern designed living room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third on our list of the best stacked stone fireplaces is this cool &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stone-fireplace-chicago/&quot;&gt;Ebony Lynia IL Tile fireplace in Chicago&lt;/a&gt;.  Even though this is a really big fireplace with stone going floor to ceiling and probably close to 8 feet wide, the smooth texture of the Lynia tiles doesn’t over power the space and compliments the long linear nature of the gas insert as well.  The modern styled décor is perfectly matched to the dark ebony color of the stone and the smooth texture of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Ochre Stacked Stone Fireplace - Austin, TX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two way stacked stone fireplace that can be seen both inside and outside&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we certainly saw a surging trend towards stone with darker colors and smoother textures in 2017, we couldn’t help but admire this awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ochre-ochre-everywhere-in-this-magnificent-austin-tx-modern-home/&quot;&gt;stacked stone fireplace application in Austin, TX&lt;/a&gt;, which comes in at number two on our list.  Although not meant to be the focal point of this dining room, this pass through fireplace going from the inside to an exterior seating area is a super cool feature that we just couldn’t pass up giving some love to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Ebony Basalt Lynia Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Bold Color Accents-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern basalt stone tile fireplace with large tv and bright color accents in the space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the top ranked stone fireplace of 2017, as voted on by the team here at Norstone, is this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge/&quot;&gt;super cool Ebony Lynia IL Stone Tile fireplace in Philadelphia&lt;/a&gt;.  The sheer size of the stone wall, the massive length of the fireplace, the cool cut outs, and funky accent color scheme all come together in this superb installation.  The durability of the stone is both practical and durable for this application in the common area of student housing at a local university, and cool enough to impress both prospective students and their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoyed our list of the top 5 stone fireplaces of 2017 and wish you and yours a tremendous holiday season and an awesome new year in 2018.  And no matter how great it might look, remember to turn off those fireplaces on December 24th so our friend in the red suit can make his annual visit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">In honor of Jolly Old St. Nick, who's made a name for himself coming through fireplaces, here are our top 5 stone fireplaces of 2017. Santa will be sure lucky if he gets to visit one of these houses in a few nights and might even pause to admire how great they look!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/12/20/Ebony%20Basalt%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Bold%20Color%20Accents.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Top%205%20Stone%20Fireplaces%20of%202017%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22The%20top%205%20stone%20fireplaces%20of%202017%20as%20voted%20on%20by%20the%20team%20at%20Norstone%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Charcoal XL Mid Century Modern Home</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/charcoal-xl-mid-century-modern-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Charcoal XL Mid Century Modern Home" /><published>2017-12-11T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-11T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/charcoal-xl-mid-century-modern-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/charcoal-xl-mid-century-modern-home/">&lt;p&gt;This cool house in Massachusetts caught our eye today when looking for a project to profile on this week’s blog.  Believe it or not, this project was worked on close to a decade ago, well before the current influx of grey and charcoal tones into the “trending” color pallete.  But with its on point style and great use of neutral colors, this house is built to weather &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;design trends&lt;/a&gt; as they come and go with classic mid century modern touches.  Let’s take a look at the stone installation and what makes this home so special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/12/Charcoal XL Residential Stone Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone Veneer on Facade of Mid Century Modern Home with White Brick&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exterior of the home has the most prominent dark and light contrasting color scheme of the entire property.  The uniformity of the white painted brick is a terrific contrast to the texture the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt; Charcoal XL stacked stone wall&lt;/a&gt; provides as it flanks the front door.  Bluestone pavers and stair treads from a nice bridge both color and texture wise between the brick and stone veneer.  And not to be lost are the subtle details, like the stainless steel house numbers, door knob, and stair railing which work nicely into the color scheme, or the cool floating wood bench which is a super unique design element to see in an exterior entryway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/12/Charcoal XL Residential Entryway Stone Accent Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charcoal Colored Stone Accent Wall in entryway of home with floating bench&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continue on our tour to the inside of the home the first thing you’ll notice is that both the stone and the bench also continue into the foyer / entryway.  This design technique of continuing a stone accent wall from the exterior to the interior is something we see often in commercial projects like restaurants and office buildings, and has been expertly completed in this space.  What also stands out to me in this view is the larger format of the individual stones in the Charcoal XL Panel.  With some of, if not the biggest individual pieces of stone in a panel system product, our XL series panels make a big, chunky look like you see here possible.  Finally, the light streaming through the sidelight panel next to the door gives the wall some subtle color movement and accentuates the texture and clean line geometry of the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/12/Charcoal XL Residential Stone Veneer Stairwell.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone Veneer used in Stairwell of Home&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;finger jointed outside corner units&lt;/a&gt; allow the stone to deftly turn two outside corners as it works it way around the foyer wall and into a cool stairwell leading to the lower level.  The continuity of this project as it works it way from the outside to the inside and then down to the lower level is a really cool design element, and is one of the reasons why accessory products like our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-ends-norstone-s-latest-addition-to-standard-and-xl-series-rock-panels/&quot;&gt;natural ends&lt;/a&gt; and outside corner units are such an important part of our product offering.  Mid Century Modern touches abound here with a cool wood and glass plan stair railing and large &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;dome shaped speckled glass pendant fixtures&lt;/a&gt;.  These modern touches feed into the clean lines and blocky texture of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/12/Charcoal XL Stacked Stone Garden Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charcoal Stacked Stone Garden Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cool garden wall which separates a hardscaped patio and grilling area from the yard is the final stone feature to admire on this project.  The dark grey color of the Charcoal XL panels pairs well with the bluestone caps, stair treads, and pavers of the space, and the overall grey / charcoal color pallete works nicely against the green landscaping.  We also love this picture as it shows the stone drying out after a rain, when an exterior stacked stone wall seems like it comes alive as it continually changes how it looks during the drying process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoyed revisiting this cool project in Massachusetts and it inspired you for your next stone job.  Whether its things like the floating bench or the outside corners used to create continuity between the foyer and stairwell, this project reminds us that while the big picture is what you’ll see first, the details are what makes something unique and memorable.  Let us show you how Norstone tile and stone veneer products can make your next project both!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We instantly loved this modern inspired home in Massachusetts for the contrasting White Brick and Charcoal XL Stone Veneer exterior before we even realized how cool the inside and backyard was. Take a look at this cool house in this week's project profile.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/12/12/Charcoal%20XL%20Residential%20Entryway%20Stone%20Accent%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20XL%20Stone%20Veneer%20Foyer%20Accent%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20Stone%20Veneer%20Accent%20wall%20in%20foyer%20of%20mid%20century%20modern%20home%20with%20floating%20bench%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Common Problems with Stacked Stone on a Fireplace and How To Fix Them</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/common-problems-stacked-stone-fireplaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Common Problems with Stacked Stone on a Fireplace and How To Fix Them " /><published>2017-12-04T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/common-problems-with-stacked-stone-on-a-fireplace-and-how-to-fix-them</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/common-problems-stacked-stone-fireplaces/">&lt;p&gt;As the temperature drops outside this winter, more and more people will light up their fireplace for both warmth and ambiance.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/fireplace-renovations-small-budget-project-with-big-return-on-investment/&quot;&gt;Fireplaces offer a great ROI for home renovation dollars&lt;/a&gt;, and we’ve sold sold our stacked stone panels to literally hundreds, maybe even thousands of fireplace projects since the mid 2000s, giving us a lot of experience in the design of these units, as well as their installation and operational maintenance.  From a stone standpoint, there’s two main areas of concern that our clients occasionally see – discoloration of the stone over time and the stone itself heating up to the touch.  Let’s take a look at what causes each of these and the best way to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discoloration on the stacked stone face of a fireplace is almost always caused by a malfunctioning fireplace insert or improper use of a more traditional wood burning fireplace box.  Wood smoke is a heavy carrier of natural carbon compounds that will easily attach themselves to the rough texture of a stacked stone wall in the form of soot.  Even gas fireplaces, since most of them rely on natural gas or propane that has an added chemical compound to make the gas smell for leak detection can create detectable exhaust staining against stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/05/Stacked Stone Fireplace With Soot Staining.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Soot Staining on a stacked stone fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix the problem of smoke or excess gas fireplace exhaust coming into the room it’s best to perform normal checks like ensuring the damper is open and flue is clear of any obstructions, the room has adequate air supply for the fireplace, the grate is positioned correctly within the firebox and the wood being burned has the appropriate moisture content.  If the fireplace is still letting smoke / exhaust into the room, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-find-a-contractor-on-houzz/&quot;&gt;find a fireplace expert&lt;/a&gt; to consult with and have check for other potential problems like a mismatched fireplace opening for the flue, lack of chimney or flue length for the application, downdrafts, and negative pressure situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/05/Stacked Stone Fireplace with Gas Exhaust Stain.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Gas exhaust discoloring stacked stone on a fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the fireplace is operating correctly, fireplace soot and exhaust is best removed from the surface of stacked stone in a tiered process, going from least abrasive to most abrasive cleaning agents.  The first tier would involve using a simple detergent based soap, hot water, and a stiff plastic bristle brush to remove the staining.  If that isn’t successful, the next tier up would involve a non acidic stone specific cleaner.  We’ve used a product called Nanoscrub by Aquamix on our stone before with good results.  If the staining persists, the final tier involves spot treating the stain with a sulfamic acid solution.  As with any cleaning job on natural stone, always follow the manufacturer’s instructions for application and test the cleaner on a sample, or in an inconspicuous place, first to confirm the results.  Once cleaned, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;sealing the stone with a natural stone sealer&lt;/a&gt; is a worthwhile investment to make any future clean ups easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other common problem we see with fireplaces is that the stacked stone on the face of the fireplace unit itself is getting hot to the touch.  The heat can be caused by outflow from the fireplace or if the wall itself is heating up from the firebox / chimney.  This is more and more important today than even 10 or 15 years ago as many fireplaces sit right beneath expensive televisions and other electronics that can be impacted due to excess heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/05/Stacked Stone Fireplace with TV Installed Above.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flat Screen TV installed above a heat producing fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mocking up what would best be described as a temporary mantle is a good way to check for this.  Something as simple as a 2x6 supported on the sides positioned 18” above the fireplace will work.  Checking temperature above and below the temporary mantle with an infrared temperature gun, and comparing that to a baseline reading without the mantle will tell you if the heat is traveling up the face of the stone on the room side, which the mantle will block and result in lower temperatures above it, or if the temperatures stay consistent with the temporary mantle in place the wall itself is the source of the heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix these heat problems, its always a good idea to contact the manufacture of the fireplace insert itself to determine if the unit seems to be functioning within spec.  The manufacturer may be able to point to unit specific changes that can be made that will impact the way the heat is produced and distributed to fix the problem.  If the fireplace is a more traditional open fire box, making sure the right size grate is being used and possibly the installation of a mantel can prevent heat from continuing to travel up the stone face of the fireplace.  Excess heat, especially if its making the stacked stone face of a fireplace hot to the touch is a bad thing.  If simple adjustments to the fireplace insert don’t fix the problem, a fireplace expert should definitely be called to ensure the unit is operating safely and poses no risk of danger while operating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/05/Outdoor Stacked Stone Fireplace with Large Open Firebox-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Fire in an outdoor stacked stone fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fireplaces are a welcome and desired addition to any home, and stacked stone is a great choice for a new application or to rejuvenate a dated fireplace.  Learn more about using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;Norstone Stacked Stone for fireplaces&lt;/a&gt; on our website or by calling one of our knowledgeable reps today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Let's take a look at two of the most common problems people see when using a fireplace clad in stacked stone and what the process looks like to fix these issues.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/12/05/Outdoor%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%20with%20Large%20Open%20Firebox.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Outdoor%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Outdoor%20wood%20burning%20stacked%20stone%20fireplace%20with%20large%20firebox%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Lynia IL Modern Stone Fireplace in Chicago</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stone-fireplace-chicago/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Lynia IL Modern Stone Fireplace in Chicago" /><published>2017-11-27T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-lynia-il-tile-modern-fireplace-in-chicago</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stone-fireplace-chicago/">&lt;p&gt;A lot of people think Chicago and immediately think brick because of the city’s rich history with that building material.  From the facades of buildings to thousands upon thousands of fireplaces inside the loop and out in the ‘burbs, Chicago brick was a staple building material in the windy city for much of the past 200 years.  We love the brick look, and especially some of the companies that are now salvaging and re-using old Chicago brick for new projects, we also really love the design of this family’s Chicago living room with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Norstone Lynia IL Tile&lt;/a&gt; in Ebony featured prominently on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;large modern stone fireplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/11/28/Modern Living Room with Stone Tile Fireplace in Chicago.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern inspired Living Room with prominent dark stone fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things that catches our eye in the space is the great use of color and light.  The Ebony Basalt Stone is naturally a very dark color, which could really bring down the overall look and feel of a room, but in this instance the space benefits from great natural light entering through two long dormer windows flanking the fireplace and glass door in the room.  Light colored flooring and accent colored furniture brighten up the room as well, but what catches our eye the most is the bluish green paint color on the side walls which works so well with the darker colors of the Ebony Basalt Stone.  Dark grey colors and the dark color pallete often have a significant amount of blue undertones, and in this example the wall colors are both light and cheery but also compliment the stone color perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/11/28/Modern Gas Fireplace Insert on Stone Tile Fireplace Chicago.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern All Glass Fireplace Insert set at waist level on a black stone tile fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fireplace unit itself, as seen in this close up picture, is long and linear to compliment the patterned mosaic of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-mesh-backed-tile/&quot;&gt;easy to install mesh backed Lynia tile&lt;/a&gt;, and also raised to be more at waist level than the traditional fireplace position nearer the floor.  This glass enclosed gas fireplace is less about pushing out heat and more about great looks and the ambiance it creates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/11/28/Stone Tile Modern Fireplace with Built In Shelves Chicago.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Built in Cabinents and Shelves flanking a large modern stone tile fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built in cabinets and shelving are always a great thing to have as a homeowner, and in this space there’s no exception.  The added storage of the cabinets helps keep the space live-able while reducing clutter when necessary, and all the surface space created by the counter tops and shelves are a decorator’s dream.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth stone face&lt;/a&gt; of the Lynia Tiles as they wrap around the outside corner away from the fireplace and back towards the wall makes it easy to abut shelving or a countertop snug up against the stone, a common issue with built ins and more variable faced fireplace material like stacked stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/11/28/Stone Tile Modern Fireplace Chicago.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Designed Living Room with Large Black Stone Tile Fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last picture does a great job of capturing the modern essence of the space.  All of the individual elements come together nicely, from the sleek and linear pattern natural stone tiles to the fireplace unit itself, to the bright and mid century inspired furniture, everything comes together to create a cohesive look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we like most about our products at Norstone is the wide range of projects we get to work with our clients on and see our stone get used for.  While we might be better known for our stacked stone rock panels, offering a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;rustic split face stone look with a contemporary clean line twist&lt;/a&gt;, we love the new products we’ve been developing over the past couple years, especially the smooth faced Lynia IL Tiles and Aksent 3D Panel Series, to share our love of natural stone and experience creating unique and easy to use wall systems with our clients.  Whatever your project and whatever design style you’re inspired by, we hope to have a unique natural stone wall covering that might interest you.  Call us today to talk to one of our knowledgeable on staff designers to start the process of creating your next space around natural stone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our Lynia tile in the ebony color is a real dark and seductive product and even in this beautifully designed Chicago living space still dominates the space with a fireplace we can't take our eyes off of. In this week's blog we're going to take a look at what makes this product and project an inspiration for any modern fireplace design.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/11/28/Stone%20Tile%20Modern%20Fireplace%20Chicago.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Modern%20Stone%20Fireplace%20in%20Chicago%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20IL%20tiles%20in%20Ebony%20on%20a%20modern%20stone%20fireplace%20project%20in%20Chicago%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Find a Contractor on Houzz</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-find-a-contractor-on-houzz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Find a Contractor on Houzz" /><published>2017-11-20T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-20T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-find-a-contractor-on-houzz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-find-a-contractor-on-houzz/">&lt;p&gt;For some people, having a good set of contractors on speed dial is as important as having a good doctor, accountant, or lawyer.  If you’re fortunate enough to be one of those folks, or at least know somebody with a good contact list of contractors able and willing to tackle a variety of jobs, and most importantly do so at a high level of workmanship and service, you’re already one step ahead of the game when it comes to any construction project, big or small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people without that knowledge, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/&quot;&gt;finding a contractor can be a daunting task&lt;/a&gt;.  Recommendations are always a great place to start, but if those get exhausted, you might find yourself in a really desperate situation.  Relying on historically shady internet advertisements on websites likes Craigslist seems like a bad idea, and simply searching google for “tile contractor «enter your city here»” might put you in touch with contractors that are either savvy enough to be a high search result, yet the question would remain how good their work actually is, or even worse, connect you with contractors that are spending a lot of money to advertise online and passing a lot of those marketing costs through to their clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/11/22/Houzz Contractor Installing Norstone Stacked Stone Panels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Contractor found using Houzz reviews installing Norstone stacked stone panels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s a homeowner to do that just desperately wants to redo their  avocado green bathroom or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;replace their 1980s brick fireplace with stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; but can’t even seem to get started by finding someone to work with?  Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.houzz.com/pro/norstoneusa/norstoneusa&quot;&gt;Houzz&lt;/a&gt; – a social network that combines design and products and can be useful in bringing together clients and contractors.  We often recommend Houzz as a good starting point for our clients when they don’t know a contractor to do their installation.  Here’s a step by step process on using Houzz to find a professional contractor for your next project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/11/22/Houzz Home Screen to Find a Contractor.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Houzz Profile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Right in the middle of the main navigation banner on all Houzz pages you’ll find a link to “FIND PROFESSIONALS”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By selecting the “FIND PROFESSIONALS” button you’ll be prompted to answer a simple question “What service do you need?” and provide your zip code.  For our stone veneer panels and interlocking tile products we tell our clients to enter “tile setter” to yield the best search results.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read the contractors overview and look at the services they provide to make sure the type of work you have planned is something they have experience doing.  We tell our clients that have selected our stacked stone veneer panels to look for someone that has worked with “stone” or “natural stone” before to ensure they have experience working on the types of products they’ll be installing for you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look at the number of overall reviews and the quality of each review.  The more quality reviews the better. Be leery of any contractor with a 5 star review, but not much detail in the reviews themselves – they might have just asked their family and friends to rate them on Houzz to build up their ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Each Houzz Professional can also post pictures and describe projects they have completed in the “Projects” tab of their profile.  This is a great chance to visually see the quality of their work but also the level of projects they have worked on in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Check for industry certifications in the pro’s profile that would indicate they are knowledgeable in certain fields.  A good certification to look for with a tile setter is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;Tile Council of North America’s (TCNA) Certified Installer certification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look for Houzz badges on the pro’s profile, like “Best of Houzz  Service 2017”, which indicates they’ve received enough positive reviews in their area of expertise to be deemed “best of” by the good folks at Houzz.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Understand if the professional you are reviewing is a contractor specializing in the specific area of expertise that you are in need of, for example “tile setting”, or if the result is more appropriately identified as a general contractor who has experience in a variety of different construction phases and needs, but might not be an expert in the field you are looking for.  Depending on the scope of your project, you might just need an expert, or a more general style contractor could work as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once you’ve found some professionals that you are interested in speaking with, take down their phone #s and give them a call to get the process started, or you can even send a preliminary message right through Houzz by selecting the “Contact Me” button on each Professional’s profile.  Use your own method (notebook,spreadsheet, etc) to keep track of who you’ve called, talked to, and are waiting for a callback from, and set a date out in the future to review what you’ve learned speaking/ interviewing each contractor, compare estimates, and hopefully select the contractor for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/11/22/Houzz Logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Houzz Logo Large&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Houzz is a great tool to increase your chance of finding a quality pro for your next project.  The social aspect of this network is designed to weed out inexperienced or bad contractors by the review system, so if you do end up finding and hiring a pro through Houzz be sure to help strengthen the community be leaving a detailed and honest review.  There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/hiring-a-contractor-for-your-next-stone-project/&quot;&gt;lots of different ways to find a good contracto&lt;/a&gt;r, and some of the best are fairly elusive, not needing to even have a houzz profile because their work speaks for itself and they stay busy by word of mouth alone, but in the absence of that “unicorn” contractor that just doesn’t seem to exist for your project, check out Houzz as a good resouce for finding your next pro.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Houzz is one of our favorite tools to get design inspiration and find cool and unique products, but it's also a great resource to find contractors for your next stone or tile installation. Let's take a look at how to find a great contractor on this increasingly popular social network.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/11/22/Houzz%20Home%20Screen%20to%20Find%20a%20Contractor.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Houzz%20Home%20Screen%20for%20Finding%20Contractors%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Houzz%20Home%20Screen%20with%20FIND%20PROFESSIONALS%20button%20on%20main%20navigation%20banner%22%7D" /></entry></feed>