<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-03T20:22:41-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Amazing Stone for an Amazing View in Cyprus</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stone-with-view-cyprus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazing Stone for an Amazing View in Cyprus" /><published>2018-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-stone-for-an-amazing-view-in-cyprus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stone-with-view-cyprus/">&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; can sometimes get lost when compared to the other colors in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Rock Panel Series&lt;/a&gt;.  The monochromatic tones of the Charcoal and White are ideal for modern inspired design, and the color friendly Ochre is a best seller for its versatility.  However those of us that have spent a long time with our products tend to agree that the Ivory ends up being most people’s favorite color.  The smooth blending of the light color tones gives this product an understated elegance that is hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it was no surprise when our distributor in the UK wanted to use the Ivory Rock Panels on a vacation home in the Mediterranean island of Cyprus.  With the product installed in two main areas, let’s take a look at this project and the amazing use of the Ivory stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Outdoor Courtyard Cyprus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels used in an outdoor courtyard of a vacation home in Cyprus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set on a rocky hillside, this home had to be somewhat built into the side of the hill, creating the need for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-retaining-walls-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor retaining wall&lt;/a&gt; like structures on the high side of the lot.  This first wall forms a side courtyard like space off the main living area.  The stone is set at waist height and above to maximize effect when viewed from the inside and have a nice contrasting feel with the smooth white stucco so popular in this region of the world.  Locally sourced polished limestone outdoor pavers, set together tightly like tile, are a nice complement color wise to the gold and yellow tones in the Ivory, and their honed finish is perfect for the modern aesthetic of this space.  Both up and down lighting add to the ambiance of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;stone centered outdoor space&lt;/a&gt; when the sun goes down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels See Thru Backsplash Cyprus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kitchen backsplash with large windows instead of a backsplash looking out onto the courtyard's stone feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same outdoor courtyard wall also becomes the focal point of the large eat in kitchen.  The unique design of the kitchen utilizes large glass windows that serve as a defacto backsplash.  We love this look and are surprised we don’t see it more often.  Glass is just as easy to clean as tile from a practical purpose, and this backsplash allows for great natural light in the space and a dual use of the outdoor stone wall, which can now also be enjoyed from the interior.  The mellow tones of the Ivory work perfectly here, not dominating the space and creating an open and inviting feel in the space, ideal for a vacation home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Outdoor Patio Feature Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Stacked stone with a view of the Mediterranean Sea in Cyprus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second space the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; were used was in a super unique patio privacy wall at the rear of the property.  The view of this space is the sort of thing office dwellers dream about from their cubicles, but for practical purposes, there was a lot of utility equipment that needed placed in this area.  To not sully the view, this unique privacy wall was designed to hide the utility equipment, match and contribute to the modern architecture of the home, and still look great.  We especially like how the ivory and cream tones of the rock panels blend into the natural color range of the surrounding landscape.  With the beautiful blue waters of the Mediterranean Sea in the distance, we can’t think of a better color stone for this installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking this quick tour around this magnificent home in Cyprus with us.  We hope it gives you a better appreciation for our Ivory Rock Panels which are an awesome product and color scheme to design with or around.  Reach out to one of our customer service reps for samples of our Ivory stone, which is currently available in both the Standard and XL Series Rock Panels, and see how beautiful this product is in person.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This vacation home on the Mediterranean island of Cyprus has got not only some life changing views but some amazing stone work worth appreciating as well. Allow us to introduce this special project we had the privilege to supply stone to in this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone%20Ivory%20Rock%20Panels%20Outdoor%20Patio%20Feature%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ivory%20Rock%20Panels%20with%20an%20amazing%20ocean%20view%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ivory%20Rock%20Panels%20that%20were%20used%20on%20an%20architectural%20design%20wall%20in%20Cyprus%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Natural Stone Panels for Siding Applications</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-siding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Natural Stone Panels for Siding Applications" /><published>2018-04-25T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-panels-for-siding-applications</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-siding/">&lt;p&gt;Siding is a common term for the exterior envelope of a building, most often a house, and historically has most often been associated with wood, metal, and most recently cement board.  All of these products generally came in long sections that were easy to install using mechanical fasteners.  Stone has also been a natural choice for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exterior siding&lt;/a&gt; of a building, offering up a far more durable and lower maintenance product than wood or metal, but was often looked over by a higher initial cost ad more complex installation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Charcoal Norstone Stone Siding in Hamptons.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used as stone siding on a residential exterior in the Hamptons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of thin stone veneer panels, stone siding for houses is becoming a much more reasonable alternative.  Panel systems are much lighter weight than traditional stone masonry, making the installation process simpler, and because the product is a panel system, the labor involved can be far less skilled than the stone masons of yesteryear, resulting in faster more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;cost effective installations&lt;/a&gt;.  Let’s take a look at what makes stone siding a great choice for your next siding project and some things to consider when tackling a stone siding project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Norstone Ochre XL Residential Stone Siding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Large Format XL Series Rock Panel used as stone siding on a modern home in the UK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest benefits to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;stone siding&lt;/a&gt; project are going to be the durability and lifetime cost of ownership of the material as compared to others.  If installed correctly, stone siding should last a minimum of 25 years, and in all reality most installations will last the lifetime of the structure.  While other forms of siding are no doubt going to be less expensive both to purchase and have installed, the lifetime ownership costs of these other products should be considered.  Depending on the environmental factors and ongoing maintenance schedule, wood, metal, and other types of siding can also last 20 years plus, but the big difference will be the time and costs associated with maintaining it.  Almost any type of siding besides stone is going to need to be painted in the range of every 5-10 years, not to mention routinely cleaned.  With quality exterior paint costing upwards of $50 per gallon, the costs add up quickly when factoring in labor and the number of repeat times a wood, metal, or cement siding product needs touched during the lifetime of the structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Stone Siding Modern Home Niagra Falls.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used as a primary stone siding feature on a large modern designed home in Niagra Falls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the benefits of using a stone siding product are clear to you, probably the most important thing for a long lasting installation is ensuring that the product is installed right the first time.  This is especially true if the stone siding is replacing another product on the exterior envelope because more than likely the way the old material was installed will be different than how stone siding should be installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Mid Century Modern Stone Siding Project Miami-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Stacked Stone Veneer used as stone siding on a mid century modern home in South Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One critical difference in a stone siding application and a more traditional lap siding application is the management of moisture within the wall system.  Depending on what type of technique is being used to install the stone, such as dry stack vs pointed mortar, the manufacturer might recommend a variety of different air / water barrier systems to ensure that any water that does get behind the stone siding is effectively managed and moves away from the wall system.  For a dry stack installation of stone siding like would be done with any of our stone veneer panel products, we recommend a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;waterproofing membrane&lt;/a&gt; be applied over the substrate that the stone siding is applied to.  This membrane waterproofs that substrate making sure that the wall behind it stays dry and issue free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for learning more about why stone siding is a great choice for exterior wall applications.  Check our our exteriors gallery for more photos and ideas about how Norstone natural stone wall products can be used in siding applications and contact us today with any questions, sample requests, and to talk more about your next stone siding project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Stacked stone panels are a great product to use for exterior siding applications, especially as part of a renovation project, which is the focus of this week's New Dimensions in Natural Stone blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/26/Mid%20Century%20Modern%20Stone%20Siding%20Project%20Miami.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Siding%20on%20Residential%20Exterior%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20thin%20stone%20rock%20panels%20used%20as%20stone%20siding%20on%20the%20exterior%20of%20a%20mid%20century%20modern%20home%20in%20South%20Florida%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer on a Mixed Use Project in Portland</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-3d-stone-veneer-mixed-use-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer on a Mixed Use Project in Portland" /><published>2018-04-24T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-stone-veneer-on-a-mixed-use-project-in-portland</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-3d-stone-veneer-mixed-use-development/">&lt;p&gt;Mixed use projects are all the rage in development right now, attracting buyers and tenants from all demographics to live in condos and apartments that are typically above commercial space on the first floor of new construction buildings.  When we first started working with the architect and design team on this project in Portland, Oregon, we were excited to introduce them to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent Series 3D Stone Panels&lt;/a&gt;, which are a smooth faced stone veneer panel product.  The color, finish and style were perfect for the new age commercial look they were going for, complete with lots of stainless steel accents and big glass windows.  Let’s take a quick look at some of the details and see what makes this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth faced modern stone panel&lt;/a&gt; a perfect fit for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Aksent 3D Commercial Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer used on a commercial facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hallmarks of mixed use development is the height of the first floor as compared to the floors above it, similar to the look of most hotels.  The extended height of the first floor allows for some great looking and functional interior commercial spaces, but can also pose a design challenge.  The design team here used height as a variable in the design, covering a majority of the major facade with the 3D stone panels from floor to ceiling and then used the columns spaced along the perimeter as an opportunity to introduce a wainscoat height to the stone application.  While subtle, this unique use of varying heights to the stone installation adds a nice accent to the columns on the facade of the building that would otherwise be absorbed color wise into the walls behind them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Aksent 3D with Metal Accents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer with metal mailbox, downspout and corner accents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something else we really love about any of our products that use our Grey Basalt Stone is how well this color pairs with stainless and brushed steel.  This project is ripe with metal features from mailboxes, emergency water supplies and down spouts that are expertly set into the tile installation melding the cool grey tones of the stone with the metal accents.  One interesting thing about this project is the use of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/designing-norstone-series-edge-options/&quot;&gt;metal corner treatment&lt;/a&gt; on the outside corners.  We do make some amazing looking finger jointed outside corner units for the Aksent series, and while we’re not sure if the corners were done this way for ease of installation, or to coalesce with the other modern metal design elements of this facade installation, but we really like the way it looks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Stone Panel Commercial Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer used on a commercial facade with glass door entryway&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great reason to use natural stone in a mixed use space is the durability of the product, particularly in a commercial setting.  Whether its shoppers or residents going in and out, or just general foot traffic along the sidewalk, natural stone is a great option for commercial projects that want a durable surface that is going to be super easy to maintain.  Something can also be said for the grey color of this Basalt 3D stone panel, which does an excellent job hiding the everyday dirt and debris that comes with any outdoor urban installation.  The honed surface texture of this panel also lends itself to easy cleaning when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Aksent 3D Commercial Facade Portland, OR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wide Angle of Mixed Use Development Building featuring Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer on the ground floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt this is a nice looking building where the developer went the extra mile to have a clean modern design and use high end finishes to attract top dollar leases both in the commercial and residential spaces of this building.  The Grey Akent 3D Panel proves itself to be a versatile product that can enhance projects both big and small.  To learn more about this product, and our other Lynia Interlocking Tiles and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Veneers&lt;/a&gt; that use this same stone, contact us today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The design team on this mixed use development project in Portland was looking for a durable yet natural surface, and hit a homerun with our Grey Aksent 3D panel which was used extensively on the primary level. Let's take a look at this project in greater detail and how this stone product is a perfect fit for the job.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash%20Grey%20Aksent%203D%20Commercial%20Multi%20Use%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Aksent%20Grey%203D%20Smooth%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20commercial%20facade%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Panoramic%20shot%20of%20a%20commercial%20mixed%20use%20building%20that%20used%20Norstone%20Aksent%20Grey%203D%20Panels%20on%20the%20first%20floor%20facade.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">PLANC – A New Dimension for Norstone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PLANC – A New Dimension for Norstone " /><published>2018-04-11T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-11T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-a-new-dimension-for-norstone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we as product developers at Norstone have focused on over the last couple years is trying to bring products to market that are super unique in terms of look and feel, trending in terms of color, and at price points that make them practical for all sorts of applications.  With the roll out of our latest product, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;PLANC Large Format Wall Tiles&lt;/a&gt; happening during Spring of 2018, we feel like we checked all those boxes and are super excited to share this great product with our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLANC is a large format loose strip veneer.  The product comes as a set of three strips, each measuring 31.5” long and either 5.5”, 3.1”, or 2.4” in height.  The strips are about .8” thick and the product weighs in at around 12.5 lbs per square foot.  We currently are producing PLANC in five unique colors including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/grey-basalt/&quot;&gt;Grey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/ebony-basalt/&quot;&gt;Ebony&lt;/a&gt; Basalt colors that many of our customers are already familiar with from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Panels&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia IL Tiles&lt;/a&gt;.  New to the color mix are a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/silver-quartz/&quot;&gt;Silver Grey Quartz&lt;/a&gt; and the color we are most excited about, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/platinum/&quot;&gt;Platinum&lt;/a&gt;, which is a beautiful lavastone complete with natural veining and surface texture that you can only find in natural stone.  The final color in our mix, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/graphite/&quot;&gt;Graphite&lt;/a&gt;, is a honed version of the Platinum, offering a slightly darker appearance along with a smoother texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Norstone Planc All 5 Color Sets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Sets in all 5 colors stacked behind each other in a staggered format&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes PLANC so unique and different is the large format of this product.  At 31.5” long there’s very little to compare this product against in terms of size when it comes to wall tiles, and especially natural stone wall tiles.  The large format is ideal for architecturally sized projects, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exteriors&lt;/a&gt;, but the scale isn’t lost on smaller projects as seen in the backsplash application done in the home of one of our longtime employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Norstone Planc Platinum Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern White Kitchen with a Planc Platinum backsplash in Orlando&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLANC is also an incredibly versatile product in terms of how the installer chooses to pattern it on the wall.  We anticipate that most of the time the product will be used in a staggered pattern with the three strips stacked on top of each other and staggered, but to the more inspired among us, the 3.1” and 2.4” strips can meet right up with the 5.5” tall strip opening up  myriad of both symmetrical and asymmetrical patterns on the wall.  We’ve laid out some cool patterns with PLANC on the ground at our warehouse and can’t wait to see how our customers use this product in unique and interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Custom Lavastone PLANC Platinum Exterior Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Custom Lavastone Blend on an exterior urban garden wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price wise, Platinum and Graphite PLANC will be some of the lowest cost products Norstone has ever brought to the market.  With a recommended retail price point on these two products in the mid $11 / square foot range, with substantial discounts typically being available for quantity and wholesale opportunities.  The relatively lower source cost of Lavastone as compared to other stones like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/quartz-ledgestone-vs-countertop/&quot;&gt;Quartz&lt;/a&gt; and Basalt allow us the opportunity to price these two colors at points making them attractive for both large scale architecturally specified products as well as residential projects of all sizes and scopes.  All PLANC colors can be used in both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/interiors/&quot;&gt;interior&lt;/a&gt; and exterior applications, however we are currently recommending Platinum, Graphite, and Silver Grey not be used in exterior freeze / thaw climates.  These stones are currently undergoing independent lab testing to ensure their stability in those areas and we hope to be able to make a recommendation soon on using them in freeze / thaw regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Norstone Planc Platinum Kitchen Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Planc Platinum used on a backsplash of a small modern kitchen with cabinets and white marble counter tops&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samples of all five colors of PLANC are available by calling our office or submitting your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact details&lt;/a&gt; through our website and we have an increasing amount of inventory of the PLANC product available for immediate sales and delivery to your project.  Reach out to our team today to learn more about this unique large format natural stone tile product and see how it might be a great fit for your next stone wall tile project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our new PLANC series has gotten us more excited than any other product we've ever launched. Check out this week's article introducing the product and diiving into what it makes it so unique!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/12/Custom%20Lavastone%20PLANC%20Platinum%20Exterior%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Strip%20Wall%20Tiles%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Planc%20in%20a%20custom%20platinum%20blend%20used%20on%20the%20exterior%20walls%20of%20an%20urban%20outdoor%20space.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen for Spring</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen for Spring" /><published>2018-04-02T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen-for-spring</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/">&lt;p&gt;An outdoor kitchen is a great addition to any home, even in northern climates where the winter season can limit year round use.  Recent data suggests that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor kitchens and living spaces&lt;/a&gt; can net anywhere between a 70 to 200% return on investment (ROI) depending on the location and materials used, with the higher ROIs seen in the areas of the country where the space can be used year round.  Stacked stone has been a popular choice for outdoor kitchens ever since they became popular in the late 90s and early 2000s, primarily used on the vertical surfaces of the cabinets, backsplashes, and vent hoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s project is a great example of a larger outdoor kitchen, complete with a large grill, small refrigerator, and plenty of counter space to meal prep and entertain with.  Let’s take a closer look at this project and explain why it stands out to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/04/Outdoor Kitchen with Norstone Ochre XL Stone Veneer.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Stacked Stone Veneer used on a large outdoor kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things we see about this project that we really liked is the way this product used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL stone veneer panels&lt;/a&gt; as a true accent color of the space.  With the stone patio, furniture cushions and counter top all having a very neutral color range, the nice rust color accents of the stone veneer really pop and catch the eye, while the brown and grey base tones of the Ochre color work nicely with the grey colors of the house and fence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of color, the stainless steel used on the grill, the refrigerator, and the cabinets not only is a great material for ease of use and long term durability, but also pairs well with the stone veneer.  Our Rock Panels have a very clean line look to their design with consistent horizontal and vertical lines that lends itself to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;modern inspired stone aesthetic&lt;/a&gt; which pairs well with a material like stainless steel.  Stainless also offers top notch durability for outdoor kitchen components ensuring you spend your weekends enjoying the space and not maintaining it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/04/Grill Island with Norstone Ochre XL Stone Veneer.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL used on an outdoor grill island with stainless steel grill and refrigerator&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the really cool features of this outdoor kitchen is the counter top itself.  The natural edge of this concrete counter top matches up nicely with the split face of the stone.  A more traditional edge profile such as a bull nose or eased edge wouldn’t look nearly as good as this natural edge does in the space.  We also really like the relatively large thickness of this counter top, which fits in just perfectly with an outdoor space where things are always just a little big bigger and gives a nice bold look to the outdoor kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing that catches our eye on the stone veneer part of this outdoor kitchen is the nice use of our finger jointed outside corner units.  We take a lot of pride in our corner units being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;best looking corner units on the market&lt;/a&gt;.  Instead of a more simple dovetail configuration which other stone veneer manufacturers employ, our finger joint corner systems pairs approximately 6 to 7 fingers for every 6 inches of vertical corner making for the most realistic corner configuration on the market.  Every piece of stone that faces out on these corner units is the natural cleft adding to the believability of the corner condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re looking for an outdoor kitchen complete with grill, fridge, and prep sink, or even if your space dictates that a grilling island is all that can fit, stacked stone is a great option for a classic look that will last a lifetime if built correctly.  With summer right around the corner, contact us today for samples or a quote on stone that will make your outdoor kitchen the envy of this year’s memorial day party!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">With Summer grilling season right around the corner we wanted to showcase a great outdoor kitchen project that used our Ochre XL Rock Panels on the base and cabinets of this awesome space. If an outdoor kitchen or grill island is in your summer 2018 plans check out this project for some great inspiration!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/04/Grill%20Island%20with%20Norstone%20Ochre%20XL%20Stone%20Veneer.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Stacked%20Stone%20on%20Outdoor%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ochre%20XL%20Stacked%20Stone%20Rock%20Panels%20on%20an%20outdoor%20kitchen%20with%20a%20stainless%20steel%20grill%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Norstone Slim Line Rock Panel Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-slim-line-budget-stone-veneer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Norstone Slim Line Rock Panel Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/introducing-norstone-slim-line-rock-panel-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-slim-line-budget-stone-veneer/">&lt;p&gt;While Norstone has spent the past 15 years making &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer products &lt;/a&gt;of exceptional quality and durability for the high end of the market, we’ve always wanted to broaden that scope and deliver a price point stone veneer product that can make a run at competing with the veneer panels found at the big box home improvement stores and discount flooring centers.  Enter our new Slim Line Series, which is still packed with features, and every bit deserving of the Norstone name, but with a lower entry level price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Ochre Slim Line Outside Corner Low Cost Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Slim Line Outside Corner Unit shown on a column in the Ochre color&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difference between Slim Line Rock Panels and our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; is the thickness of each panel, with the Slim Line Panels checking in between 5/8” and 1 1/4” thick, compared with the Standard Series which ranges from 3/4” to 1 ¾”.  The panel sizes are the same, with each field unit clocking in at 6” tall x 24” wide and each corner unit consisting of a short side that is appx 8” long and a long side appx 16” long, that come together in an interlocking fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Slim Line Field Units Ochre Charcoal-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Slim Line Collage showing Ochre and Charcoal Field Units&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a practical standpoint, the thinner panels weigh less and can be packed 5 panels, or 5 square feet, per box .  This also means we can fit more square footage onto each crate we ship, allowing us to deliver more material for a lower cost to our customers.  From a visual standpoint, the smaller range of thicknesses creates a slightly less dimensional look on the wall as compared to our Standard and XL Panels, however Norstone Slim Line Panels still have more depth variation and thus create a more complex and visually interesting look on the wall and than the ultra cheap stone veneer panel products available at the big box home improvement centers and discount flooring centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Slim Line Charcoal Feature Wall Detail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Feature Wall of Norstone Slim Line Charcoal Color&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes Norstone Slim Line panels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;unique from other budget stone veneer panels&lt;/a&gt; is not just the Norstone name, but the areas of our production process that we refuse to cut in the name of creating a price point product.  Currently available in our ever popular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal&lt;/a&gt; colors, the stone we use for SlimLine is the exact same stone we use in our Standard and XL Panels.  We also use the same high grade two part epoxy to join the individual stones together in making the panels to ensure a much stronger bond as compared to poly based glues commonly seen on budget stone veneer panels.  Lastly, we have the best in house team of Norstone production managers, stone pickers, saw men, assemblers and packers that bring to the table a decade and half of knowledge making quality stone veneer products and bring that knowledge and expertise to the production line every day no matter what product is being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone Ochre Slim Line Budget Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Residential project that used Norstone Slim Line in Ochre surrounding entryway&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim Line was originally developed for large commercial projects that demanded the merits of a natural stone product but had the financial constraints often associated with large projects.  Starting Spring 2018, Norstone USA will be stocking Slim Line in both Ochre and Charcoal Colors at both our East Coast and West Coast Distribution Centers and selling to all customers for jobs of all sizes.  With prices in the range of a 25% discount from our Standard Series Rock Panels, Slim Line might be a good fit for your next project, or speed up and make the project you’ve been thinking about doing a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;Contact the Norstone Team&lt;/a&gt; today to learn more about Slim Line, request samples, get a quote and see how this product might be a great fit for your project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">If you've always loved Norstone's Standard Series Rock Panels, but the price hasn't worked for your project, we're happy to introduce our new Slim Line Series Rock Panels, a thinner and lower cost product that we're debuting this Spring.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/28/Norstone%20Slim%20Line%20Field%20Units%20Ochre%20Charcoal.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Slim%20Line%20Rock%20Panel%20Series%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Slim%20Line%20Rock%20Panel%20Field%20Units%20in%20Ochre%20and%20Charcoal%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grey Lynia Tiles Make this Pool Cool!</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-lynia-tile-pool/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Lynia Tiles Make this Pool Cool!" /><published>2018-03-25T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-25T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-lynia-tiles-make-this-pool-cool</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-lynia-tile-pool/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we really like about our natural stone tile products is that you can use almost all of them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/pools/&quot;&gt;pool environments&lt;/a&gt;.  Pools are typically a really harsh environment for any type of material.  Having to deal with moisture, lots of sunlight, and chemicals really narrows down the type of materials you can use and especially so in the natural stone world.  A lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Norstone products are perfect for pools&lt;/a&gt; because we make them from quartz or quartz based stones, or in the case of this project, Basalt, which are much more durable stones than cheaper slates and sandstones which won’t stand up to the rigors of a pool environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really like the look of this pool project in Texas that one of our customers finished last year.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/basalt/&quot;&gt;Lynia IL Tile in Ash Grey&lt;/a&gt; was used as part of a raised beam feature flanking the entire back side of the pool.  There’s some great design hidden in plain sight with this project, so let’s take a closer look at what stands out to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/26/Grey Lynia Stone Tile in Pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tile Ash Grey Basalt color used in pool raised beam feature wall in Texas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things we notice about this pool is the modern angular layout.  While curves are still popular in pool design, clean line pools like this one are increasingly popular as well.  From a product pairing standpoint, the clean lined staggered format of the Lynia natural stone tiles is a complimentary to this design scheme and definitely adds to the modern vibe this pool exudes through the smooth finishes and sheer descent waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another really unique thing about the Lynia Interlocking is that it is relatively large for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-mesh-backed-tile/&quot;&gt;mesh mounted tile product&lt;/a&gt;.  Each strip in the Lynia Tiles is 12” long and is going to range between about 1” to 2.4” tall.  The medium format nature of this product is a nice compliment to the much smaller format of the square glass tile used on the waterline, spa spillover and large water feature.  If too small a tile was used in place of the Lynia, the overall look would start to get really busy, but as it stands the two prominent tile finishes of the pool work quite nicely with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/26/Grey Interlocking Natural Stone Tile in Pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Mesh Mounted Tile used in swimming pool raised beam feature wall in Texas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that grey is a currently a very popular color in the design world right now, and this pool and patio area is no exception.  The darker tones of the Ash Grey Lynia Tile used here match up nicely with the furniture and trim color of the patio, while also serving as a nice contrast against the lighter grey of the smooth faced stucco retention wall that is the primary backdrop of this backyard.  The movement of color within the Lynia tile, which is pronounced in these photos as they show some of the tile being wet and other parts being dry, is another nice contrast against the uniformity of the stucco wall behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have always been big fans of combining grey and blue tones in design, which has been done here with the stone tiles, the glass tile and the color of the pool surface itself.  Most grey tones have a lot of blue undertone, so when paired together the two colors tend to look great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With summer right around the corner we hope this article inspires some great design ideas for upcoming pool projects using natural stone.  Using the right types of natural stone tiles and veneers in the right applications is the key for a great pool project.  Call one of our knowledgeable design reps for a free consult on using Norstone Natural Stone Veneers and Tiles on your next pool project today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">It's hard not to like this pool that was completed last year which used our Lynia Interlocking Tiles in grey as part of an extensive raised beam feature. Let's take a look at what makes a product like the Lynia IL tiles a great fit for this type of project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/26/Grey%20Interlocking%20Natural%20Stone%20Tile%20in%20Pool.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Natural%20Stone%20Tile%20on%20Pool%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocling%20Natural%20Stone%20Tile%20in%20Ash%20Grey%20Basalt%20used%20on%20a%20pool%20raised%20beam%20feature%20wall%20in%20Texas%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mechanical Fastening vs Direct Adhesion for Stacked Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mechanical-fastening-stacked-stone-veneer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mechanical Fastening vs Direct Adhesion for Stacked Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-03-11T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mechanical-fastening-vs-direct-adhesion-for-stacked-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mechanical-fastening-stacked-stone-veneer/">&lt;p&gt;Most large format stone veneers, such as the granite and limestone slabs that you see on the facades of many commercial buildings, are installed using a clip system to mechanically fasten or anchor the stone to the substrate.  In the mid 2000s when Norstone was getting started bringing our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; to the US market, we were often asked if our panels needed to be installed with mechanical fasteners as well.  The quick answer to that question is no – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;thin stone veneer is made specifically to be installed like a tile using thinse&lt;/a&gt;t, directly adhered to the substrate, which is commonly referred to as direct adhesion.  Both mechanical fastening and direct adhesion can be used to install stacked stone, so let’s learn a little more about each method and what types of installations they are best suited for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mechanical fastening of stone facade work is mainly born out of necessity.  As architects and designers sought out larger format stone products to use, the building industry needed to find a way to safely secure these products to the outside of buildings.  Capable of weighing far in excess of 15 lbs a square foot, and often much heavier than that, a mechanical solution was needed.  The varieties and styles of stone clips and mechanical fasteners is far ranging, but they all work on the same basic concept that they get attached to the stone itself and then also are attached back to the substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/13/Mechanical Fastening of Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Format Limestone Veneer nstalled using stone clips&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pros and cons of mechanical fastening for stone veneer are pretty straightforward.  This installation method allows for larger format pieces to be used yet still installed safely and effectively.  The disadvantages are that the installation process itself can be time consuming and require a lot of precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct adhesion, which is how we recommend all of our Norstone Natural Stone Products be installed, has a few key components – the substrate, the setting material, and the stone.  The substrate is probably the most important as it needs to be made a of a material that can effectively bond with the setting material, and also represents the outer layer of the wall system which should be engineered to meet the weight requirements of the new material being adhered to the wall.  Setting materials should be selected based on the product being installed and the substrate being used.  In most cases, stacked stone veneer like our Rock Panels or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Stone Panels&lt;/a&gt; should be installed over a cementious substrate, like CMU, cement board, or a lathe + scratch coat using a polymer modified tile thinset designed to support the heavier weight load of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;large format tiles&lt;/a&gt; or stacked stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/13/Installed Stacked Stone using Direct Adhesion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Panels installed using tile thinset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages and disadvantages of direct adhesion for stacked stone veneer is that stone and tile is installed relatively easily in a thinset setting bed and doesn’t require the exacting precision needed for mechanical fastening.  The main disadvantage of direct adhesion is that the building industry sets maximum unit sizes, weight per sq ft limits, and height restrictions for directly adhered veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re asking yourself if mechanically fixed or directly adhesion is the best option for your project, the answer is almost always going to be direct adhesion is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;best installation practice for stacked stone veneer&lt;/a&gt;.  Provided the products are less than 36” in any one dimension, less than 15 lbs per sq ft, and not to be installed more than 15’ above the finished floor, direct adhesion will provide you with a faster and easier install.  If the specifics of your project exceed any of the limits notated above, work with the construction and engineering team on your project to determine what the best combination of installation techniques will be best for your project.  Most stacked stone panel products are made with these upper limits in mind and are therefore suitable to be installed using a direct adhesion method.  Traditional loose veneer, that a mason artfully stacks by hand on site can sometimes require mechanical fasteners depending on the relative thickness and weight of the stone being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/13/Large Format Stone Tile Installed Using Direct Adhesion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Format Lavastone Tiles installed using thinset in a direct adhesion method&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Norstone we enjoy the more technical aspects of our industry and design our products with them in mind, to create beautiful products while still maximize installation output.  Never hesitate to contact us about any of our products or to ask a question and learn more about their recommended installation techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">A lot of stone facades, particularly large format, are installed using a variety of clip systems for a mechanical bond with the substrates. If you've ever wondered if this type of mechanical fastening can be used for a stacked stone panel installation, this article is for you!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/13/Mechanical%20Fastening%20of%20Stone%20Veneer.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Mechanical%20Fastening%20of%20Stone%20Veneer%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Large%20limestone%20veneer%20slabs%20directly%20attached%20to%20a%20concrete%20substrate%20using%20mechanical%20fasteners%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Natural Stone Veneer at a New High End Assisted Living Facility</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-accent-walls-assisted-living/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Natural Stone Veneer at a New High End Assisted Living Facility" /><published>2018-03-04T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-veneer-at-a-new-high-end-assisted-living-facility</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-accent-walls-assisted-living/">&lt;p&gt;Assisted living facilities are one of the fastest growing industries in the country, and might likely see explosive growth over the next decade plus as the baby boom segment of the population becomes more and more likely to engage these services.  The health care segment has always embraced natural stone in their design, and we’ve had the opportunity to have our natural stone veneers placed on dozens of doctors offices, hospitals, and clinics throughout the country.  This particular project slipped under our radar until we saw pictures of the finished installations and wow, were we impressed when they came across our desk.  Let’s take a quick tour and see how our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; are a great addition to the space for the residents and caregivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Stacked Stone Veneer Floor to Ceiling Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Rock Panels used on a floor to ceiling fireplace with long linear gas fireplace insert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main community room is the breathing heart of a facility like this one, and the magnificent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-fireplaces-2017/&quot;&gt;floor to ceiling stone fireplace&lt;/a&gt; with its modern linear gas fireplace is the main attraction in this space.  The incredible durability of natural stone means this wall surface will be maintenance free for years to come, and the sensible brown / grey blend of the Ochre Rock Panels works great with the neutral pallete the design teams of these facilities must work between.  While the fireplace is slightly more form than function in terms of heat output, the visual it creates in the space is exceptional and again will be very easy for the staff to maintain without the hassle of a more cumbersome fuel source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Stacked Stone Feature Wall in Hair Salon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Natural Stacked Stone Panels used on the feature wall in a small hair salon with two chairs and two large mirrors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An onsite hair salon is a really unique feature of this facility that comes with an exceptional look.  The big feature wall of Ochre stone veneer adds a high end spa like feeling to the space and is infinitely nicer to look at while getting a trim or color than painted drywall.  The big floor mounted leaning mirrors, colorful chairs and minimalist design is plucked right from any high end big city hair salon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Commercial Buffet Station with Stone Veneer Backdrop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone panels used behind a commercial buffet station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next area the rock panel are featured on is as an accent wall over a serving station in the breakfast area.  This stone wall serves as almost a pseudo backsplash, offering up a much more durable wall covering option than painted drywall.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Sealing the stone for a backsplash&lt;/a&gt; application is a good idea as it will allow for any stains that find their way onto the face of the stone to be easily wiped off.  The neutral color pallet of the Ochre Blend stone works in nicely with the light colored wood cabinets and furniture of the space and the cream colored solid surface countertop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/06/Ochre Blend Feature Wall in Treatment Room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Veneer Panels on a feature wall in a spa like treatment room at an assisted living facility&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the last areas the stone was used on is a series of treatment rooms where the residents can receive a variety of services, from massages to physical therapy / rehab, to hydrotherapy.  Just even having facilities like this in house is a major selling point for an assisted living facility, however this facility takes it to the next level with high end finishes.  The main wall is a beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt;floor to ceiling stacked stone feature wall&lt;/a&gt; of our rock panels in Ochre Blend, while other design features like vessel sinks, flat euro-styled cabinetry, and luxe bath towels make this space feel a lot more like a spa than your typical medical treatment room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With projects like this under our belt, we look forward to continue to provide the health care industry with new and exciting wall veneer options that serve the dual purpose of meeting the unique needs of the industry while still looking amazing.  Whether its health care, hospitality, retail, office, or high end residential, our team of design experts is here to help plan your next project – call us today to get started!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Assisted Living Facilities aren't in general one of our favorite places, but this one that just opened recently in New Jersey might help us change our mind. With many of the same amenities as a spa mixed with a country club, like a sweet stone veneer feature wall and fireplace that used our Ochre Rock Panels, getting old is starting to look more appealing!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/06/Ochre%20Blend%20Feature%20Wall%20in%20Treatment%20Room.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Accent%20Wall%20Assisted%20Living%20Facility%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Accent%20Wall%20in%20the%20treatment%20room%20of%20a%20new%20assisted%20living%20facility%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Install Stacked Stone in a Shower</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stacked-stone-shower/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install Stacked Stone in a Shower" /><published>2018-02-27T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-27T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-in-a-shower</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stacked-stone-shower/">&lt;p&gt;Open up any architectural or design magazine or tour a new construction model home and one of the trends you’ll notice is master bathrooms getting bigger and bigger.  With the middle to high end homebuyer seeking out both spacious tubs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/showers/&quot;&gt;showers fitted out with spa like finishes&lt;/a&gt;, the master bath, and in particular the shower stall, is an area we find our stacked stone veneer products showing up in more and more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Stone Veneer Accent Wall in Modern Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charcoal Rock Panels used on an accent wall in a large walk in doorless shower&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the early adopters of this trend, there were some fairly basic questions that needed answered about how stacked stone could be used in a shower.  After all, our stacked stone panels are created and installed on a dry stack concept, where the stone is neatly cut and but up against the surrounding stones, but in no way does that form a watertight seal to keep moisture out.  And since we’re working with natural stone to begin with, which tends to be very porous, the big question people had was how do we prevent water from getting behind the stone and into the wall cavity, possibly destabilizing the installation and causing moisture problems in surrounding rooms, and even creating health problems related to mold and mildew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution to the problem is a multi pronged approach starting with substrate preparation, using the right bedding and setting materials, and then simple ongoing maintenance steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real key to the moisture problem a stacked stone wall in a shower presents is using the correct substrate.  Cement board, or similar anti microbial tiling board designed for vertical tile installations is the perfect starting point to cover the framing.  The next, and possibly most important step in the entire installation is the application of a waterproofing membrane.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Waterproofing membranes are important for many tile installations&lt;/a&gt; and can be either sheet membranes or fluid applied membranes that roll on like thick paint.  This layer serves a vital step of ensuring that water that does pass through the stone does not get past the membrane and into the wall cavity where it can cause problems.  The membrane should overlap the shower pan to allow gravity to take its course and manage the flow of moisture away from the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Norstone Ochre Rock Panels in a Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone on a shower wall with a pebble floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stacked stone veneer should be applied to the prepared substrate using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;polymer modified thinset&lt;/a&gt;, and since moisture is a concern in shower installations, an anti-microbial thinset is recommended.  Anti-microbial thinsets are designed by setting material manufacturers to help prevent the growth of mold and mildew and as part of a whole installation system are effective at doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Charcoal Stone Veneer Walk In Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Walk In Shower with a Frameless Glass Enclosure and Stacked Stone used on the walls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the stacked stone is successfully installed, a quality &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;natural stone sealer &lt;/a&gt;should be applied to the wall prior to putting the shower to use.  One thing important to understand with sealers is that a sealer doesn’t form a waterproof layer or barrier of protection.  The main function of the sealer is to treat the stone and make it harder for any staining, or in the case of a shower, mold or mildew to form on the surface of the stone.  Natural stacked stone veneer should be periodically resealed according to the timeline provided by the seal manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final, and often overlooked ongoing maintenance tip for a stacked stone shower wall is to always run the exhaust vent in the bathroom during and after a shower.  The exhaust vent is an effective tool at evacuating the steamy/ moisture rich air created during a shower.  By removing this warm and moist air from the space you greatly inhibit mold and mildew growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/03/01/Walk in Shower with Vertical Stacked Stone Accents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Shower with vertical stacked stone accent strips set in porcelain tile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stacked stone shower walls are a statement piece in any master bathroom, but one of the things we tell all of our clients that are considering this type of application is that they should understand that this is not a maintenance free installation.  From remembering to run the exhaust fan, to regular cleanings, to periodic re-sealings, the maintenance of a stacked stone shower wall isn’t terribly hard or time consuming, but definitely necessary to keep an installation looking great.  Thanks for taking the time to learn more about using stacked stone veneer in a shower application.  Contact any of our in house design experts to discuss how stacked stone, or any of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone wall tile products&lt;/a&gt; can be a good fit for you next shower project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">As the trend of turning master bathrooms into mini spa like retreats continues, we're seeing more and more customers thinking about using stacked stone products in their showers. So how does a product with loads of texture and small tinygaps between each stone work in a wet environment? Learn all about how to use stacked stone in a shower in this week's blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/01/Walk%20in%20Shower%20with%20Vertical%20Stacked%20Stone%20Accents.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Used%20in%20a%20Shower%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ochre%20Rock%20Panels%20used%20in%20a%20shower%20application%22%7D" /></entry></feed>