<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-07T23:00:54-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Installing Norstone Stone Veneer with a Vertical Orientation</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing Norstone Stone Veneer with a Vertical Orientation " /><published>2018-06-04T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-stone-veneer-with-a-vertical-orientation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Traditional stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; has what we refer to as a horizontal orientation, meaning the longest dimension of any piece of stone is going to be set parallel to the ground.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Rock Panel system&lt;/a&gt; took that traditional concept one step further in that the panels themselves were designed to be 6” tall and 24” long, with all the stones that made up each of the panels also adhering to the same philosophy with the longest dimension coming along the 24” axis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we soon found out was that when you put great products in the hands of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-spec-build/&quot;&gt;amazing architects and designers&lt;/a&gt; you’ll learn things about the product that you might had never considered before, such as changing the orientation of our product from horizontal to vertical.  Specifically, that meant installing our Rock Panels with the 6” dimension running horizontally and the 24” dimension running vertically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone White Stacked Stone Rock Panels Vertical Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels installed vertically on commercial signage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first times we saw our stacked stone rock panels get used in a vertical orientation was in the photo above which is at the entrance to a law office in Charlotte, NC.  We were just getting started and had only been selling the product in the United States for less than a year and it really blew our minds that a product that we thought we knew so well could end up looking so different by simply rotating it 90 degrees during the installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond just wanting to subtly change the look of an installation by opting for a vertical orientation, there are also a handful of technical or design related reasons to adopt a vertical orientation for a specific installation.  These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vertically Oriented Rock Panels can be used on a tighter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/&quot;&gt;concave radius wall&lt;/a&gt; than a traditional horizontal orientation.  For radius work, the primary variables to consider is the measurement of the radius itself, or simply how curved the wall is, and the horizontal dimension of the wall covering that is meant to go around the radius.  By switching to a vertical orientation the 6” dimension of our panel products becomes the horizontal dimension and can easily be wrapped into tight concave radius walls like the circular stair landing shown here.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone White Stacked Stone Rock Panels Vertical Radius Wall Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels installed on a tight concave radius wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From a design standpoint, a vertical orientation of a stacked stone product provides much the	same effect as vertical stripes in accentuating the height of a space.  So if you have a space with low ceilings, like a basement man cave, vertically orienting stacked stone rock panels will help that space feel taller.  On the opposite end of the spectrum, running rock panels vertically can serve to draw attention to an already high ceiling, making it truly the focal point of a space by drawing eyes upward.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone Aksent Honed Veneer Panels Installed Vertically on Exterior.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Panels installed vertically on the exterior of a bank designed to accentuate the height of the design feature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main drawbacks to consider with a vertically oriented installation of stacked stone is how outside corners will work.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;corner units&lt;/a&gt; are designed to work along the 24” axis of the panels, so if the orientation is changed they will no longer line up against a vertical outside corner.  If a project does require corners the best option is probably a pre-fabricated corner unit designed for tile or perhaps even a simple but join as seen in the photo below.  Miter cuts could be made along the 24” axis, but would likely require a production level wet saw to make such a specialized cut along such a long dimension and it will also be difficult to keep some of the smaller stones together during the miter cut process, likely requiring some hand setting of small final pieces along a miter cut corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone Aksent Honed Veneer Panels Vertical Orientation on Columns.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Askent 3D Panels installed on short columns using a simple but join corner in lieu of a miter or pre fabricated corner unit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vertical orientation doesn’t make sense for every stacked stone veneer project, but its definitely worth considering if you have the right space, corners won’t be an issue, and the design aesthetic leans more towards modern.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Sometimes a simple change, like installing our Rock Panels with a vertical orientation can yield a big change in the overall look of a product. In this week's blog post we discuss more about this installation scheme and why it might make sense for your next project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/06/Norstone%20Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Rock%20Panels%20Vertical%20Curved%20Wall.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Rock%20Panels%20Installed%20on%20a%20Vertical%20Orientation%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ochre%20Blend%20Rock%20Panels%20installed%20on%20a%20vertical%20orientation%20on%20an%20exterior%20convex%20radius%20wall%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jaw Dropping Views of More than Just Norstone in the Seychelle Islands</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-views-seychelle-islands-africa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jaw Dropping Views of More than Just Norstone in the Seychelle Islands" /><published>2018-06-03T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/jaw-dropping-views-of-more-than-just-norstone-in-the-seychelle-islands</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-views-seychelle-islands-africa/">&lt;p&gt;When we first heard about our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;stacked stone rock panels&lt;/a&gt; being used for a project in the Seychelle Islands the first thing we had to do was go and look up where that even was.  It was then we first learned about this little known group of islands that sits off the Eastern Coast of Africa, north of Madagascar and a little over 900 miles off the coast of mainland Africa.  In a part of the Indian Ocean that is perhaps most synonymous with modern day piracy, the Seychelle Islands have a unique beauty unto themselves and are a place that we wouldn’t mine being marooned at for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes the Seychelle Islands incredibly unique, and in turn brought about the use of our Charcoal Stacked Stone Panel on this project, is that most of the islands in the Seychelles are actually made of granite.  This is incredibly unique and unlike most other tropical islands which tend to either be based on coral, such as the Maldives, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/&quot;&gt;basaltic lava stone&lt;/a&gt; like Hawaii and Fiji.  Turns out the Seychelles were actually part of an ancient super continent and have been separated from the rest of the continents for about 75 million years!  However it’s explained, we find it pretty remarkable that you’ll find similar granite formations in this tropical paradise as you will in the rolling hills of Wisconsin or the famous domes of Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/05/Norstone Charcoal Stacked Stone Rock Panels with Granite Domes in Background Seychelle Islands Africa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used on a resort in the Seychelle Islands in Africa with Granite Domes in the background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design team on this project was incredibly focused on blending the architecture of the buildings into the granite outcroppings, and were especially keen on using a color palette that blended with the granite formations.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; product was chosen for its dark gray tones that blend in so nicely with the granite domes that rise above the tropical fauna and are magnificent in their own right.  The darker color scheme of the stone also works incredibly well with the rich browns from the tropical hardwood beams and flooring throughout the project and is a nice accent against the lush greenscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/05/Norstone Charcoal Stacked Stone Rock Panels Seychelle Islands Africa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stunning view of a Norstone Stacked Stone Feature Wall with a unique circular cut out in the Seychelle Islands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture and view we have a hard time taking our eyes off of is this incredible balcony.  The Charcoal Rock Panels create great texture on the wall and the clean lines of our Standard Series Rock Panel works well in this modern inspired architecture, but the real award goes to the design team’s idea to put a circular cut out in this wall.  The view through the cut out frames beautiful granite formations, a smaller island off in the distance, and ocean so blue that you think you’re dreaming.  And even with absolutely breathtaking views in all directions, the uniqueness of this architectural feature undoubtedly draws everyone’s eye and frames the very essence of what makes this place special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while it doesn’t showcase any of our stacked stone panels, the view from this balcony is precisely what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;infinity edge pools&lt;/a&gt; were made for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/06/05/Infinity Edge Pool Seychelle Islands Africa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Infinity Edge Pool Under Construction with an incredible view in the Seychelle Islands Africa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re day dreaming with us from the confines of your cubicle or on the way to install your next stone veneer project, thanks for taking a quick mind vacation with us to the coast of Africa and seeing what makes the Seychelle Islands so special, and how the design team did a magnificent job capturing all of those things in one view of a stacked stone feature wall.  Even if you don’t have a view like this, or granite formations in your backyard, we’d love to talk with you about any of our ledge stone and smooth faced stone veneer panels and tiles.  Call today or fill out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; for more information and to request a sample or quote.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This project in the Seychelle Islands off the Eastern Coast of Africa has always been a favorite of ours. We get to see our products in a lot of truly extraordinary places all over the world, but none are as stunningly gorgeous as this one. Come take a closer look at this beautiful project and location in this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/06/05/Norstone%20Charcoal%20Stacked%20Stone%20Rock%20Panels%20Seychelle%20Islands%20Africa.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Rock%20Panel%20Feature%20Wall%20Seychelle%20Islands%20Africa%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Rock%20Panels%20on%20a%20Feature%20Wall%20in%20the%20Seychelles%20with%20a%20circular%20cut%20out%20showing%20granite%20formations%20and%20another%20Island%20in%20the%20distance%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Volcanoes are bad, but Lava Stone Rocks!</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Volcanoes are bad, but Lava Stone Rocks!" /><published>2018-05-21T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/volcanoes-are-bad-but-lava-stone-rocks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lava-stone-rocks/">&lt;p&gt;The eruption of the Kilauea volcano on the big island of Hawaii has been front page news for several days, with captivating photos of streams of lava snaking across the countryside.  Our hearts go out to the great people of Hawaii, some of whom have had their lives turned upside down.  Seeing all the lava flow on tv reminds us of the Lava Stone that we make some of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;Planc Series large format tiles&lt;/a&gt; with, so we wanted to take a look this week at what exactly Lava Stone is and isn’t, and why it makes a great building material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/22/Kilauea Lava Flow May 2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arial View of the Lava Flowing from the Kilauea volcano in Hawaii in May 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first started considering using Lava Stone to make our natural stone tile and veneer products, one of the first questions we wanted to get answered was what makes Lava Stone different than Basalt?  Having worked with Basalt for almost a decade, starting with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt;, and more recently in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Stone Veneer&lt;/a&gt; Series, we knew that Basalt was by definition a volcanic rock in the grey to black color range.  After some research and talking to the team at our quarry we learned that Lava Stone and Basalt are actually very similar.  The main difference is that Basalt is formed when lava cools at a fast rate, or sometimes even cools under pressure, making it a very hard and dense stone.  The Lava Stone that we are sourcing and using in our products is nearly the same stone from a mineralogical make up, but the lava cooled slowly and not under pressure, forming the very veining and light honeycombing that can be seen in this stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/22/Norstone Planc Large Format Lava Stone with Honed Finish.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lava Stone Planc with a honed finish in graphite color shown from a side view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The veining and other “surface characteristics” is one of the things we really like about Lava Stone and is something that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ceramic-wall-tile-%E2%80%93-color-variation-natural-stone-vs-manmade-tile-products-norstone-classroom-s/&quot;&gt;sets natural stone apart from man made stone and tile&lt;/a&gt;.  Since we’re a company that focuses only on natural stone materials, the unique way that this stone looks is super appealing and something that can only ever be imitated, but never duplicated by man made tile production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we’ve enjoyed the most about working with Lava Stone on a few of our first installations is how with a little bit of foresight, an installer can really take advantage of the veining and other surface characteristics to create continuity from piece to piece.  As seen in the photo below, we were able to position and match up some of the veining on the two bottom rows to the left of the kitchen faucet to create an eye catching, and totally unexpected look in a tile product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/22/Norstone Lava Stone Tile Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lava Stone Planc in Platinum color used on a modern kitchen backsplash with cabinets and a marble countertop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardness and durability of Lava Stone is something else that makes it very special.  This is especially true with our Planc large format tile, which is 31.5” long and can be as narrow as 2.4”, all at just over 3/4” thick.  A relative toothpick in natural stone fabrication terms, it takes a strong stone to hold up along these dimensions for transport, cutting, and installation, a task that Lava Stone has proven to be up for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently working with Lava Stone on a couple different products in our line up.  Our Platinum color in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc Series&lt;/a&gt; is a saw cut Lava Stone and the Graphite color in that same series is the same stone but with a honed face.  While the markings and veining tend to steal the show with the Platinum product, the smooth honed finish of the Graphite is a texture that will have people wanting to reach out and touch.  We are also currently prototyping using these same two stones to add them to our existing Aksent 3D panel line in the future.  Keep checking back with our blog to see what other products we can dream up using Lava Stone and contact us today to learn more about how a Lava Stone product might be a good fit for your next natural stone project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The photos and videos of the eruptions and lava flows from the Kilauea volcano in Hawaii are incredible to look at and a good reminder of the power of mother earth. Did you know Norstone has crafted a select line of natural stone products from Lava Stone that we launched earlier this year? Let's take a look this week at Lava Stone and what makes these new products so unique to use for natural stone tile.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/05/22/Kilauea%20Lava%20Flow%20May%202018.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Lava%20Stone%20from%20Lava%20Flow%20in%20Hawaii%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Lava%20Flow%20from%20Kilauea%20volcano%20in%20Hawaii%20May%202018%20that%20will%20eventually%20become%20Lava%20Stone%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Lynia Interlocking Tiles for Outdoor Corporate Space</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Interlocking-Tiles-Outdoor-Office-Space/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Lynia Interlocking Tiles for Outdoor Corporate Space" /><published>2018-05-14T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-lynia-interlocking-tiles-for-outdoor-corporate-space</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/Interlocking-Tiles-Outdoor-Office-Space/">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago we worked with an architect designing the new headquarters of a medium sized energy company in Nebraska.  One of the finishes Norstone got to be a part of was a cool outdoor space tucked away in the back of the building where our Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tiles in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/ebony/&quot;&gt;Ebony&lt;/a&gt; were used on a long landscaping wall used to define the perimeter of the space.  This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;interlocking natural tile system&lt;/a&gt; is really cool and its used really well in this project.  Let’s take a look at a few of the things we think make this project special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural Stone Interlocking Tile Landscaping Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tile on a Landscaping wall in a corporate outdoor break space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first thing that catches our eye about this project is the color pallete and commercial focused design of the building.  If you’ve been to any large office park you’ve probably seen a lot of the same color pallete of grey, brown, and white tones along with what most people will conclude as “forgettable” architecture.  The design team on this project did a great job using some interesting color and subtle yet effective design to make this building look like more than just a grey box with windows.  A variety of surfaces were used as well as muted pops of color, such as the reddish grey main panels of the building and the dark black of the Ebony interlocking natural stone tile, to help break up the commercial “office space” feel of the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural Stone Interlocking Tile Patio Seating Area.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tile on a garden wall in the seating area of a corporate ourdoor space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking specifically at the wall where the Ebony interlocking tiles were installed, one of the things we really appreciate is the design of the wall, with its straight runs, right angles, and varied heights, which matches the design style of the tile product.  Each Lynia tile consists of 9 strips of tile, staggered and mounted to a mesh backer, which creates a very linear, geometric, modern inspired look.  A product like our Lynia Interlocking natural stone tiles wouldn’t look nearly as good on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/&quot;&gt;serpentine or curved stone wall&lt;/a&gt;.  Detail like this is the hallmark of good design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How corners are addressed is a common question in almost any stone and tile installation, and we really like how the installer opted for a pre-manufactured corner trim on this project.  These trim pieces eliminate the need to miter cut the corner on site and provide a consistent, safe, and durable look to the corner.  While corner units are important to create the illusion of full bed stone veneer like our Rock Panel line, with a tile product the corner trim pieces are a good option with both a classy look and easy installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural Stone Interlocking Tile Commercial Outdoor Space.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ebony Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tile on a landscape wall at a commercial office building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the last things we take away from this project is the use of stone in particular on this landscaping wall and how appropriate a building material that is for a commercial space like this where durability and a long life span with minimal maintenance is something all products are measured against.  A natural stone product like our Ebony Lynia tiles are going to require minimal maintenance in a situation like this, and are going to stand up to elements for decades.  Being in Nebraska, imagine the open grassy area behind this building with a couple feet of snow on it after a big winter storm and know that underneath that snow bank is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/freeze-thaw-and-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;freeze thaw stable stone&lt;/a&gt; that is going to be ready to go once the sun comes out and melts it all away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural stone interlocking tiles are a great product that can impart subtle design cues on a project all in an easy to install, durable and long lasting package.  Norstone’s Lynia Natural Stone Interlocking Tiles come in four unique colors, and we invite you to check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/basalt-il-tiles/interiors/&quot;&gt;interiors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/basalt-il-tiles/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exteriors&lt;/a&gt; galleries for inspiration on your next project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Everybody needs to get away from their cubicle every now and then, but not everyone has a great outdoor space like this at their office! Let's check out how our Lynia Interlocking Natural Stone Tiles were used on the landscaping walls of this week's featured project!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/05/15/Natural%20Stone%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Landscaping%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Interlocking%20Tile%20on%20Exterior%20Landscape%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Ebony%20Lynia%20Natural%20Stone%20Interlocking%20Wall%20Tiles%20used%20on%20an%20exterior%20landscaping%20wall%20at%20an%20office%20building%20in%20Nebraska%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Install Signage on a Stacked Stone Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-signage-on-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install Signage on a Stacked Stone Wall" /><published>2018-05-07T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-07T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-signage-on-a-stacked-stone-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-signage-on-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Over the years, we’ve been fortunate enough to see our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Norstone Stacked Stone Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; products used on many commercial applications ranging from the professional offices of lawyers, doctors and accountants, to hospitality settings such as hotels, casinos, restaurants, and bars, as well as retail locations like malls and grocery stores.  One of the things that is very important to any commercial project is the signage, after all, it doesn’t matter how great the building or the stacked on it looks, if a client or customer can’t find your company you’re moving backwards.  Our stone products are often used in conjunction with the signage because their unique color and texture can be used to create a nice accent area, making it an ideal backdrop for a company’s signage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One question we get a lot with signage is what’s the best way to to install it over stacked stone.  A product like our&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/&quot;&gt; Standard Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; can have up to 1” in depth variation, making it impossible to get something like commercial signage to lay flat.  The best solution we’ve found to installing signage on a stacked stone wall is using specific hardware called “stand offs”.  A “stand off” is a couple pieces of hardware that work together to position the signage out in front of the face of the stone, while still keeping the signage flat and level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/08/Diagram of Stand Off Hardware for Stacked Stone.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram showing how signage can be installed over stacked stone using stand off hardware&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attached diagram illustrates how “stand offs” work in a very basic format.  Most often, a stand off comes with a couple different parts.  The barrel is a cylinder shaped object which gets screwed into the wall, or stone in our example.  Typically, a headless threaded screw will screw into the barrel and then nuts and / or caps are threaded onto the screw and connect and hold the signage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/08/Signage Installed Using Stand Offs In Stacked Stone-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Commercial signage in a medical office that is installed in front of a wall of Ochre XL Stone using stand off mounting hardware&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo from a physician’s office shows the barrels that were sunk into a wall of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL Series stone veneer panels&lt;/a&gt;.  A masonry bit is the best tool to use to drill these holes into the stone, and then the barrels are typically cut down to the right elevation so that when the signage is installed it remains flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/08/Signage Installed Using Stand Offs On Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stainless Steel signage installed with stand off mounting hardware on a wall of Norstone White Quartz Stacked Stone Rock Panels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project photo is from the entrance way to a law firm in Charlotte, NC.  As we can see here, the signage can be both individual letters as well as larger format shapes and designs using stand offs to keep the signage out in front of the stone.  Stainless steel is a very common product used in signage, and looks great in this application against our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;Standard Series White Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most commercial applications, a qualified sign installer is going to be the right person to be planning, manufacturing and installing the signage and appropriate hardware, especially over a more challenging vertical surface like stacked stone.  It’s critically important that the holes for the signage are in both the right location on the wall, as well as the “stand off” hardware is drilled and positioned at the right elevation so that the end result is signage that is level, spaced correctly, and looks great.  Stand off hardware is also versatile enough that it can be used to hang art, shelves, and a variety of other things on a stacked stone wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to hang anything on a stacked stone wall, call any of our friendly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;stone experts&lt;/a&gt; and we can offer our advice and if its outside your area of expertise, help get you in touch with the right professional in your area to do the job.  Contact us today to learn more!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Stacked stone is a great look for a commercial application, and one thing every commercial space needs is great signage. If you've ever wondered what the best way is to handle signage on a variable thickness product like stacked stone, this week's blog is for you!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/05/08/Signage%20Installed%20Using%20Stand%20Offs%20In%20Stacked%20Stone.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22How%20to%20Install%20Signage%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Walls%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Commercial%20signage%20installed%20on%20a%20stacked%20stone%20wall%20using%20stand%20offs%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazing Stone for an Amazing View in Cyprus</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stone-with-view-cyprus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazing Stone for an Amazing View in Cyprus" /><published>2018-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-stone-for-an-amazing-view-in-cyprus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stone-with-view-cyprus/">&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; can sometimes get lost when compared to the other colors in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Rock Panel Series&lt;/a&gt;.  The monochromatic tones of the Charcoal and White are ideal for modern inspired design, and the color friendly Ochre is a best seller for its versatility.  However those of us that have spent a long time with our products tend to agree that the Ivory ends up being most people’s favorite color.  The smooth blending of the light color tones gives this product an understated elegance that is hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it was no surprise when our distributor in the UK wanted to use the Ivory Rock Panels on a vacation home in the Mediterranean island of Cyprus.  With the product installed in two main areas, let’s take a look at this project and the amazing use of the Ivory stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Outdoor Courtyard Cyprus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels used in an outdoor courtyard of a vacation home in Cyprus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set on a rocky hillside, this home had to be somewhat built into the side of the hill, creating the need for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-retaining-walls-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor retaining wall&lt;/a&gt; like structures on the high side of the lot.  This first wall forms a side courtyard like space off the main living area.  The stone is set at waist height and above to maximize effect when viewed from the inside and have a nice contrasting feel with the smooth white stucco so popular in this region of the world.  Locally sourced polished limestone outdoor pavers, set together tightly like tile, are a nice complement color wise to the gold and yellow tones in the Ivory, and their honed finish is perfect for the modern aesthetic of this space.  Both up and down lighting add to the ambiance of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;stone centered outdoor space&lt;/a&gt; when the sun goes down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels See Thru Backsplash Cyprus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kitchen backsplash with large windows instead of a backsplash looking out onto the courtyard's stone feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same outdoor courtyard wall also becomes the focal point of the large eat in kitchen.  The unique design of the kitchen utilizes large glass windows that serve as a defacto backsplash.  We love this look and are surprised we don’t see it more often.  Glass is just as easy to clean as tile from a practical purpose, and this backsplash allows for great natural light in the space and a dual use of the outdoor stone wall, which can now also be enjoyed from the interior.  The mellow tones of the Ivory work perfectly here, not dominating the space and creating an open and inviting feel in the space, ideal for a vacation home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone Ivory Rock Panels Outdoor Patio Feature Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Stacked stone with a view of the Mediterranean Sea in Cyprus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second space the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; were used was in a super unique patio privacy wall at the rear of the property.  The view of this space is the sort of thing office dwellers dream about from their cubicles, but for practical purposes, there was a lot of utility equipment that needed placed in this area.  To not sully the view, this unique privacy wall was designed to hide the utility equipment, match and contribute to the modern architecture of the home, and still look great.  We especially like how the ivory and cream tones of the rock panels blend into the natural color range of the surrounding landscape.  With the beautiful blue waters of the Mediterranean Sea in the distance, we can’t think of a better color stone for this installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking this quick tour around this magnificent home in Cyprus with us.  We hope it gives you a better appreciation for our Ivory Rock Panels which are an awesome product and color scheme to design with or around.  Reach out to one of our customer service reps for samples of our Ivory stone, which is currently available in both the Standard and XL Series Rock Panels, and see how beautiful this product is in person.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This vacation home on the Mediterranean island of Cyprus has got not only some life changing views but some amazing stone work worth appreciating as well. Allow us to introduce this special project we had the privilege to supply stone to in this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/05/04/Norstone%20Ivory%20Rock%20Panels%20Outdoor%20Patio%20Feature%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ivory%20Rock%20Panels%20with%20an%20amazing%20ocean%20view%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ivory%20Rock%20Panels%20that%20were%20used%20on%20an%20architectural%20design%20wall%20in%20Cyprus%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Natural Stone Panels for Siding Applications</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-siding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Natural Stone Panels for Siding Applications" /><published>2018-04-25T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-panels-for-siding-applications</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-siding/">&lt;p&gt;Siding is a common term for the exterior envelope of a building, most often a house, and historically has most often been associated with wood, metal, and most recently cement board.  All of these products generally came in long sections that were easy to install using mechanical fasteners.  Stone has also been a natural choice for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exterior siding&lt;/a&gt; of a building, offering up a far more durable and lower maintenance product than wood or metal, but was often looked over by a higher initial cost ad more complex installation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Charcoal Norstone Stone Siding in Hamptons.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used as stone siding on a residential exterior in the Hamptons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of thin stone veneer panels, stone siding for houses is becoming a much more reasonable alternative.  Panel systems are much lighter weight than traditional stone masonry, making the installation process simpler, and because the product is a panel system, the labor involved can be far less skilled than the stone masons of yesteryear, resulting in faster more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;cost effective installations&lt;/a&gt;.  Let’s take a look at what makes stone siding a great choice for your next siding project and some things to consider when tackling a stone siding project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Norstone Ochre XL Residential Stone Siding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Large Format XL Series Rock Panel used as stone siding on a modern home in the UK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest benefits to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;stone siding&lt;/a&gt; project are going to be the durability and lifetime cost of ownership of the material as compared to others.  If installed correctly, stone siding should last a minimum of 25 years, and in all reality most installations will last the lifetime of the structure.  While other forms of siding are no doubt going to be less expensive both to purchase and have installed, the lifetime ownership costs of these other products should be considered.  Depending on the environmental factors and ongoing maintenance schedule, wood, metal, and other types of siding can also last 20 years plus, but the big difference will be the time and costs associated with maintaining it.  Almost any type of siding besides stone is going to need to be painted in the range of every 5-10 years, not to mention routinely cleaned.  With quality exterior paint costing upwards of $50 per gallon, the costs add up quickly when factoring in labor and the number of repeat times a wood, metal, or cement siding product needs touched during the lifetime of the structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Stone Siding Modern Home Niagra Falls.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels used as a primary stone siding feature on a large modern designed home in Niagra Falls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the benefits of using a stone siding product are clear to you, probably the most important thing for a long lasting installation is ensuring that the product is installed right the first time.  This is especially true if the stone siding is replacing another product on the exterior envelope because more than likely the way the old material was installed will be different than how stone siding should be installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/26/Mid Century Modern Stone Siding Project Miami-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Blend Stacked Stone Veneer used as stone siding on a mid century modern home in South Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One critical difference in a stone siding application and a more traditional lap siding application is the management of moisture within the wall system.  Depending on what type of technique is being used to install the stone, such as dry stack vs pointed mortar, the manufacturer might recommend a variety of different air / water barrier systems to ensure that any water that does get behind the stone siding is effectively managed and moves away from the wall system.  For a dry stack installation of stone siding like would be done with any of our stone veneer panel products, we recommend a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;waterproofing membrane&lt;/a&gt; be applied over the substrate that the stone siding is applied to.  This membrane waterproofs that substrate making sure that the wall behind it stays dry and issue free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for learning more about why stone siding is a great choice for exterior wall applications.  Check our our exteriors gallery for more photos and ideas about how Norstone natural stone wall products can be used in siding applications and contact us today with any questions, sample requests, and to talk more about your next stone siding project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Stacked stone panels are a great product to use for exterior siding applications, especially as part of a renovation project, which is the focus of this week's New Dimensions in Natural Stone blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/26/Mid%20Century%20Modern%20Stone%20Siding%20Project%20Miami.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Siding%20on%20Residential%20Exterior%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20thin%20stone%20rock%20panels%20used%20as%20stone%20siding%20on%20the%20exterior%20of%20a%20mid%20century%20modern%20home%20in%20South%20Florida%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer on a Mixed Use Project in Portland</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-3d-stone-veneer-mixed-use-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer on a Mixed Use Project in Portland" /><published>2018-04-24T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-stone-veneer-on-a-mixed-use-project-in-portland</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-3d-stone-veneer-mixed-use-development/">&lt;p&gt;Mixed use projects are all the rage in development right now, attracting buyers and tenants from all demographics to live in condos and apartments that are typically above commercial space on the first floor of new construction buildings.  When we first started working with the architect and design team on this project in Portland, Oregon, we were excited to introduce them to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent Series 3D Stone Panels&lt;/a&gt;, which are a smooth faced stone veneer panel product.  The color, finish and style were perfect for the new age commercial look they were going for, complete with lots of stainless steel accents and big glass windows.  Let’s take a quick look at some of the details and see what makes this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth faced modern stone panel&lt;/a&gt; a perfect fit for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Aksent 3D Commercial Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer used on a commercial facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hallmarks of mixed use development is the height of the first floor as compared to the floors above it, similar to the look of most hotels.  The extended height of the first floor allows for some great looking and functional interior commercial spaces, but can also pose a design challenge.  The design team here used height as a variable in the design, covering a majority of the major facade with the 3D stone panels from floor to ceiling and then used the columns spaced along the perimeter as an opportunity to introduce a wainscoat height to the stone application.  While subtle, this unique use of varying heights to the stone installation adds a nice accent to the columns on the facade of the building that would otherwise be absorbed color wise into the walls behind them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Aksent 3D with Metal Accents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer with metal mailbox, downspout and corner accents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something else we really love about any of our products that use our Grey Basalt Stone is how well this color pairs with stainless and brushed steel.  This project is ripe with metal features from mailboxes, emergency water supplies and down spouts that are expertly set into the tile installation melding the cool grey tones of the stone with the metal accents.  One interesting thing about this project is the use of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/designing-norstone-series-edge-options/&quot;&gt;metal corner treatment&lt;/a&gt; on the outside corners.  We do make some amazing looking finger jointed outside corner units for the Aksent series, and while we’re not sure if the corners were done this way for ease of installation, or to coalesce with the other modern metal design elements of this facade installation, but we really like the way it looks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Stone Panel Commercial Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer used on a commercial facade with glass door entryway&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great reason to use natural stone in a mixed use space is the durability of the product, particularly in a commercial setting.  Whether its shoppers or residents going in and out, or just general foot traffic along the sidewalk, natural stone is a great option for commercial projects that want a durable surface that is going to be super easy to maintain.  Something can also be said for the grey color of this Basalt 3D stone panel, which does an excellent job hiding the everyday dirt and debris that comes with any outdoor urban installation.  The honed surface texture of this panel also lends itself to easy cleaning when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash Grey Aksent 3D Commercial Facade Portland, OR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wide Angle of Mixed Use Development Building featuring Norstone Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer on the ground floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt this is a nice looking building where the developer went the extra mile to have a clean modern design and use high end finishes to attract top dollar leases both in the commercial and residential spaces of this building.  The Grey Akent 3D Panel proves itself to be a versatile product that can enhance projects both big and small.  To learn more about this product, and our other Lynia Interlocking Tiles and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Veneers&lt;/a&gt; that use this same stone, contact us today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The design team on this mixed use development project in Portland was looking for a durable yet natural surface, and hit a homerun with our Grey Aksent 3D panel which was used extensively on the primary level. Let's take a look at this project in greater detail and how this stone product is a perfect fit for the job.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/25/Ash%20Grey%20Aksent%203D%20Commercial%20Multi%20Use%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Aksent%20Grey%203D%20Smooth%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20commercial%20facade%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Panoramic%20shot%20of%20a%20commercial%20mixed%20use%20building%20that%20used%20Norstone%20Aksent%20Grey%203D%20Panels%20on%20the%20first%20floor%20facade.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">PLANC – A New Dimension for Norstone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PLANC – A New Dimension for Norstone " /><published>2018-04-11T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-11T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-a-new-dimension-for-norstone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we as product developers at Norstone have focused on over the last couple years is trying to bring products to market that are super unique in terms of look and feel, trending in terms of color, and at price points that make them practical for all sorts of applications.  With the roll out of our latest product, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;PLANC Large Format Wall Tiles&lt;/a&gt; happening during Spring of 2018, we feel like we checked all those boxes and are super excited to share this great product with our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLANC is a large format loose strip veneer.  The product comes as a set of three strips, each measuring 31.5” long and either 5.5”, 3.1”, or 2.4” in height.  The strips are about .8” thick and the product weighs in at around 12.5 lbs per square foot.  We currently are producing PLANC in five unique colors including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/grey-basalt/&quot;&gt;Grey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/ebony-basalt/&quot;&gt;Ebony&lt;/a&gt; Basalt colors that many of our customers are already familiar with from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Panels&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia IL Tiles&lt;/a&gt;.  New to the color mix are a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/silver-quartz/&quot;&gt;Silver Grey Quartz&lt;/a&gt; and the color we are most excited about, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/platinum/&quot;&gt;Platinum&lt;/a&gt;, which is a beautiful lavastone complete with natural veining and surface texture that you can only find in natural stone.  The final color in our mix, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/graphite/&quot;&gt;Graphite&lt;/a&gt;, is a honed version of the Platinum, offering a slightly darker appearance along with a smoother texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Norstone Planc All 5 Color Sets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Sets in all 5 colors stacked behind each other in a staggered format&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes PLANC so unique and different is the large format of this product.  At 31.5” long there’s very little to compare this product against in terms of size when it comes to wall tiles, and especially natural stone wall tiles.  The large format is ideal for architecturally sized projects, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exteriors&lt;/a&gt;, but the scale isn’t lost on smaller projects as seen in the backsplash application done in the home of one of our longtime employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Norstone Planc Platinum Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern White Kitchen with a Planc Platinum backsplash in Orlando&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLANC is also an incredibly versatile product in terms of how the installer chooses to pattern it on the wall.  We anticipate that most of the time the product will be used in a staggered pattern with the three strips stacked on top of each other and staggered, but to the more inspired among us, the 3.1” and 2.4” strips can meet right up with the 5.5” tall strip opening up  myriad of both symmetrical and asymmetrical patterns on the wall.  We’ve laid out some cool patterns with PLANC on the ground at our warehouse and can’t wait to see how our customers use this product in unique and interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Custom Lavastone PLANC Platinum Exterior Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Custom Lavastone Blend on an exterior urban garden wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price wise, Platinum and Graphite PLANC will be some of the lowest cost products Norstone has ever brought to the market.  With a recommended retail price point on these two products in the mid $11 / square foot range, with substantial discounts typically being available for quantity and wholesale opportunities.  The relatively lower source cost of Lavastone as compared to other stones like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/quartz-ledgestone-vs-countertop/&quot;&gt;Quartz&lt;/a&gt; and Basalt allow us the opportunity to price these two colors at points making them attractive for both large scale architecturally specified products as well as residential projects of all sizes and scopes.  All PLANC colors can be used in both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/interiors/&quot;&gt;interior&lt;/a&gt; and exterior applications, however we are currently recommending Platinum, Graphite, and Silver Grey not be used in exterior freeze / thaw climates.  These stones are currently undergoing independent lab testing to ensure their stability in those areas and we hope to be able to make a recommendation soon on using them in freeze / thaw regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/12/Norstone Planc Platinum Kitchen Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Planc Platinum used on a backsplash of a small modern kitchen with cabinets and white marble counter tops&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samples of all five colors of PLANC are available by calling our office or submitting your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact details&lt;/a&gt; through our website and we have an increasing amount of inventory of the PLANC product available for immediate sales and delivery to your project.  Reach out to our team today to learn more about this unique large format natural stone tile product and see how it might be a great fit for your next stone wall tile project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our new PLANC series has gotten us more excited than any other product we've ever launched. Check out this week's article introducing the product and diiving into what it makes it so unique!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/12/Custom%20Lavastone%20PLANC%20Platinum%20Exterior%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Strip%20Wall%20Tiles%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Planc%20in%20a%20custom%20platinum%20blend%20used%20on%20the%20exterior%20walls%20of%20an%20urban%20outdoor%20space.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen for Spring</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stacked Stone Outdoor Kitchen for Spring" /><published>2018-04-02T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen-for-spring</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/">&lt;p&gt;An outdoor kitchen is a great addition to any home, even in northern climates where the winter season can limit year round use.  Recent data suggests that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor kitchens and living spaces&lt;/a&gt; can net anywhere between a 70 to 200% return on investment (ROI) depending on the location and materials used, with the higher ROIs seen in the areas of the country where the space can be used year round.  Stacked stone has been a popular choice for outdoor kitchens ever since they became popular in the late 90s and early 2000s, primarily used on the vertical surfaces of the cabinets, backsplashes, and vent hoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s project is a great example of a larger outdoor kitchen, complete with a large grill, small refrigerator, and plenty of counter space to meal prep and entertain with.  Let’s take a closer look at this project and explain why it stands out to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/04/Outdoor Kitchen with Norstone Ochre XL Stone Veneer.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Stacked Stone Veneer used on a large outdoor kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things we see about this project that we really liked is the way this product used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL stone veneer panels&lt;/a&gt; as a true accent color of the space.  With the stone patio, furniture cushions and counter top all having a very neutral color range, the nice rust color accents of the stone veneer really pop and catch the eye, while the brown and grey base tones of the Ochre color work nicely with the grey colors of the house and fence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of color, the stainless steel used on the grill, the refrigerator, and the cabinets not only is a great material for ease of use and long term durability, but also pairs well with the stone veneer.  Our Rock Panels have a very clean line look to their design with consistent horizontal and vertical lines that lends itself to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;modern inspired stone aesthetic&lt;/a&gt; which pairs well with a material like stainless steel.  Stainless also offers top notch durability for outdoor kitchen components ensuring you spend your weekends enjoying the space and not maintaining it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/04/Grill Island with Norstone Ochre XL Stone Veneer.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL used on an outdoor grill island with stainless steel grill and refrigerator&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the really cool features of this outdoor kitchen is the counter top itself.  The natural edge of this concrete counter top matches up nicely with the split face of the stone.  A more traditional edge profile such as a bull nose or eased edge wouldn’t look nearly as good as this natural edge does in the space.  We also really like the relatively large thickness of this counter top, which fits in just perfectly with an outdoor space where things are always just a little big bigger and gives a nice bold look to the outdoor kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing that catches our eye on the stone veneer part of this outdoor kitchen is the nice use of our finger jointed outside corner units.  We take a lot of pride in our corner units being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;best looking corner units on the market&lt;/a&gt;.  Instead of a more simple dovetail configuration which other stone veneer manufacturers employ, our finger joint corner systems pairs approximately 6 to 7 fingers for every 6 inches of vertical corner making for the most realistic corner configuration on the market.  Every piece of stone that faces out on these corner units is the natural cleft adding to the believability of the corner condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re looking for an outdoor kitchen complete with grill, fridge, and prep sink, or even if your space dictates that a grilling island is all that can fit, stacked stone is a great option for a classic look that will last a lifetime if built correctly.  With summer right around the corner, contact us today for samples or a quote on stone that will make your outdoor kitchen the envy of this year’s memorial day party!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">With Summer grilling season right around the corner we wanted to showcase a great outdoor kitchen project that used our Ochre XL Rock Panels on the base and cabinets of this awesome space. If an outdoor kitchen or grill island is in your summer 2018 plans check out this project for some great inspiration!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/04/04/Grill%20Island%20with%20Norstone%20Ochre%20XL%20Stone%20Veneer.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Stacked%20Stone%20on%20Outdoor%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ochre%20XL%20Stacked%20Stone%20Rock%20Panels%20on%20an%20outdoor%20kitchen%20with%20a%20stainless%20steel%20grill%22%7D" /></entry></feed>