<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-10T10:27:49-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Stone Fireplace 101: The Hearth</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-veneer-fireplace-hearths/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stone Fireplace 101: The Hearth" /><published>2018-12-10T10:06:08-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-10T10:06:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-fireplace-101-the-hearth</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-veneer-fireplace-hearths/">&lt;p&gt;The fireplace hearth, while normally associated with a more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;classically styled fireplace&lt;/a&gt;, is really just an extension of the floor of the firebox. It started out, especially with wood burning fireplaces, as a functional and needed space, protecting the floor against sparks and embers that might fly out of the fireplace. Fireplace tools and even cooking instruments were stored and used on the hearth. In most homes built over the past half century, the majority of fireboxes are raised off the floor so you don’t have to bend down as much to tend the flame, which also raised the hearth and created a “hearth step”, where the hearth gets raised up as well and then typically extends out at least 12 inches from the face of the fireplace. A vast majority of these fireplaces, particularly with the explosion of regional and national home builders, were faced with some variety of brick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Gas Fireplace with Cantilevered Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels used on a natural stone veneer fireplace with cantilevered hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;natural stone panel systems&lt;/a&gt; and thin veneer products in the last 15 or so years, fireplaces started to get renovated at a pace never seen before. These products made it possible to cover up that old worn out brick and really change the look of an entire room. And since the new stone products were veneers, in most cases they could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-over-brick-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;applied directly to the existing brick fireplace&lt;/a&gt; resulting in a complete transformation with just a few hours of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Fireplace with Stone Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels used on a large wood burning fireplace with natural hewn stone hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another fundamental change in the fireplace industry was the increasing popularity of gas fireplace units over the last 2-3 decades. Homeowners loves these units because they don’t require wood fuel to burn and then clean up after.  From a practical design standpoint, gas fireplace units also eliminated the need for a hearth, so while many gas fireplaces still get built with a hearth, a new wave of fireplace design was also ushered in where the hearth was removed completely, creating a sleeker, and in many cases more contemporary look.  Gas fireplace units have also played a big role in changing the vertical position of where a fireplace gets installed on a wall.  Most commonly, the fireplaces were either on the floor or maybe set 12” up the wall, forming the aforementioned hearth step.  With the gas units not requiring a hearth, positioning them anywhere on the wall, especially at eye level is now possible, opening up more design possibilities within a space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Gas Fireplace with No Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent stone veneer used vertically with a modern gas fireplace with no hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When renovating or building a new fireplace with a traditional hearth step, natural stone veneer products typically are going to get used on the face of the step as well as the returns to the wall.  The outside corners that most hearth steps form are an important part of the installation, which is why having &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;great looking stone corner units&lt;/a&gt; is an important consideration when looking at products.  The horizontal top of the hearth is another area where design can really shine through.  The main requirement is that the product used must be non combustible, which makes stone and tile a popular choice.  Cut field and flag stone, slate, and marble are all popular materials that work well with our natural stone products and that we see get used for the hearth step topper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Gas Fireplace with Granite Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels used on a gase fireplace with granite hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we’ve come to appreciate after working on hundreds, maybe thousands of natural stone veneer fireplace projects over the years with our clients is that no two fireplaces are really the same.  Whether it’s the material they choose for the face, the design of fireplace on the wall, and how functional accessories like hearth steps and mantles get used, the combinations are endless, allowing you to put your own unique stamp on each project.  Our sales reps and technical services team have lots of experience with fireplaces so don’t hesitate to reach out if you are just starting to plan for a fireplace renovation or have already selected materials – we’re here to share our knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Fireplace renovations are one of the most popular uses of our natural stone veneer products. The hearth can pose some design challenges, especially in a remodel project, but also provide a signature look for the space. Let's take a deep dive into fireplace hearths and explore the possibilities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20with%20Stone%20Hearth.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20Hearth%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20with%20raised%20cut%20stone%20hearth%20with%20storage%20cubbies%20underneath%20it.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Before and After Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-aztec-xl-stone-veneer-fireplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before and After Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace" /><published>2018-11-28T13:42:09-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-28T13:42:09-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-aztec-xl-stone-veneer-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-aztec-xl-stone-veneer-fireplace/">&lt;p&gt;When we first released our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/aztec/&quot;&gt;Aztec&lt;/a&gt; color several years ago we knew it was a going to be a great product for interior applications.  Aztec is really a brightened up version of our tried and true &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre&lt;/a&gt; color, with light earth tones of brown, grey and off white, with undertones ranging from blush to orange.  Aztec, because of its high mica content, also splits with a lot of facets, giving this color, along with its close cousins Pearl and Sierra, an understated glitter effect that isn’t overwhelming but definitely adds to the appeal of the product.  Interior projects,where lighter colors help set the tone of a space and good lighting really brings to life wall coverings, is the perfect playground for this color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace - Before.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Before photo of an old brick fireplace set to be redone with Norstone Aztec XL Stone Veneer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project profile this week is a customer we worked with directly a couple years ago that had an old brick fireplace that was in need of a new look.  One of the cool parts about this old installation was the unique way the original installers created “vents” out of cut pieces of brick for the “heatilator” system, which draws cold air from the room in and pumps it back out several degrees warmer.  Needless to say the ventilation system itself was scrapped in lieu of a new insert that is more energy efficient without the need for a ventilation system.  Overall, this fireplace had good bones, just needed a face lift!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace - Masonry Skim Coat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old brick fireplace receiving a masonry skim coat to prep it for installation of Norstone Aztec XL Stone Veneer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homeowner really liked our natural stone veneer panel system because it could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-over-brick-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;installed over the existing brick substrate&lt;/a&gt; with minimal prep work, our finger-joint corner units offered up a good solution to turn the outside corners and cover the small return back to the wall on each side of the fireplace, and because our system is DIY friendly, allowing him to do the work and save the money a tile installer would charge.  The photo here shows the fireplace as a masonry skim coat is being applied to the existing bricks to fill in any gaps and provide a smooth, level and plumb substrate to start from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace - After-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace Remodel Project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finished product here is a night and day difference from the starting point.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/light-and-bright-aztec-stacked-stone-backsplash-in-orlando-fl/&quot;&gt;light and bright color of the Aztec&lt;/a&gt; works nicely with the wall color and hardwood flooring to liven up the space as compared to the drab red tones of the brick.  An updated lighting fixture that is nice and shiny not only helps drag the room out of the 90s, but also provides some great focused light on the stone.  While difficult to pick up on in a photo, that light along with the subtle sparkle / glitter effect the Aztec creates really creates a focal point for the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working components of the fireplace received a major overhaul as well, including a new insert and a nice set of new gas logs that do a much better job of drawing attention to the flame itself, whereas the old insert was more focused on the functionality of heating the room than style or design.  Luckily, with advances in fireplace and fireplace insert technology, now we can have fireplaces that are ultra efficient, and look great too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace Remodel Project with new granite hearth stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing to point out is the new hearth stone.  Previously just bricks, the hearth is now really set off with a piece of black granite that contrasts well with the color the stone and ties in nicely with the insert as well as other element of the décor.  Granite or other types of natural stone like flag stone, field stone, marble,and travertine, whether sourced in smaller tiles and set to form the hearth, or cut as one piece from larger slabs, are all excellent ideas for hearth selections.  And since the size needed is generally pretty small, checking with your local slab yard is always worth doing to see what they have in their off cut stack where really good deals on beautiful materials can be found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this before and after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplace project&lt;/a&gt; with us – we hope you agree that the stone veneer really turned this space from quite ordinary to extraordinary.  If you have a space that you’re thinking about using stone veneer to enhance, contact one of our knowledgeable staff today to learn more, order samples, and get started designing your own extraordinary space.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">A recent cold snap at Norstone's headquarters in Central Florida has got us thinking about staying warm in front of a fireplace – so we dug through our archives and found this cool before and after project featuring our Aztec XL Series Rock Panels. Stay warm and enjoy this major transformation!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone%20Aztec%20XL%20Fireplace%20-%20After.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Aztec%20XL%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20Before%20and%20After%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Before%20and%20After%20Project%20Photos%20of%20an%20old%20brick%20fireplace%20redone%20using%20Norstone%20Aztec%20XL%20Stone%20Veneer%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone’s Top 5 Dining Room Stacked Stone Feature Walls for Thanksgiving</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-dining-room-stacked-stone-feature-walls/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone's Top 5 Dining Room Stacked Stone Feature Walls for Thanksgiving" /><published>2018-11-19T20:57:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-19T20:57:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-s-top-5-dining-room-stacked-stone-feature-walls-for-thanksgiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-dining-room-stacked-stone-feature-walls/">&lt;p&gt;For many of us, Thanksgiving is the most important, often times the biggest meal of the year.  Whatever your traditions are, one thing we can all agree on is that a beautiful setting for the meal certainly enhances the entire experience.  So for this holiday season, we put together our top 5 dining room &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt;stacked stone feature walls&lt;/a&gt;.  Here they are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall Cyprus Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels visible through two large panoramic glass windows in an open concept kitchen and dining room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first space is a cool modern inspired open concept dining room / kitchen.  Prominent from any location in this big open space is the beautiful Ivory Rock Panel feature visible through the impossibly large panoramic glass windows.  Equally beautiful during the day as well as night time when this wall is lit up, this feature wall is a great focal point for the space and a beautiful backdrop for a festive meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Ochre Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels serving as a background feature wall in a small corner dining area with a spectacular sunburst syle overhead light fixture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every holiday celebration brings together friends and families near and far, and this next dining area is a great example of a how great design can work in small spaces.  This corner dining nook has an appropriately sized table for just a few, and is beautifully situated in front of a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend Stacked Stone Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; Feature wall.  Low slung benches instead of traditional backed chairs minimize the bulk of the furniture in this space, while the light fixture creates a lot of texture that is works well with the geometric three dimensionality of the stacked stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall Cyprus Outdoor Patio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels on an outdoor feature wall surrounding an open air patio with dining chairs in Cyprus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next space expands on the traditional concept of a dining room as we go“al fresco” as they say in Italy.  This outdoor dining area is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stone-with-view-cyprus/&quot;&gt;Norstone project on the island of Cyprus&lt;/a&gt; in the Mediterranean Sea, and is nestled into a rocky outcrop on the owner’s property.  The stacked stone feature wall behind the area is actually designed as a utility screen, to block various equipment and control systems needed for the home from view.  We love the Ivory Rock Panels used on this wall as they tie in perfectly with the native limestone outcroppings and have great contrast against the bright blue Mediterranean sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone White Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels on a prominent feature wall in a cozy modern inspired kitchen and dining area&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project features stacked stone perhaps the most prominently of any of our projects, with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;White Quartz Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; extending along the entire back side of this cozy living room.  The name of the game with this space is color and texture.  The White Rock Panels tie in perfectly with the color scheme of the marble counter top and white cabinetry while adding in a significant amount of texture to create some contrast against an otherwise sleek and modern inspired kitchen.  The light up “cafe” sign with its warm incandescent lighting helps to bring down the space and warm it up just the right amount to make it super appealing for any meal, holiday or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall Dallas See Through Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels on a see through fireplace on a wall in a beautiful dining room with a large wood table and multiple floor to ceiling glass windows and a bubble style light fixture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last dining room in our top 5 list is this beautifully designed space in Dallas.  There are so many small details in this space that some of them get lost!  The table itself is gigantic, with seating for 12 and a very cool natural edge that creates a real rustic vibe.  The stone is used on cool feature wall adjoining the space with a clever see through two side fireplace that adjoins an outdoor seating area.  The rest of the space is amazing with its prominent floor to ceiling windows and doors which give the space amazing natural light, and for when the sun does go down, this room has some of the coolest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;light fixtures we’ve seen paired with our stone&lt;/a&gt;.  Thanksgiving, Christmas, or any meal in between, this is a great space to break bread with family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at our top 5 dining room stacked stone feature wall projects.  If you are considering stacked stone for a feature wall in your dining room, you still have time to get it done before the new year – so call us today to get started!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">With Thanksgiving a few days away, we thought it would be fun to put together a list of our top 5 dining room stacked stone feature walls to get ready for the big day. Check this out and let the feasting begin!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone%20Stacked%20Stone%20Dining%20Room%20Feature%20Wall%20Dallas%20See%20Through%20Fireplace.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Top%205%20Dining%20Room%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Walls%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Top%205%20Dining%20Room%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Walls%20countdown%20for%20the%202018%20Holiday%20Season%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">South Florida Kitchen Remodel with Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/kitchen-remodel-grey-lynia-interlocking-tile/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="South Florida Kitchen Remodel with Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile" /><published>2018-11-19T12:07:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-19T12:07:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/south-florida-kitchen-remodel-with-grey-lynia-interlocking-tile</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/kitchen-remodel-grey-lynia-interlocking-tile/">&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about going out on the road and visiting clients is hearing and seeing about the projects that are being done with our products.  I was down in South Florida last week and one of our awesome sales reps showed me this set of photos of her customer’s kitchen remodel project that is almost completed and which used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt; in the Ash Grey color as the back splash tile.  This isn’t the biggest kitchen, but they pack a lot of great design and features in the space they have.  Let’s take a closer look at some of these details that makes this space really special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash with Vent Hood.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile used on a backsplash application with a prominent stainless steel vent hood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Color is the first thing you’ll notice about this project.  The homeowner has really committed to a white and grey color pallet with stainless steel accent pieces throughout.  In particular the white cabinets and flooring really open the space up and allow for a nice open and airy feeling within the relatively small space they had to work with.  Going with the white colored grout on the installation of the medium format mosaic back splash is a bold move and really tests the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/&quot;&gt;installers accuracy and precision&lt;/a&gt; in maintaining straight lines and even courses – the end result though is beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash Modern Kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile used as a backsplash tile for a modern white and grey themed kitchen in Miami&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing the contrasting grout color does is it sets off the design of the interlocking tile which adds to the modern feel of the space. Our Lynia Interlocking Tiles consists of 9 strips of our basalt or marble stone that is cut to size and mounted on a two part backer system for ease of installation.  The design of this product is very modern leaning, with its symmetrical patterning, and use of both sharp horizontal and vertical lines in the layout.  The unspoiled white pallet of the cabinets and counter top come together nicely with the dark grey and geometric patterning of the Lynia Interlocking Tile to create a clean modern vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash to Ceiling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile used as a backsplash tile going from counter top to ceiling in a project in South Florida.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another often overlooked but very important part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;tile back splash project&lt;/a&gt; is where to end the back splash tile vertically on the wall.  This decision is often going to be dependent on specifics of the space and configuration of upper cabinets.  We really like how the tile was taken all the way to the ceiling in this application, both above the cook top and around the vent hood, as well as around the window near the sink.  While this does require a little extra tile, the effect of stretching the installation vertically and keeping the wall look consistent with just one finish really enhances the finished look of this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile on a backsplash tile with LED under cabinet lighting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Lighting is an important element of a successful natural stone tile installation&lt;/a&gt; that should not be overlooked.  The natural lighting in this space is better than most, with a relatively large window over the sink bringing in lots of the natural stuff.  While it’s a little hard to tell in the photos because of the great natural light, the under cabinet lighting is a great feature that I think the homeowners will end up loving.  This low level lighting not only highlights and makes the stone stone tile back splash look amazing, but it is also really functional for any of those times when full on overhead lighting isn’t necessary.  One area that probably could use a lighting assist is the wall above the range hood.  Without a recessed ceiling light in this area, this corner starts to really pick up some shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick look at this cool back splash project down in South Florida with us today.  Our entire line up of natural stone products can be used on back splashes, as well as a host of other wall applications, equally suited for both modern as well as more rustic design schemes.  Contact us today to learn more about any of natural stone wall veneer products for your next project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">While meeting customers last week in South Florida I saw this great set of photos where our Lynia Interlocking Tiles in Ash Grey were used as part of a complete kitchen remodel. It turned out better than the homeowners imagined, so let's take a quick look around this project and see what it's all about.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Backsplash%20Modern%20Kitchen.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Interlocking%20Tile%20Backsplash%20in%20Modern%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Backsplash%20in%20a%20Modern%20Kitchen%20Remodel%20Project%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone’s Favorite Stacked Stone Man Caves</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-man-caves/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone's Favorite Stacked Stone Man Caves" /><published>2018-11-12T22:21:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-12T22:21:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-s-favorite-stacked-stone-man-caves</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-man-caves/">&lt;p&gt;Football season is about half way over and you’re still looking at your basement, garage, den, or spare bedroom and regretting that you haven’t started your man cave project sooner – don’t fret!  There’s still plenty of time to put together an awesome space that’ll have you relaxing and your wife or significant other wondering what she agreed to!  For those of you that appreciate great looking spaces, consider stacked stone or other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;modern natural stone wall veneers&lt;/a&gt; as an excellent choice for a feature wall in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our previous clients have worked on man cave projects in the past, and today we wanted to share with you a few of our favorites, including one or two that admittedly might have taken the “man design” a bit too far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/13/Norstone Stacked Stone Man Cave Bar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels on a bar backsplash and surrounding wall in a basement man cave&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first project was part of a complete basement remodel in the greater Philadelphia area that was done many years ago.  No man cave is complete without a bar, and this one looks like a great place to belly up to.  Our Ochre Stacked Stone Rock Panels line the short bar back splash, as well as cover the adjoining wall surrounding the back lit bottle built in shelves.  Beyond the bar, this entire basement is a really special space complete with a beautiful modern fireplace, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/&quot;&gt;wall mounted large screen tv&lt;/a&gt;, and lots of music memorabilia displayed to highlight the interests of the owner.  The one thing that really stands out about this space to us is that it’s done incredibly classy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/13/Norstone Stacked Stone Man Cave Card Room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels on a large feature wall with two fireplaces, two tvs, and a stuffed longhorn cow head in an upscale card room man cave&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project isn’t actually in anyone’s personal home, but for anyone that is drawn to the allure of table games, this would be high on their wish list.  This high roller’s private room has everything a man cave needs – big tvs, card tables with comfortable seating for you and your closest dozen friends, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-fireplaces-2017/&quot;&gt;beautiful gas fireplaces&lt;/a&gt;, and to top it off a mounted long horn cow at the figurative, and literal, center of the room.  Our Charcoal Rock Panels are done in an elegant way such that their modern linear style complement the long and thin gas fireplaces and serve as a perfect backdrop of the two large screen tvs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something not too many people know about when it comes to a stacked stone wall is that it also is a great noise reducer.  The thickness and density of natural stone obviously help with sound suppression from one room to the next, while the variable texture of a product like ledgestone does an excellent job of bouncing sounds waves in multiple directions, helping to diffuse sound within the room.  This makes stacked stone a great pick nor just for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/project/rockport/&quot;&gt;award winning concert halls&lt;/a&gt;, but for keeping the sound of a man cave in the man cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/13/Norstone Stacked Stone Man Cave Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels used on a fireplace with outside corners at a man cave hunting lodge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last project is a tongue in cheek example of what can go wrong with a man cave.  We absolutely love the stone on this project, especially the use of our outside corner units on both the hearth and main face of the fireplace.  But, the sheer number of mounted and stuffed fish and other animals in this space can be a bit overwhelming!  We also really like the large wood burning fireplace in this space – not something that you see too often anymore, but I think most would agree that having to start your own fire is certainly a manly thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick look at a couple of our favorite man cave projects featuring some of our stacked stone products.  If you’re working on your own man cave, or just want to learn more about how our stacked stone products can work on just about any wall project you are considering, drop us a line a and we’ll be glad to help!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">What's more manly, or cave like for that matter, then an awesome stacked stone wall in a man cave? In this week's blog we take a look at some man caves customers of ours have done and poke a little fun at some of the strange design choices that happen when the boys are left in charge!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/13/Norstone%20Stacked%20Stone%20Man%20Cave%20Bar.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Favorite%20Stacked%20Stone%20Man%20Caves%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Favorite%20Stacked%20Stone%20Man%20Caves%20with%20bars,%20fireplaces,%20and%20poker%20tables%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone Planc Large Format Tile on Hollywood Home</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-large-format-tile-hollywood-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone Planc Large Format Tile on Hollywood Home" /><published>2018-11-04T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-large-format-tile-hollywood-house</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-large-format-tile-hollywood-home/">&lt;p&gt;It’s really exciting to start to see project photos of the new Planc product that we released earlier this year.  We’ve seen a lot of interior projects, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplaces&lt;/a&gt; and kitchen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;backsplashes&lt;/a&gt;, but this residential project in Hollywood, CA is one of the first we’ve gotten some really good photos of that used the product on both the interior and the exterior.  The exterior looks amazing with the style, design and pattern of the product really fitting into the architectural style of the property, but the really amazing use of the product is on an interior feature wall / fireplace where the design team and installers thought outside the box as it relates to how Planc can be patterned and created a look on the wall that a lot of people will emulate in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So even though this project is still in construction, let’s get some dust on your shoes and take a look around this awesome project and get inspired to use this awesome new product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/05/Planc Large Format Tile on Exterior Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Platinum Planc Large Format Tile used as an accent on the front facade of a modern home under construction in Hollywood, CA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main street facing view of the home shows the Platinum Planc product being used as an accent around the garage and entryway.  This modern design has lots of straight lines and keys off the rectangular shapes of the prominent windows and doors, all of which beautifully into the linear format of the Planc tiles.  One thing we really love about this view is the use of the wood door, fascia, and soffitt accents.  The wood contrasts nicely color wise with the overall modern grey theme of this home, but also plays together well with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-difference-between-basalt-and-lavastone/&quot;&gt;lavastone&lt;/a&gt; of the Platinum Planc with both of them being natural products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/05/Planc Large Format Tile on Exterior Patio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Platinum Planc Large Format Tile used on the exterior of a modern home around large sliding glass doors in Hollywood, CA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same design scheme plays a prominent role in the back of the home as well.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;Glass is always an attractive choice to pair with modern stone materials&lt;/a&gt;, and the two sets of over-sized triple pane sliding glass doors push that combination to the max.  We also are really impressed with the installers attention to detail, especially with all the outside corner work done to return the tile back up tight against the windows and doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/05/Planc Large Format Tile on Interior Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Platinum Plance Large Format Tile set in a symmetrical pattern on an interior feature wall with two windows and a fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really took our breath away on this project was this interior wall, and specifically how the design and installation team chose to lay the stone in a straight vertical stack with a continuous pattern of the large, medium and small Planc tile heights.  Interestingly enough, the same pattern is used outside, but we think its a more powerful visual used on the interior walls where there aren’t as many competing visuals from the design of the exterior.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc large format tile&lt;/a&gt; is a highly calibrated product that doesn’t need grouted and generally is set in a dry stack method, but we love what the installer did here.  By setting these large format tiles with a larger than average grout joint both horizontally and vertically, the symmetrical nature of the pattern that the tiles are laid in really gets accentuated.  Since the lavastone that the Platinum Planc is made from is considered a porous stone, sealing it prior to grouting is a good idea.  The darker grout against the grey tones of the platinum color are a lot more forgiving on the preciseness of the installation, especially important on a symmetrical installation like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking about using a large format tile like Planc on a project, this is a tremendous example of what is possible.  While it definitely leans more towards the modern end of the design spectrum, the natural veining of the platinum and graphite colors, along with a more traditional brick set or completely random stagger pattern would move this product a lot more towards the realm of traditional design.  We’ve very excited about this product and hope you are too!  Give us a shout if you’ve installed Planc as we’d love to see what else has been done by our clients.  Or if you think Planc might be a good choice for a project you’re working on, our knowledgeable team is here to answer your questions and get samples headed your way!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This project isn't even done and its got us sweatin' how good the new Planc large format tile looks! If you're a fan of modern design, this project and this product should be on your next idea board! Let's take a look!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/05/Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20on%20Interior%20Feature%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20on%20Hollywood%20Home%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20on%20interior%20feature%20wall%20with%20fireplace%20in%20Hollywood,%20CA%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Is Drywall A Suitable Substrate for Stone Veneer?</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/is-drywall-good-for-stone-veneer-installations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Drywall A Suitable Substrate for Stone Veneer?" /><published>2018-10-22T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/is-drywall-a-suitable-substrate-for-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/is-drywall-good-for-stone-veneer-installations/">&lt;p&gt;Most people, the author included, that have ever swung a hammer in the name of home improvement have experienced the temptation to want to cut a corner every now and again.  Maybe it’s something as simple as working with your thinset to lay stone or tile right after you get done mixing it instead of letting it set for a few minutes, or possibly even something with a greater risk for danger, like changing out a light fixture but only turning the power off at the switch and not the breaker.  Working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt;, especially the ones that get used on a lot of renovations and remodel projects, we hear from customers frequently about cutting one corner in particular on the installation – whether or not the product can be installed over drywall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, the answer to that question is no, without any exceptions or conditions.  There are a number of suitable substrates for installing stone veneer, all of which are cementious based, such as cement board, brick, block, or a wooden substrate that has been prepared with a metal lath and masonry scratch coat.  Now that we got that out of the way, let’s take a look at why drywall isn’t a suitable substrate for stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/24/Side Profile View of Drywall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side profile view of a piece of drywall showing the paper outer layers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weight is the primary reason that drywall does not make a suitable substrate for a stone veneer installation.  Our stone veneers can weigh anywhere from about 7 to 13 lbs per square foot.  If you take a few minutes to study the composition of drywall, you’ll find a pretty basic product – essentially its gypsum between two heavy pieces of paper.  Drywall is a perfect product for interior walls and ceilings as its relatively lightweight, easy to install and work with, and can accept a variety of textures, paints, and lightweight veneer applications such as wall paper.  However, the physics don’t work when you start to think about hanging a heavy stone tile or panel that’s being bonded to the outer paper layer of the drywall with a wet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;cement based thinset setting material&lt;/a&gt;.  Not only is the paper layer not designed to hold that weight up, the moisture in the thinset is going to start off by compromising the integrity of that paper layer right from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/24/Norstone Stacked Stone Veneer Backsplash Installed over Cement Board.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels installed on cement board over existing drywall on a modern kitchen backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get the question so frequently about installing our stone veneer products over drywall because of its prevalence in the building industry and also that many of the products that our product is ideally suited for are likely going to have existing drywall already in place as the wall system.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;Back splashes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplaces&lt;/a&gt; are great examples of this.  Both are fantastic applications for stone veneer, but if the space is being remodeled, or even in the case of most new construction projects, drywall will likely be what’s currently in place because it’s inexpensive, easy, and prevalent in all other areas of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/24/Installing Cement Board over Drywall for a Stone Veneer Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cement board being installed over drywall in preparation for a stone veneer installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear not if the drywall has got your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY stone veneer project&lt;/a&gt; at a standstill!  Beyond the obvious solution of ripping out the existing drywall, getting back to the studs or furring strips, and rebuilding the wall for your stone veneer using cement board, there is another alternative.  Many of our customers end up leaving the drywall in place and simply covering it with .25” thick cement board.  The thinner cement board will have plenty of structural rigidity for most stone veneer projects seeing as though its gaining flexural strength from the existing drywall behind it.  Probably the most important part of a cover up installation like this is to make sure that you’re using screws that are long enough to go through both your cement board, existing drywall and still sink at least half way into your studs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a few minutes to learn why installing stone veneer over drywall is not a good idea.  We have a great team of knowledgeable reps with industry experience that are ready and willing to answer your stone veneer installation questions, so don’t hesitate to contact Norstone today to learn more and get your hard to answer questions answered.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We get this question a lot, and the answer every time is NO! Let's take a quick look at why installing a heavy product like stone veneer on drywall is not a good idea.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/24/Norstone%20Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20Backsplash%20Installed%20over%20Cement%20Board.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Veneer%20Backsplash%20Installed%20On%20Cement%20Board%20Over%20Drywall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Charcoal%20Stone%20Veneer%20Backsplash%20installed%20on%20cement%20board%20over%20existing%20drywall%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Before and After – A Charcoal Stacked Stone Entryway Feature Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-feature-wall-before-and-after/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before and After – A Charcoal Stacked Stone Entryway Feature Wall" /><published>2018-10-16T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-a-charcoal-stacked-stone-entryway-feature-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-feature-wall-before-and-after/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we always tell clients before starting any project is to take a “before” picture of what their space looks like so they can have a great visual reference point to compare against what the finished project yields.  The author readily admits that sometimes even I forget to do this!  In the excitement of starting a new project most of us are so focused on wanting to see actual results that its easy to dive right into tearing out a wall, or ripping up a floor and forget to take that “before” picture.  We’re lucky that a client we recently worked with shared with us some awesome “before” and “after” pictures of their stacked stone entryway feature wall project where our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Charcoal Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; were used that we’ll be diving into on this week’s project profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/18/Entry Way Wall - Before.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Entry Way Wall - Before Stacked Stone Installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a “before” standpoint, the thing we really notice about this space is that the wall this client ends up cladding in stone veneer is actually less of a traditional entryway wall – it’s almost a reverse entryway in that the stone isn’t really going to be something you see when walking through the door, but instead becomes a focal point of that space of the larger room that the entryway opens up to.  Perhaps the most prominent feature of the “before” wall is the 90 degree outside corner that undoubtedly made selecting a product with a good corner solution a priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/18/Stacked Stone Entry Way Wall - After.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Entryway feature wall project with Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels and a recessed shelf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting onto the good stuff, the “after” picture of the space reveals an amazing transformation focused around the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt; stacked stone entryway feature wall&lt;/a&gt;.  The two big things that catch our eye is the recessed shelf that was added along the short wall and the prominent outside corner that looks absolutely fantastic with our corner units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recessed shelf is a really great idea in this application because it would have been fairly easy to add during the construction process when the existing drywall was either torn out and replaced with cement board, or covered up with cement board.  Built ins always up the level of sophistication of any home, so whether this ends up getting used to display a nice art piece or even just a convenient spot to drop your keys when walking in the door, this small add makes a big difference in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Norstone we really take our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;stacked stone corner units&lt;/a&gt; seriously.  And while that level of sophistication might get lost on some people, or might not be applicable for certain projects, it’s a project like this that really allows our unique finger jointed corner design to shine through.  This corner is not just an integral part of the installation, its at an extremely prominent part of this space.  The corner is the natural focal point of the larger room this area expands out to and is something everyone will be looking at as they walk down the stairs or out the door.  The interlocking stone fingers of each corner unit create the most seamless looking corner on the stone veneer market and ensure that no matter which angle you look at the corner you’ll always see the natural cleft face of the stone and never a saw cut or finished edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/18/Charcoal Stacked Stone Entry Way Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Entryway Feature Wall using Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels with recessed overhead lighting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, this next view of the stacked stone entryway feature wall shows off some awesome lighting that was added into the ceiling to face downward over the stone.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Good lighting is important for a stacked stone installation&lt;/a&gt; and we’re glad this project took that into consideration.  The other thing that really catches our eye from this angle is the nice color blend between the brown hardwood floors and the dark grey of the Charcoal Standard Series Rock Panel.  This classic combination of not only brown and grey but also wood and stone ensures this project won’t ever look like a trend that has since passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick “before” and “after” look at this project with us.  If you have your own “before” and “after” photos of a Norstone project, please share them with us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sales@norstoneusa.com&quot;&gt;sales@norstoneusa.com&lt;/a&gt; and we’ll use them on a future article.  And if you’re looking for help on your next stacked stone veneer project &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;give us a call&lt;/a&gt; and our experts will help make your “before” the “after” you’re dreaming of!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We love the before and after of this client's entryway project where they took a space with good bones and layout and really created a focal point for the space. Let's have a closer look at the before and afters and see what makes this stacked stone veneer project a winner!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/18/Stacked%20Stone%20Entry%20Way%20Wall%20-%20After.jpeg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Entryway%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Entryway%20Feature%20Wall%20project%20using%20Norstone%20Charcoal%20Standard%20Series%20Rock%20Panels%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Installing Stone Veneer over a Metal Substrate</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-on-metal-substrate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing Stone Veneer over a Metal Substrate" /><published>2018-10-10T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-stone-veneer-over-a-metal-substrate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-on-metal-substrate/">&lt;p&gt;In just the past couple days we’ve heard from a handful of our clients and some of the installers that are working with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt; about how the product can be installed over a metal substrate.  There is actually a couple different ways to approach this type of installation, and metal actually shows up more often than you’d think as a substrate.  So let’s take a look at how stone veneer can be installed over metal substrates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the types of projects that you see metal projects on, almost all of the folks we’ve talked to recently have been working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplaces&lt;/a&gt;, which is a popular project at this time of the year as we’re all getting ready for winter and to start cranking up those fireplaces for heat very soon.  Most often the fireplace insert is going to have a metal flange, similar to a window,  that extends out along the wall that the fireplace is mounted on and that provides vertical anchoring points for the unit.  These flanges can vary in how far they extend out from barely two or three inches, to several inches.  Fireplace units with larger flanges are the ones where a different form of adhesive needs to be considered.  If the flange only sticks out an inch or two, and the overwhelming bulk of a stone veneer unit or natural stone tile is going to be adhered directly to the masonry wall substrate (block, brick, cement board, etc), then extra consideration about adhering stone to the metal substrate is probably not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/11/Fireplace Insert with Large Metal Flange.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fireplace Insert with a large metal flange to be installed and covered with stone veneer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other metal applications that we tend to see natural stone being used on are exterior applications of prefab buildings which often have exterior steel shells.  Our natural stone products have been used as a decorative top layer on prefab buildings of all kinds, including marinas, warehouse/industrial space, and even prefab railway sheds that sit along train lines in remote areas to house control and safety equipment.  More often than not, the metal building is in place for a very practical reason, especially since metal buildings can be cost effective to construct, and then the stone comes along later in an effort to spruce up the overall look of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another very common application is prefabricated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stacked-stone-outdoor-kitchen/&quot;&gt;outdoor kitchens and grills islands&lt;/a&gt;, which often can ship straight from the manufacturer preassembled with a  metal outer layer that can be clad with stone, or a variety of other materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/11/Stacked Stone Veneer on PreFab Outdoor Kitchen.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Veneer installed on a prefab outdoor kitchen with metal substrate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the actual installation of stone veneer over metal substrates, we recommend two different methods.  With either method, the first step is making sure the surface is clean of any contamination, such as dirt, rust, paint, etc.  Pressure washing and sand blasting are effective techniques to get a clean metal substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the metal substrate is clean your two options for installing stone veneer are to either tack weld a wire lathe to the steel and then build out that layer with thick bed mortar mix, which will set and then the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;stone veneer can be applied to using a traditional cementious based thinset&lt;/a&gt;.  An alternative option that eliminates the metal lathe and scratch coat  is apply the stone veneer directly to the metal substrate using an epoxy based tile adhesive.  Be sure to talk to the manufacturer of the stone, or a sales rep with good knowledge of tile setting materials for a specific recommendation on the epoxy adhesive to use.  Set the stone veneer using the epoxy adhesive according to the instructions of the adhesive manufacturer, and if you have any of the epoxy adhesive left over, you can likely use it up over other more standard substrates since epoxy adhesives adhere to almost any type of substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/11/Stacked Stone Veneer on Exterior of Metal Building.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Metal Building with stacked stone veneer accents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been fortunate enough to work on a lot of unique and different installation processes with our clients having operated Norstone over the past decade plus and seeing millions of square feet of stone veneer get sold and installed.  Installations over metal substrates is just one example of a unique condition that a product like stone veneer can easily adapt to.  If you have a unique installation condition you are considering stone veneer for, please don’t hesitate to contact our sales and technical teams for more information on how stone veneer can be successfully used on just about any project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Did you know that stone veneer can be installed over metal substrates? We've gotten this question a couple times from clients in the past couple days so figured it'd be a good topic to tackle in this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/11/Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20PreFab%20Outdoor%20Kitchen.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20prefab%20outdoor%20grill%20island%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Prefab%20outdoor%20grill%20island%20and%20summer%20kitchen%20with%20a%20metal%20substrate%20that%20has%20been%20clad%20with%20a%20stone%20veneer%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A One of A Kind Stone Bathroom</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/one-of-a-kind-stone-bathroom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A One of A Kind Stone Bathroom" /><published>2018-10-03T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/a-one-of-a-kind-stone-bathroom</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/one-of-a-kind-stone-bathroom/">&lt;p&gt;Natural stone is a great choice for bathroom projects because it helps evoke that spa like feel that really elevates a space.  This master bath renovation project took the natural stone design scheme and ran with it all the way to the goal line.  Beautiful flooring and an amazing textured wall of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Norstone Ochre XL Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; all lead up to the real show stopper, which is the amazing free standing one-piece natural stone tub.  Let’s take a look at all of those things and the awesome details that make this space noteworthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/04/Stacked Stone Bathroom Feature Wall with Freestanding Tub.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Feature Wall in a bathroom feauturing a freestanding one piece natural stone tub&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flooring has always been a primary use for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-bathrooms-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;natural stone in high end bathrooms&lt;/a&gt;.  We don’t have a ton of detail about the flooring used in this project, but visually we can tell its a large format tile that is either natural stone, or a high end porcelain version that uses HD printing and other technologies to very closely mimic the look of natural stone.  In recent years, porcelain tile manufacturing has gotten so good that its almost impossible to tell from pictures alone whether a product is natural stone or manufactured tile.  Regardless, the floor tile in this bathroom sets the color tone for the entire space which the tub, accent wall, and all other design elements work off of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stacked stone feature wall stands out from both a color and texture standpoint.  While still working within the base “earth tones” of the space, the Ochre XL Rock Panels also bring in a nice blend of accent colors, including some darker charcoals that work with the storage unit and inside of the tub, as well as some lighter brown and orange accents that complement the exposed wood beam on the ceiling.  The texture the wall creates is super important to the overall feel of the space, complementing the freestanding natural hewn tub.  The height of the room and the decision to go floor to ceiling with the stone helps give this feature wall an added visual impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/04/Stacked Stone Bathroom Feature Wall with Vintage Tub Hardware.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre XL Stacked Stone on a bathroom feature wall showing a close up of vintage tub hardware&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small detail not to be missed is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;light fixture on the stone wall&lt;/a&gt;.  Positioned to illuminate the tub hardware and provide some low level ambient lighting to enjoy both a soak and a good book, this light fixture also does a great job of blending into the wall and not detracting from the stone feature wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving the best for last, the tub itself is really the focus of the space and in and of itself an incredibly unique design element.  One piece stone stubs are kind of like the Rolls Royce of bathrooms and you most often see them made from marble.  What is really cool about this particular tub is that the stone its made from has a very unique looking natural cleft to the outside of it as well as the overall shape of the tub.  To truly appreciate natural stone, you have to learn to appreciate the imperfections in nature and how those manifest themselves in finished products.  The asymmetrical nature of this tub really hits home that the beauty is in the imperfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the box design ideas aren’t for everyone when it comes to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/showers/&quot;&gt;bathroom design&lt;/a&gt; or remodel project, but they sure are fun to look and dream about for your own space.  If you are considering using stone in your next bathroom project give any of our product experts a call and we’d be happy to walk you through our line of veneers that can help take your project to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We see a lot of bathroom project photos come across our desk, but this one definitely stands out! There's amazing stone and natural details everywhere you look – come take a peek with us and get inspired for your next bathroom remodel.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/10/04/Stacked%20Stone%20Bathroom%20Feature%20Wall%20with%20Freestanding%20Tub.jpeg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22One%20of%20a%20Kind%20Stone%20Bathroom%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22A%20super%20unique%20stone%20bathroom%20featuring%20a%20floor%20to%20ceiling%20stacked%20stone%20feature%20wall%20and%20a%20freestanding%20one%20piece%20natural%20stone%20tub.%22%7D" /></entry></feed>