<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-14T21:59:25+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Grey Aksent Panels in a Modern Fireplace Design</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-panels-modern-fireplace-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Aksent Panels in a Modern Fireplace Design" /><published>2019-01-14T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-panels-in-a-modern-fireplace-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-panels-modern-fireplace-design/">&lt;p&gt;We’re huge fans of modern design with its open spaces, clean lines and hard surfaces, so we instantly fell in love with this fireplace project recently finished using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; in the Ash Grey color.  There’s so much to like about this space and the way the fireplace has been designed into it that we knew right away we’d be featuring it on a blog to share with our followers.  So let’s get right into it and tell you what we love about this modern fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent Modern Fireplace in Loft Space.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Stone Panels in Ash Grey used on a modern fireplace in a large open loft style space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we even get to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;stone veneer fireplace&lt;/a&gt;, you really have to appreciate the space this unit has been designed into.  The high ceilings create a ton of volume in the space and the magnificent glass windows above the fireplace let in an amazing amount of natural light which really opens the space up.  We’re not normally big fans of seeing shadows in photos, but in this particular case it all kind of comes together to create that “lofty” modern feel that is so desirable in design these days.  The clean lines of the windows and doorways – no arches here – add to straightforward linear design this space does such a fantastic job creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent Modern Fireplace TV and Fireplace.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Stone Panels in Ash Grey used on a modern fireplace with a large tv mounted above a linear gas insert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the fireplace itself, there’s just so much detail going on in a relatively little space that its hard to see it all without really looking hard at the design.  First off, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-uk-modern-home/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Panel in Grey is a very modern designed product&lt;/a&gt;, with its horizontal linear orientation is a perfect color selection to slightly contrast against the base white color palette of this space and also tie in nicely to the color of the built in shelving, storage, and counter top spaces flanking the fireplace.  The long linear look of the Aksent 3D Panel is also a perfect fit with the long and skinny gas fireplace insert chosen for the fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a product standpoint, there are two things that shine through about the design of the Aksent 3D Panel product that worked really well in this application.  The first is the outside corners, which turn back from the face of the fireplace into the inserts on each side.  Norstone has been making &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;the best corner system on the stone veneer market&lt;/a&gt; for over a decade using our finger joint concept and building them with a high degree of calibration and a final hand test fit before they leave our factory.  It’s projects like this, where the outside corner is super prominent for both the face of the fireplace as well as the functional inserts, where a super functional and perfect looking corner unit outshines the lower level dovetail and z-style corner concepts of some of our competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent Modern Fireplace-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Stone Panels in Ash Grey used on a modern fireplace with outsider corners and where the stone extends partially towards the high ceilings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that sticks out from a design standpoint how the design of this modern fireplace opted to extend the stone partially up the wall, above the height level of the inserts but not all the way up to the ceiling.  From an application standpoint, this isn’t something you see very often, as designers tend to either keep the height of the stone at a specific level that’s tied to other features of the fireplace, such as mantel height, or take the stone veneer all the way to the ceiling.  In this instance, stopping it at the height of the built ins and doorways would make the fireplace appear small in stature, and probably wouldn’t even cover the TV mounted on it.  Taking it all the way to the ceiling isn’t an option either as the pattern of the windows would create an uneven break.  Although we’ve never seen it done before, the Aksent Modern stone panel is a perfect product to take and stop mid wall like has been done here.  The thin side profile of this modern panel doesn’t create too much bulk on the wall and the clean horizontal lines create a nice break point for the fireplace stone installation, midway between the top of the built ins and the windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got a fireplace that needs a re-do and you like modern styled products, our Aksent 3D Panels are definitely worth taking a look at.  Available in four colors ranging from dark to light, you’ll find a great fit for your next modern fireplace project.  Contact us today to learn more about our contemporary stone veneer products, as well as our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;traditional stacked stone panel products&lt;/a&gt; that are a great option for more traditional looking designs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our Grey Aksent panels are the perfect choice for this modern fireplace that a customer of ours recently completed. A big space like this “lofty” feeling great room needs a focal point, and the Aksent 3 Dimensional panels deliver!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/01/14/Aksent%20Modern%20Fireplace.jpeg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Grey%20Aksent%20Panels%20on%20a%20Modern%20Fireplace%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Grey%20Aksent%20Panels%20used%20on%20a%20modern%20designed%20fireplace%20in%20a%20large%20loft%20style%20space%20in%20the%20upper%20Midwest%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Acid Should Not Be Used to Clean Natural Stone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/why-acid-is-bad-for-natural-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Acid Should Not Be Used to Clean Natural Stone" /><published>2019-01-08T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/why-acid-should-not-be-used-to-clean-natural-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/why-acid-is-bad-for-natural-stone/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re familiar with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;installation guide&lt;/a&gt; you’ll know that one of the few things we highlight in red type is that our natural stone products should not be cleaned with any form of acidic solution.  In the tile world, diluted acid is commonly used in the initial clean up after an installation as it’s an effective cleaner for porcelain and ceramic tiles, quickly removing thinset as well as any other grime that a tile might catch during installation.  However, many natural stone products are much more sensitive to acid and using acid to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-clean-natural-stone-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;clean some natural stone products&lt;/a&gt; can result in a variety of different issues.  Let’s take a look at two of the most common negative results of cleaning natural stone with acid, oxidation and surface etching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oxidation in the natural stone world is most often caused when something catalyzes a reaction with iron content in stone and the result is a rust like bloom across the stone.  Lots of different types of natural stones, including many used for building materials, have varying levels of iron content in them, but generally speaking there’s no major concern about the stone rusting out because a significant amount of catalyst would be needed to start a reaction.  Unfortunately, muriatic acid, which is the most common acid used in the tile industry for cleaning is a really strong acid and can catalyze an oxidation reaction with no problem.  Several years ago we tested the effects on our rock panel products of different types of acid, ranging from everyday household acid based cleaners to undiluted muriatic acid.  All of them resulted in some form of oxidation to the stone, with the stronger the acid the more oxidation was created.  The photo below shows the effect of muriatic acid on a test piece of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/08/Natural Stone that has been Cleaned with Muriatic Acid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Charcoal Rock Panels that were tested with undiluted muriatic acid resulting in oxidation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other common negative result of combining acid with natural stone is surface etching.  Since natural stone products, particularly tiles, come in a variety of different finishes, surface etching can take on a variety of different visual outcomes.  On a more highly polished or honed finish, the acid will tend  to dull out the color of the stone visually, and if you’re able to take a look up close at the finish the once smooth surface will have significant surface marks and divots.  The photo below shows some of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia tile&lt;/a&gt; in the Ebony Basalt color that has been washed with acid based commercial cleaning chemicals for several years – what was once a smooth to the touch almost glassy finish to the stone is now significantly pockmarked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/08/Polished Natural stone with surface divots from acidic cleaning.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lynia Tile showing surface divots after years of being cleaned with acidic commercial cleaning products&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural stone that has a more textured finish from the start, such as the natural cleft finish of our stacked stone rock panels, can also be negatively impacted by surface etching of acid on the face of the stone.  While each stone is different, most often we see acid surface etch this type of finish to a very fine pumice like consistency, eating away the natural cleavage plans of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution for dealing with the effects of acid on natural stone vary as well.  Most oxidation situations can be cleaned through a variety of different stone specific cleaning products and techniques.  The stone is then often &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;sealed for protection&lt;/a&gt; against future oxidation blooms.  Surface etching is a much more damaging result of acid interaction with natural stone.  Depending on the type of and finish of the original stone, it might be possible to refinish the damaged stone in place, however many surface etching problems also result in tear down and re-installations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, whether its for our Norstone products or any other natural stone products, feel free to give our expert tech services team a call or send us an email and we’re happy to share our knowledge and offer any suggestions.  And remember, whenever you’re working with natural stone – lay off the acid!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Acid can wreak havoc on a natural stone installation, whether used directly after installation as part of the clean up process, or over time as part of routine cleaning and maintenance. Let's take a look at a real life example of how acid cleaners can cause problems for a natural stone installation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/01/08/Natural%20Stone%20Installation.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Installation%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20White%20Rock%20Panels%20being%20installed%20on%20an%20exterior%20garden%20wall%20and%20cleaned%20up%20post%20installation%20without%20the%20need%20for%20acid.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Planc Modern Fireplace</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-planc-modern-fireplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Planc Modern Fireplace" /><published>2019-01-03T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-03T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-planc-modern-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-planc-modern-fireplace/">&lt;p&gt;When we think of our most ultra modern color, Basalt Ebony is always what comes to mind.  We’ve been making our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Panels&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt; for several years in this color, but with the introduction of the new Planc large format tile product, Basalt Ebony really went next level in terms of a modern look.  This quick set of photos is one of the first projects we’ve gotten back from our clients and we’re ecstatic with how the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/ebony-basalt/&quot;&gt;Ebony Planc&lt;/a&gt; came together on this modern fireplace project.  It’s always the details that take a project from ordinary to extraordinary, and this one is no different!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/03/Ebony Planc Modern Fireplace with Linear Gas Insert.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Large Format Tiles in Ebony installed on a modern fireplace with linear gas insert and tv recess&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and primary design feature of most fireplace applications is going to be the fireplace itself, and it’s always important to match the style of the fireplace unit to the design scheme and style of the overall fireplace and space itself.  This was done exceptionally well with this fireplace – the long linear gas fireplace insert is a nice design complement to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-new-dimension-norstone/&quot;&gt;large format of the Planc tile product&lt;/a&gt;.  Both products encourage the design to be stretched horizontally and make the fireplace look bigger and wider than it actually is.  We also love the symmetry between the fireplace and tv recess, which look to be almost the exact same width which also complements the modern look.  And lastly, while it doesn’t have much to do with the stone veneer, I do love the fact that this fireplace is actually putting out some flames!  It’s always disappointing to the author when you see a beautiful gas fireplace insert, especially a long linear one like we have in this installation, that is just barely putting out any flame whatsoever.  Nothing beats the natural curl of a flame, and we really appreciate this particular unit pumping out some nice sized flames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting televisions on fireplaces is something relatively new, only with the advent of flat screens in the past decade or so have we seen this start to become quite normal.  While’s its not hard to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/&quot;&gt;hang a television on a stone veneer installation&lt;/a&gt;, we do really love the way the unit is recessed in this installation.  From a build standpoint, it would be much easier to not frame out the recess and simply mount the tv proud of the stone veneer, but by creating this recess and essentially keeping the front of the tv almost flush with the face of the stone and fireplace, it gives the space a much more cohesive look that was planned out and designed, not added as an after thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2019/01/03/Ebony Planc Modern Fireplace with Flat Screen TV Recess-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Large Format Tiles in Ebony installed on a modern fireplace with outside corners&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside corners are almost always part of a fireplace project, and while this project was no exception, the Planc large format modern tile product does offer some unique corner options.  If you zoom in on this application, the installer actually used a very simple technique to turn the outside corner by simply leaving the cut edge of the tiles on the front of the fireplace facing out on each side, and then the simply butting the tile on the returns up behind the face tile.  This exposes one cut edge, that is all facing the same direction, in this case away from the face of the fireplace.  Some installers, especially those that have some experience working with natural stone, might even buff or polish the cut edges of a corner installation like this to make them look the same as the honed finish of the face of the tile.  A more technically advanced option would be a simple 45 degree outside miter cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;modern stone fireplace project&lt;/a&gt; is on your to-do list for 2019, definitely check out our new Planc tile product as its quickly becoming a go to product for our clients that are looking for the beauty of a natural stone product, but in a clean, smooth format that’s really trending in fireplace design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We're loving seeing photos of our new Planc product come back and this one is no exception. Let's take a quick look around this stunning modern fireplace project that used the ultra luxe Basalt Ebony color on this week's blog.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2019/01/03/Ebony%20Planc%20Modern%20Fireplace%20with%20Flat%20Screen%20TV%20Recess.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Wall%20Tile%20Modern%20Fireplace%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Ebony%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20wall%20tile%20used%20on%20a%20residential%20fireplace%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2018 – A Year in Natural Stone for Norstone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-a-year-in-natural-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 – A Year in Natural Stone for Norstone" /><published>2018-12-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-a-year-in-natural-stone-for-norstone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-a-year-in-natural-stone/">&lt;p&gt;2018 has been one heck of a year for the team here at Norstone’s New Dimensions in Natural Stone blog.  With the calendar resetting to January in a few short days, we wanted to take a quick moment to review some of the highlights from a truly incredible year.  With no further delay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Products&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/27/Norstone Planc Large Format Wall Tile Launched in 2018-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Platinum Planc Large Format Tile Product Launched in 2018 used on a modern kitchen backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past year saw the culmination of a lot of work by our overseas R&amp;amp;D teams based in Australia and Vietnam come to fruition in the form of new products we successfully brought to market.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc large format tile&lt;/a&gt; has been tremendously successful and is pushing the limits of not just what people think or as wall veneer, but also the types of products that the market and many of our legacy customers associate Norstone with.  The super &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth modern stone look&lt;/a&gt; of the Planc series is considerably different than the traditional stacked stone panel systems Norstone has been known for over the past decade plus and has helped reignite old customers and inspire new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/27/Norstone Slim Line Rock Panels Launched in 2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Slim Line Rock Panel Launched in 2018 used on a residential exterior&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-slim-line-budget-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Slim Line budget stacked stone panel&lt;/a&gt; system also officially launched in 2019, and while not as trend setting as the Planc, has given all of our customers the ability to compete with far inferior products that are becoming more and more prevalent in the market.  Slim Line, which is a thinner version of our Standard Series Rock Panel, has so much to offer, including the Norstone craftsmanship and design, outside corner units and natural end pieces, as well as a being eligible for an extended system warranty via Laticrete, that it’s a no brainer to use Slim Line instead of a bargain basement stone veneer panel from a big box store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New and Re Kindled Relationships&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best parts about working with a product where we supply the entire vertical, from a top level distributor / re-seller to sometimes working direct with a homeowner client is making new relationships on practically a daily basis.  One of the things we’re most grateful for in 2018 was new relationships that we formed and a few old ones that we re-kindled.  Becoming vendor partners in the United Buyers Group in the early Spring and attending their Buyers University in Texas this April where we instantly were able to show our product to hundreds of top fireplace showrooms from across the country was an amazing experience.  And through the launch of our new products and display systems, we got a chance to get back out in front of many of our legacy wholesale customers and re-invigorate them on what Norstone looks like in 2018 and beyond – we’re not just stacked stone anymore!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great Content on the New Dimensions in Natural Stone Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/27/Norstone New Dimension in Natural Stone Blog Logo.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone's New Dimensions in Natural Stone Blog Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we’re really proud about is that come January 2019, this blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/&quot;&gt;New Dimensions in Natural Stone&lt;/a&gt;, will be two years old and counting.  We’re excited to be pumping out 50+ posts each year of all sorts of natural stone related content.  From our “How To” Series, to technical / installation related posts, to industry news, as well as our bi weekly project profiles, we hope you find what we’re doing here week in and week out useful and interesting.  We get almost all the inspiration for our weekly articles from customers questions to our sales and technical staff, but if there’s ever anything that you would like to see covered don’t be shy and email us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sales@norstoneusa.com&quot;&gt;sales@norstoneusa.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick trip down memory lane with us today.  We hope 2018 was a great year for you, and we look forward to sharing with you weekly the comings and goings of Norstone and our team, and all the amazing things we have planned for 2019!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">With 2018 coming to a close in just a few short days we wanted to recap some of the highlights of a year in natural stone for the Norstone team.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/12/27/Norstone%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Wall%20Tile%20Launched%20in%202018.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%202018%20Year%20In%20Review%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%202018%20Year%20In%20Review%20Title%20Photo%20of%20a%20Planc%20Platinum%20Backsplash%20Project%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Pattern Choice Can Impact Takeoffs on Stone Veneer Installations</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-pattern-impacts-stone-installations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Pattern Choice Can Impact Takeoffs on Stone Veneer Installations" /><published>2018-12-20T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-20T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-pattern-choice-can-impact-takeoffs-on-stone-veneer-installations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-pattern-impacts-stone-installations/">&lt;p&gt;Most of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;natural stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt; are installed in what we call a random pattern, where basically the installer is taking care to not line up the vertical seam between two panels from one course to the next.  This is true for the majority of the products we sell, including our Standard, XL, and Slim Line Series Rock Panels as well as our Aksent 3D Honed Stone Veneer panel system.  The Lynia Interlocking Tile and our newly released Planc Large Format Tile can be laid in a variety of patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/20/Norstone Planc Large Format Tile Fireplace Set in Running Bond Pattern-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norsotne Planc in Platinum Color set in a running bond pattern on a floor to ceiling fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love it when our customers set these products in different patterns, like a nice herringbone Planc installation, or simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/installing-norstone-vertical-orientation/&quot;&gt;installing Lynia tile on a vertical orientation&lt;/a&gt; instead of horizontally.  It’s almost like you’re seeing a totally different product!  An important step when setting a tile product in a specific pattern is determining how that pattern fits into the space where it’s going and then making sure the amount of material ordered and on hand is enough to cover the job.  Certain patterns with certain relative dimensions are going to create more waste than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/20/Norstone Planc Large Format Tile in Herringbone Pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc in Basalt Grey laid out in a herringbone pattern&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way we’ve found to explain this concept, both internally when training our own team members, as well as when speaking with our dealers, distributors, and customers is by providing examples.  So let’s take a look at a few simple ones to grasp this concept so it can be applied to any project you are working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/20/Norstone Lynia Tile with Interocking Pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile in Ash Grey shown as a single unit with dimensions listed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt; are preset in a staggered pattern.  Each tile unit consists of 9 strips, and when laid in its native horizontal orientation, each unit is about 17” end to end and 15” tall.  A great, and very common, example of how pattern can impact how much material is needed for a project is to consider a standard kitchen back splash that is 18” tall from counter top to the bottom of the upper cabinets and for purposes of our example, we’ll assume its 10 feet long.  If you’re setting a 2” tall subway tile in this space you simply need to calculate length (10 feet) x width (18”) to get your total sq ft, which in this example turns out to be 15 sq ft.  If selecting a patterned tile like Lynia, you’d need to consider the height of the tile unit (15”) relative to the height of the space (18”).  In this example, you’d need TWO rows of Lynia units to fill up the 18” height – the first row will be a full unit at 15” tall and the second row will be a full unit cut down to 3” in height.  Calculating this out, you’d need 20 units total, or about 26 sq ft, of the Lynia tile for this job, due to the pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/20/Norstone Planc Large Format Tile in Stagger Pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Planc Large Format Tile in Platinum shown as a single unit in a running bond pattern with dimensions listed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Tiles&lt;/a&gt; offer an even wider range of pattern options because each Planc set is three loose strips of stone, each of the strips are 31.5” long and are 5.5”, 3.1” and 2.4” tall.  A good example of how a pattern with Planc can impact the material calculation is to consider a simple feature wall that is 48” wide and 10’ tall.  The simple width x height calculation gives you an easy 40 sq ft of material, and if you’re choosing to set the Planc in a random running bond pattern, you’ll get great coverage out of each unit and be good with 40 sq ft plus a normal waste factor.  But what if you wanted to do a symmetrical pattern where you split the wall in half down the middle and straight stacked the tiles from floor to ceiling?  In this pattern you’d end up cutting each of the Planc sets down from 31.5” to 24” (equal to half the width of the wall), and your material requirement would be 22 full sets, or 52.8 sq ft plus a normal waste factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confused yet?  We hope not!  Patterns do take a cerebral approach to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-how-measure/&quot;&gt;calculating the material needed for a stone installation&lt;/a&gt;, and often times a complicated pattern, especially if used in a small space, will result in more material needed than just the actual square footage on the wall suggests, but we think you’ll agree that a pattern can really enhance the look  of a stone installation.  If you’re considering a pattern and want help calculating how much material is needed for your project, or just want to learn more about any of our products, please call one of our amazing team members who will be more than happy to help walk you through the process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Did you know that what pattern you choose to install your stone veneer in, along with the specifics of your project could substantively change how much material you need to finish the job? Let's look at how that happens and what you need to know to order right the first time!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/12/20/Norstone%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Fireplace%20Set%20in%20Running%20Bond%20Pattern.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22How%20Stone%20Installation%20Patterns%20Impact%20Quantity%20Required%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Patterns%20that%20impact%20the%20amount%20of%20stone%20needed%20for%20an%20installation%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Awesome Exterior Platinum Planc on a Reno Hillside</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-large-format-tile-hillside-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Awesome Exterior Platinum Planc on a Reno Hillside" /><published>2018-12-14T15:37:19+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-14T15:37:19+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/awesome-exterior-platinum-planc-on-a-reno-hillside</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/planc-large-format-tile-hillside-home/">&lt;p&gt;The past couple weeks we’ve started to see a bunch of project photos come back from very happy clients who are working with our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;Planc Large Format Tile&lt;/a&gt; product.  The Planc was officially launched in the Spring of this year, so there are a lot of products that are just starting to near completion after going through the design and construction process over the Summer and Fall.  This particular set from a new residential construction project in Reno is not quite complete, but the installation of Platinum Planc looks so good we just had to share them with you asap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/14/Platinum Planc Large Format Tile Residential Exterior.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Platinum Planc Large Format Tile on a residential exterior feature wall on a hillside home in Reno&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pulled back view of this project is really what caught our eye the most.  The setting is idyllic, with the tall western Pine trees framing a beautifully modern inspired house.  The clean lines and sharp angles of the roof flow nicely down to the yet to be completed bump out where the outdoor grill can be seen, and then on further down to where the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/platinum/&quot;&gt;Platinum Planc&lt;/a&gt; is used around the base of an outdoor area as it comes out from the main level of the home and then travels down the natural grade of the hillside.  The large format design of the Planc product, where each tile is 31.5” long appears to be in perfect scale to the rest of the house, and the smooth honed finish is exactly what it should be to match the rest of the design scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Platinum Planc is made of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-difference-between-basalt-and-lavastone/&quot;&gt;lavastone&lt;/a&gt;, which from a mineral composition is very similar to basalt, the main difference between the two being that basalt dries under pressure and lavastone tends to cool on or near the surface without as much pressure.  The lack of pressure in the cooling process is what gives lavastone its unique visual properties, such as veining and marking which gives it that unique, one of a kind look that only natural stone has.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;Natural stone pairs well with glass and steel&lt;/a&gt; in the framework of modern design as they form a nice contrast between the materials, but one thing that really stood out to us on this project is the beautiful wood siding also used extensively on the exterior of this home.  The inherent natural beauty of the stone and the wood play well off each other, and they both really look like they belong in this natural hillside setting with both beautiful tall trees and exposed boulders abounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/14/Platinum Planc Large Format Tile Residential Exterior Outside Corner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Platinum Planc Large Format Tile used on a residential feature wall with prominent outside corner on a modern hillside home in Reno&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The up close view of the project offers up some great detail about the Planc large format tile was used.  The prominent outside corner is done using an overlapping technique, where the cut edge of the corner is rotated from one side to the other from one course to the next.  Since the Platinum Planc product has  a saw cut finish, the cut edges end up looking the same as the face.  Other colors in the Planc Series have a honed finish, such as our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/ebony-basalt/&quot;&gt;Ebony&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/large-format-stone-veneer/grey-basalt/&quot;&gt;Grey Basalt&lt;/a&gt; colors, which would require either on site polishing of the exposed edge, or more likely the outside corner is made using a simple miter cut technique leaving no exposed edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An often overlooked installation detail is how far a natural stone installation should come to grade.  Typical practice is to leave a veneer product like natural stone a minimum of 6” above grade, but always check with your local building authority for local rules as they vary considerably based on climate.  We look forward to seeing photos of this project in the Spring once its complete and the landscaping is done to cover up the gap between the grade and the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this super cool Planc project with us today.  In many parts of the country its getting too cold for exterior projects like this, but the Planc product is ideally suited for interior projects as well, especially fireplaces.  Contact us today to learn more about Planc large format tile, to order a sample, and see how it can work for your next stone veneer project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Our new Planc Large Format Tile is perfect for exterior applications,especially as part of a modern design scheme. Come check out this in process hillside home in Reno, Nevada that just installed some Platinum on an exterior feature wall that showcases what this product is all about!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/12/14/Platinum%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20Residential%20Exterior%20Outside%20Corner.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Platinum%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20on%20Exterior%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Platinum%20Planc%20Large%20Format%20Tile%20on%20an%20exterior%20feature%20wall%20in%20modern%20designed%20hillside%20home%20in%20Reno%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stone Fireplace 101: The Hearth</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-veneer-fireplace-hearths/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stone Fireplace 101: The Hearth" /><published>2018-12-10T15:06:08+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-10T15:06:08+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-fireplace-101-the-hearth</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-veneer-fireplace-hearths/">&lt;p&gt;The fireplace hearth, while normally associated with a more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;classically styled fireplace&lt;/a&gt;, is really just an extension of the floor of the firebox. It started out, especially with wood burning fireplaces, as a functional and needed space, protecting the floor against sparks and embers that might fly out of the fireplace. Fireplace tools and even cooking instruments were stored and used on the hearth. In most homes built over the past half century, the majority of fireboxes are raised off the floor so you don’t have to bend down as much to tend the flame, which also raised the hearth and created a “hearth step”, where the hearth gets raised up as well and then typically extends out at least 12 inches from the face of the fireplace. A vast majority of these fireplaces, particularly with the explosion of regional and national home builders, were faced with some variety of brick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Gas Fireplace with Cantilevered Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels used on a natural stone veneer fireplace with cantilevered hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;natural stone panel systems&lt;/a&gt; and thin veneer products in the last 15 or so years, fireplaces started to get renovated at a pace never seen before. These products made it possible to cover up that old worn out brick and really change the look of an entire room. And since the new stone products were veneers, in most cases they could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-over-brick-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;applied directly to the existing brick fireplace&lt;/a&gt; resulting in a complete transformation with just a few hours of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Fireplace with Stone Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels used on a large wood burning fireplace with natural hewn stone hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another fundamental change in the fireplace industry was the increasing popularity of gas fireplace units over the last 2-3 decades. Homeowners loves these units because they don’t require wood fuel to burn and then clean up after.  From a practical design standpoint, gas fireplace units also eliminated the need for a hearth, so while many gas fireplaces still get built with a hearth, a new wave of fireplace design was also ushered in where the hearth was removed completely, creating a sleeker, and in many cases more contemporary look.  Gas fireplace units have also played a big role in changing the vertical position of where a fireplace gets installed on a wall.  Most commonly, the fireplaces were either on the floor or maybe set 12” up the wall, forming the aforementioned hearth step.  With the gas units not requiring a hearth, positioning them anywhere on the wall, especially at eye level is now possible, opening up more design possibilities within a space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Gas Fireplace with No Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Grey Aksent stone veneer used vertically with a modern gas fireplace with no hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When renovating or building a new fireplace with a traditional hearth step, natural stone veneer products typically are going to get used on the face of the step as well as the returns to the wall.  The outside corners that most hearth steps form are an important part of the installation, which is why having &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;great looking stone corner units&lt;/a&gt; is an important consideration when looking at products.  The horizontal top of the hearth is another area where design can really shine through.  The main requirement is that the product used must be non combustible, which makes stone and tile a popular choice.  Cut field and flag stone, slate, and marble are all popular materials that work well with our natural stone products and that we see get used for the hearth step topper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural Stone Veneer Gas Fireplace with Granite Hearth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels used on a gase fireplace with granite hearth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we’ve come to appreciate after working on hundreds, maybe thousands of natural stone veneer fireplace projects over the years with our clients is that no two fireplaces are really the same.  Whether it’s the material they choose for the face, the design of fireplace on the wall, and how functional accessories like hearth steps and mantles get used, the combinations are endless, allowing you to put your own unique stamp on each project.  Our sales reps and technical services team have lots of experience with fireplaces so don’t hesitate to reach out if you are just starting to plan for a fireplace renovation or have already selected materials – we’re here to share our knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Fireplace renovations are one of the most popular uses of our natural stone veneer products. The hearth can pose some design challenges, especially in a remodel project, but also provide a signature look for the space. Let's take a deep dive into fireplace hearths and explore the possibilities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/12/10/Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20with%20Stone%20Hearth.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20Hearth%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Natural%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20with%20raised%20cut%20stone%20hearth%20with%20storage%20cubbies%20underneath%20it.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Before and After Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-aztec-xl-stone-veneer-fireplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before and After Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace" /><published>2018-11-28T18:42:09+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-28T18:42:09+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-aztec-xl-stone-veneer-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/before-and-after-aztec-xl-stone-veneer-fireplace/">&lt;p&gt;When we first released our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/aztec/&quot;&gt;Aztec&lt;/a&gt; color several years ago we knew it was a going to be a great product for interior applications.  Aztec is really a brightened up version of our tried and true &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre&lt;/a&gt; color, with light earth tones of brown, grey and off white, with undertones ranging from blush to orange.  Aztec, because of its high mica content, also splits with a lot of facets, giving this color, along with its close cousins Pearl and Sierra, an understated glitter effect that isn’t overwhelming but definitely adds to the appeal of the product.  Interior projects,where lighter colors help set the tone of a space and good lighting really brings to life wall coverings, is the perfect playground for this color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace - Before.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Before photo of an old brick fireplace set to be redone with Norstone Aztec XL Stone Veneer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project profile this week is a customer we worked with directly a couple years ago that had an old brick fireplace that was in need of a new look.  One of the cool parts about this old installation was the unique way the original installers created “vents” out of cut pieces of brick for the “heatilator” system, which draws cold air from the room in and pumps it back out several degrees warmer.  Needless to say the ventilation system itself was scrapped in lieu of a new insert that is more energy efficient without the need for a ventilation system.  Overall, this fireplace had good bones, just needed a face lift!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace - Masonry Skim Coat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old brick fireplace receiving a masonry skim coat to prep it for installation of Norstone Aztec XL Stone Veneer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homeowner really liked our natural stone veneer panel system because it could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-over-brick-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;installed over the existing brick substrate&lt;/a&gt; with minimal prep work, our finger-joint corner units offered up a good solution to turn the outside corners and cover the small return back to the wall on each side of the fireplace, and because our system is DIY friendly, allowing him to do the work and save the money a tile installer would charge.  The photo here shows the fireplace as a masonry skim coat is being applied to the existing bricks to fill in any gaps and provide a smooth, level and plumb substrate to start from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace - After-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aztec XL Fireplace Remodel Project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finished product here is a night and day difference from the starting point.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/light-and-bright-aztec-stacked-stone-backsplash-in-orlando-fl/&quot;&gt;light and bright color of the Aztec&lt;/a&gt; works nicely with the wall color and hardwood flooring to liven up the space as compared to the drab red tones of the brick.  An updated lighting fixture that is nice and shiny not only helps drag the room out of the 90s, but also provides some great focused light on the stone.  While difficult to pick up on in a photo, that light along with the subtle sparkle / glitter effect the Aztec creates really creates a focal point for the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working components of the fireplace received a major overhaul as well, including a new insert and a nice set of new gas logs that do a much better job of drawing attention to the flame itself, whereas the old insert was more focused on the functionality of heating the room than style or design.  Luckily, with advances in fireplace and fireplace insert technology, now we can have fireplaces that are ultra efficient, and look great too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/28/Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aztec XL Stone Veneer Fireplace Remodel Project with new granite hearth stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing to point out is the new hearth stone.  Previously just bricks, the hearth is now really set off with a piece of black granite that contrasts well with the color the stone and ties in nicely with the insert as well as other element of the décor.  Granite or other types of natural stone like flag stone, field stone, marble,and travertine, whether sourced in smaller tiles and set to form the hearth, or cut as one piece from larger slabs, are all excellent ideas for hearth selections.  And since the size needed is generally pretty small, checking with your local slab yard is always worth doing to see what they have in their off cut stack where really good deals on beautiful materials can be found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this before and after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplace project&lt;/a&gt; with us – we hope you agree that the stone veneer really turned this space from quite ordinary to extraordinary.  If you have a space that you’re thinking about using stone veneer to enhance, contact one of our knowledgeable staff today to learn more, order samples, and get started designing your own extraordinary space.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">A recent cold snap at Norstone's headquarters in Central Florida has got us thinking about staying warm in front of a fireplace – so we dug through our archives and found this cool before and after project featuring our Aztec XL Series Rock Panels. Stay warm and enjoy this major transformation!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/28/Norstone%20Aztec%20XL%20Fireplace%20-%20After.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Aztec%20XL%20Stone%20Veneer%20Fireplace%20Before%20and%20After%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Before%20and%20After%20Project%20Photos%20of%20an%20old%20brick%20fireplace%20redone%20using%20Norstone%20Aztec%20XL%20Stone%20Veneer%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone’s Top 5 Dining Room Stacked Stone Feature Walls for Thanksgiving</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-dining-room-stacked-stone-feature-walls/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone's Top 5 Dining Room Stacked Stone Feature Walls for Thanksgiving" /><published>2018-11-19T20:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-19T20:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-s-top-5-dining-room-stacked-stone-feature-walls-for-thanksgiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-dining-room-stacked-stone-feature-walls/">&lt;p&gt;For many of us, Thanksgiving is the most important, often times the biggest meal of the year.  Whatever your traditions are, one thing we can all agree on is that a beautiful setting for the meal certainly enhances the entire experience.  So for this holiday season, we put together our top 5 dining room &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt;stacked stone feature walls&lt;/a&gt;.  Here they are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall Cyprus Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels visible through two large panoramic glass windows in an open concept kitchen and dining room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first space is a cool modern inspired open concept dining room / kitchen.  Prominent from any location in this big open space is the beautiful Ivory Rock Panel feature visible through the impossibly large panoramic glass windows.  Equally beautiful during the day as well as night time when this wall is lit up, this feature wall is a great focal point for the space and a beautiful backdrop for a festive meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Ochre Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels serving as a background feature wall in a small corner dining area with a spectacular sunburst syle overhead light fixture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every holiday celebration brings together friends and families near and far, and this next dining area is a great example of a how great design can work in small spaces.  This corner dining nook has an appropriately sized table for just a few, and is beautifully situated in front of a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend Stacked Stone Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; Feature wall.  Low slung benches instead of traditional backed chairs minimize the bulk of the furniture in this space, while the light fixture creates a lot of texture that is works well with the geometric three dimensionality of the stacked stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall Cyprus Outdoor Patio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Rock Panels on an outdoor feature wall surrounding an open air patio with dining chairs in Cyprus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next space expands on the traditional concept of a dining room as we go“al fresco” as they say in Italy.  This outdoor dining area is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ivory-stone-with-view-cyprus/&quot;&gt;Norstone project on the island of Cyprus&lt;/a&gt; in the Mediterranean Sea, and is nestled into a rocky outcrop on the owner’s property.  The stacked stone feature wall behind the area is actually designed as a utility screen, to block various equipment and control systems needed for the home from view.  We love the Ivory Rock Panels used on this wall as they tie in perfectly with the native limestone outcroppings and have great contrast against the bright blue Mediterranean sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone White Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Rock Panels on a prominent feature wall in a cozy modern inspired kitchen and dining area&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project features stacked stone perhaps the most prominently of any of our projects, with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;White Quartz Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; extending along the entire back side of this cozy living room.  The name of the game with this space is color and texture.  The White Rock Panels tie in perfectly with the color scheme of the marble counter top and white cabinetry while adding in a significant amount of texture to create some contrast against an otherwise sleek and modern inspired kitchen.  The light up “cafe” sign with its warm incandescent lighting helps to bring down the space and warm it up just the right amount to make it super appealing for any meal, holiday or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone Stacked Stone Dining Room Feature Wall Dallas See Through Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Rock Panels on a see through fireplace on a wall in a beautiful dining room with a large wood table and multiple floor to ceiling glass windows and a bubble style light fixture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last dining room in our top 5 list is this beautifully designed space in Dallas.  There are so many small details in this space that some of them get lost!  The table itself is gigantic, with seating for 12 and a very cool natural edge that creates a real rustic vibe.  The stone is used on cool feature wall adjoining the space with a clever see through two side fireplace that adjoins an outdoor seating area.  The rest of the space is amazing with its prominent floor to ceiling windows and doors which give the space amazing natural light, and for when the sun does go down, this room has some of the coolest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;light fixtures we’ve seen paired with our stone&lt;/a&gt;.  Thanksgiving, Christmas, or any meal in between, this is a great space to break bread with family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at our top 5 dining room stacked stone feature wall projects.  If you are considering stacked stone for a feature wall in your dining room, you still have time to get it done before the new year – so call us today to get started!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">With Thanksgiving a few days away, we thought it would be fun to put together a list of our top 5 dining room stacked stone feature walls to get ready for the big day. Check this out and let the feasting begin!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/20/Norstone%20Stacked%20Stone%20Dining%20Room%20Feature%20Wall%20Dallas%20See%20Through%20Fireplace.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Top%205%20Dining%20Room%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Walls%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Top%205%20Dining%20Room%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Walls%20countdown%20for%20the%202018%20Holiday%20Season%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">South Florida Kitchen Remodel with Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/kitchen-remodel-grey-lynia-interlocking-tile/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="South Florida Kitchen Remodel with Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile" /><published>2018-11-19T12:07:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-19T12:07:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/south-florida-kitchen-remodel-with-grey-lynia-interlocking-tile</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/kitchen-remodel-grey-lynia-interlocking-tile/">&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about going out on the road and visiting clients is hearing and seeing about the projects that are being done with our products.  I was down in South Florida last week and one of our awesome sales reps showed me this set of photos of her customer’s kitchen remodel project that is almost completed and which used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt; in the Ash Grey color as the back splash tile.  This isn’t the biggest kitchen, but they pack a lot of great design and features in the space they have.  Let’s take a closer look at some of these details that makes this space really special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash with Vent Hood.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile used on a backsplash application with a prominent stainless steel vent hood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Color is the first thing you’ll notice about this project.  The homeowner has really committed to a white and grey color pallet with stainless steel accent pieces throughout.  In particular the white cabinets and flooring really open the space up and allow for a nice open and airy feeling within the relatively small space they had to work with.  Going with the white colored grout on the installation of the medium format mosaic back splash is a bold move and really tests the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/&quot;&gt;installers accuracy and precision&lt;/a&gt; in maintaining straight lines and even courses – the end result though is beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash Modern Kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile used as a backsplash tile for a modern white and grey themed kitchen in Miami&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing the contrasting grout color does is it sets off the design of the interlocking tile which adds to the modern feel of the space. Our Lynia Interlocking Tiles consists of 9 strips of our basalt or marble stone that is cut to size and mounted on a two part backer system for ease of installation.  The design of this product is very modern leaning, with its symmetrical patterning, and use of both sharp horizontal and vertical lines in the layout.  The unspoiled white pallet of the cabinets and counter top come together nicely with the dark grey and geometric patterning of the Lynia Interlocking Tile to create a clean modern vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash to Ceiling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile used as a backsplash tile going from counter top to ceiling in a project in South Florida.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another often overlooked but very important part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;tile back splash project&lt;/a&gt; is where to end the back splash tile vertically on the wall.  This decision is often going to be dependent on specifics of the space and configuration of upper cabinets.  We really like how the tile was taken all the way to the ceiling in this application, both above the cook top and around the vent hood, as well as around the window near the sink.  While this does require a little extra tile, the effect of stretching the installation vertically and keeping the wall look consistent with just one finish really enhances the finished look of this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone Lynia Interlocking Tile Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ash Grey Lynia Interlocking Tile on a backsplash tile with LED under cabinet lighting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Lighting is an important element of a successful natural stone tile installation&lt;/a&gt; that should not be overlooked.  The natural lighting in this space is better than most, with a relatively large window over the sink bringing in lots of the natural stuff.  While it’s a little hard to tell in the photos because of the great natural light, the under cabinet lighting is a great feature that I think the homeowners will end up loving.  This low level lighting not only highlights and makes the stone stone tile back splash look amazing, but it is also really functional for any of those times when full on overhead lighting isn’t necessary.  One area that probably could use a lighting assist is the wall above the range hood.  Without a recessed ceiling light in this area, this corner starts to really pick up some shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a quick look at this cool back splash project down in South Florida with us today.  Our entire line up of natural stone products can be used on back splashes, as well as a host of other wall applications, equally suited for both modern as well as more rustic design schemes.  Contact us today to learn more about any of natural stone wall veneer products for your next project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">While meeting customers last week in South Florida I saw this great set of photos where our Lynia Interlocking Tiles in Ash Grey were used as part of a complete kitchen remodel. It turned out better than the homeowners imagined, so let's take a quick look around this project and see what it's all about.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/11/19/Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Backsplash%20Modern%20Kitchen.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Interlocking%20Tile%20Backsplash%20in%20Modern%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Backsplash%20in%20a%20Modern%20Kitchen%20Remodel%20Project%22%7D" /></entry></feed>