<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-19T12:24:28-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">Stone to the Ceiling at Boston Airport Area Hotel</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/three-story-stacked-stone-feature-wall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stone to the Ceiling at Boston Airport Area Hotel" /><published>2018-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-to-the-ceiling-at-boston-airport-area-hotel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/three-story-stacked-stone-feature-wall/">&lt;p&gt;One of the really cool things about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;thin stone veneer like Norstone Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; is that they can be used in applications not traditionally associated with traditional stone masonry.  A great example is this amazing lobby feature wall completed several years ago at a Boston Airport area hotel.  Soaring the equivalent of about three traditional stories, or over 30 feet into the air, this is an amazing large scale installation of our White Rock Panel product.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/aztec-stone-veneer-hotel/&quot;&gt;Hotels often use stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; and other hard surfaces for their commercial durability, and while extra large in size, this project has a lot of great detail and thought put into the space by the design team which we’ll dive into in this week’s blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/White Quartz Stacked Stone Hotel Lobby Atrium Feature Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Three Story Hotel Lobby Atrium Stacked Stone Feature Wal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing catches everyone that looks at this wall is the sheer size of it.  It’s actually hard to do it justice with the camera angles that the space provides!  One of the best views in our opinion is this angle looking back towards the entrance and reception desk on the first floor and mezzanine level on the second.  As is common in hotels, the first couple “public” floors tend to have higher ceilings to accommodate scaled up lobbies, restaurants, and meeting spaces, so when you actually put a measurement on this wall, the stone is going just over 30 feet floor to ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the cool things about stacked stone veneer is that it’s lightweight and can therefore be installed using a direct bond thinset method instead of mechanical fastening which is more common with traditional full thickness stone masonry.  Norstone Standard Series Rock Panels weight about 12.5 lbs per sq ft, below the threshold of 15 lbs per sq ft allowing them to be installed using the direct bond thinset method, making an installation like this hotel lobby possible.  The engineering team did make sure the wall was designed and built to accommodate the extra weight load, but apart from that this product was installed just like a our Rock Panels would be installed on one of our client’s fireplaces, backsplashes, or feature walls – just super sized!  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Installing stacked stone is easy&lt;/a&gt; when you’ve got a great product to work with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/Stone Veneer Hotel Lobby Atrium Wall with Skylights.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone White Quartz on large feature wall in Boston area hotel with skylights&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural light makes almost any space better, and this one is no exception.  Significant glass along the back wall of this lobby atrium adds a lot of natural light, as does the unique domed glass ceiling right above the stone feature wall.  While the glass doesn’t extend across the entire ceiling of the atrium space it hits the mark as far as bringing in beautiful natural light and maintaining an open feeling in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/Art Installation over White Stacked Stone Veneer.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Art installed over white stacked stone in boston area hotel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art pieces located on each expanse of the stone feature wall are unique and grand enough in size to not get overpowered by the overall scale of the wall and atrium.  We really liked this four segmented modern piece.  The black color and curved lines contrast nicely against the white blank canvas of the stone and the linear geometry of the rock panel system.  The installer expertly used metal stand offs to position the pieces in front of the stone, which not only makes it possible to get the art pieces to be flat against the variable face of the stone, but also adds an extra little bit of dimensionality to the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/19/Lighting Fixture in White Stacked Stone Feature Wall.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Large scale lighting fixtures installed on top of white stacked stone veneer panels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Light fixtures are an important accent to any stacked stone installation&lt;/a&gt;, and this one is no exception.  The scale of these fixtures, being almost 4 feet from tip to tip, and the brushed stainless finish which creates a great modern color scheme with the starkness of the White Rock Panels, makes them excellent choices for the space.  The installation team again has done an amazing job to get these fixtures sitting flat against the dimensional face of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While lobby atriums like this one will always pose design and material selection challenges due to the wall heights involved, so too will many of the “great rooms” of homes built in the last decade or so.  If you have a great room of your own at home with high ceilings and tall walls, stone veneer is a great product to consider since its classic in style and not the latest fad you’ll want to change out in two years, and lightweight enough to not warrant much, if any, structural work prior to installation.  We have a great team knowledgeable in the intricacies of installing stone veneer at height, so come to us with your questions and we’ll be happy to help.  And if you’re checking into a hotel in Boston anytime soon, be sure to look up and you might just have a view worth enjoying for a while!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">If you travel in and out of Boston a lot you might have seen this amazing lobby atrium wall featuring our White Quartz Rock Panels at one of the airport area hotels. This project was several years ago, but one we still go back to frequently to show customers how stacked stone veneer can be used in applications that go beyond normal ceiling height, which we'll explain in great detail in this week's blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/19/White%20Quartz%20Stacked%20Stone%20Hotel%20Lobby%20Atrium%20Feature%20Wall.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Three%20Story%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20White%20Rock%20Panels%20used%20on%20three%20story%20atrium%20lobby%20feature%20wall%20in%20Boston,%20MA%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Seal Stacked Stone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Seal Stacked Stone" /><published>2018-02-11T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-11T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-seal-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Stacked stone is a one of the most durable building materials on the planet, but even with that accolade there are still a variety of reasons why &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;stacked stone should be sealed post installation&lt;/a&gt;.  This can range from the type of installation such as exterior vs interior or wet vs dry, what kind of stone it is, and sometimes sealing the stone can just be used to create a specific visual effect desired.  Most sealers for natural stone are penetrating, meaning they soak into the stone and don’t exist just topically, and form a protective barrier that helps prevent any build up on or deterioration of the stone face.  Let’s dive a little deeper into the reasons why to seal stacked stone and then learn how to apply the sealer as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Stacked Stone on a Pool Feature.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone that has been sealed used on a pool feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exterior installations and installations where the stone is going to be in or around water, such as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone pool wall&lt;/a&gt;, fountain, or other water feature, should all be sealed after installation.  The sealer forms a protective barrier against the elements, especially water, which have the potential to damage a stacked stone installation, especially over time and in areas subject to freeze – thaw cycling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Stacked Stone on a Shower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vertical Strips of stacked stone used in a large walk in shower that have been sealed with a natural stone sealer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also always a good idea to seal certain types of stone.  Some stone, like limestone and travertine is more porous and sealing it helps prevent staining.  Other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/slate-tile-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;types of stone including slate&lt;/a&gt; can be high in iron content so a good quality seal prevents rust spotting when exposed to moisture.  The manufacturer of the stone product, or the local outlet where the stone is purchased from should be able to tell you if a certain type of stone absolutely needs sealed, and in general there’s really no harm in sealing stone even if it’s not a required step in the installation process for your project.  For Norstone products, we recommend that all colors of our Standard Series and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; be sealed for exterior and water applications.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Norstone’s Lynia IL Tile&lt;/a&gt; and Aksent 3D Panels should be sealed in all applications, both interior and exterior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the protective value of a sealer, they can also be used to create certain visual effects desirable in many installations.  Good examples of this are color enhancing sealers which darken up natural stone and high gloss sealers which leave behind a semi reflective sheen on the stone surface.  Since these sealers are designed for a specific effect we always recommend making sure they are compatible with your stone and to test the sealer on a sample piece to see that it achieves the desired effect before committing it to an entire wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Sealed Stacked Stone Garden Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Curved Stacked Stone garden wall that has been sealed with an enhancing sealer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might expect, there are a lot of different natural stone sealer options to choose from.  Some of the key differences in sealers is if they are water based or oil based and if they are penetrating or topical.  Always check with the manufacturer of the stone product you are working with to determine what’s right for your stone.  For all Norstone products we recommend sealers that are water based and penetrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/12/Sealed Interior Stacked Stone Water Feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interior stacked stone water feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the actual application of the natural stone sealer goes, the best and easiest way we’ve found to apply sealer is with a hand held pump sprayer.  This handy tool is readily available in the garden center of any home improvement store and most come with an adjustable tip to allow for a wider spray pattern to be used.  The key to applying sealer to stacked stone is to do multiple light coats versus fewer, heavier coats.  Allow the sealer time to soak into the stone before making another pass.  When you start to see the sealer sit on the surface of the stone and not soak in any more dab the excess sealer off with a cloth so it won’t dry and leave a haze.  Sealers will need to be re-applied every so often, based on the sealer manufacturer’s recommendation and in field testing of how strong the original seal is holding up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sealing is a relatively easy and inexpensive maintenance item that will protect and enhance the investment you’ve made in a stacked stone wall.  Here at Norstone we’re happy to share our expertise and answer technical questions about sealing and stacked stone in general, so contact us today and thanks for learning all about sealing stacked veneer with us today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Sealing stacked stone is an important finishing step for many projects, especially exterior installations, or where the stone is in or around water. Let's take a look at how and why stacked stone should be sealed in this week's blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/12/Stacked%20Stone%20on%20a%20Pool%20Feature.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20that%20should%20be%20sealed%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22A%20pool%20feature%20wall%20of%20stacked%20stone%20that%20should%20be%20sealed%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ebony Aksent 3D Panels Commercial Storefront Project</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-3d-panels-commercial-storefront/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ebony Aksent 3D Panels Commercial Storefront Project" /><published>2018-02-05T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-05T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-aksent-3d-panels-commercial-storefront-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ebony-3d-panels-commercial-storefront/">&lt;p&gt;Commercial storefronts are all about durability while still meeting the style and design demands of the developer and tenants.  Norstone has been fortunate enough to work with many higher end developers on commercial build outs where a natural stone veneer or facade was required as a way to distinguish a particular development compared to lower cost exterior veneers such as stucco, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/real-stone-vs-faux-norstone-industry-series/&quot;&gt;faux stone&lt;/a&gt;, and split face block.  The storefront featured in this week’s project profile is no exception featuring both our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL Series Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/ebony/&quot;&gt;Ebony Aksent 3D Panel&lt;/a&gt; set among a modern designed facade of steel paneling and glass.  Let’s take a closer look at the Ebony Aksent 3D Panels and see what makes them so special on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/07/Ebony Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Commercial Facade Under Construction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Commercial Entryway under construction where Norstone Ebony Aksent 3D Panels and Ochre XL Series Rock Panels were used&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that really catches our eye with the Ebony Aksent 3D stone veneer panels on this project is the height that they were installed.  Flanking two sets of doors on both sides, the stone veneer goes from finished floor height all the way to above the facade of building, where the vertical features connect with a horizontal bridge section.  At easily 20 feet in the air, the thin veneer format of the Aksent 3D Panels allows for the product to be set using an adhesive method in lieu of mechanical fastening (in accordance with the building codes of most areas).  Weighing in at around 8.5 lbs per foot, this stone veneer easily is below the 15 lb per square foot requirement where mechanical fastening becomes the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/07/Ebony Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Commercial Facade-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smooth stone veneer used on commercial entryway feature with prominent outside corners&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that we really liked about this project was the use of our finger jointed outside corner units for the Aksent 3D series.  We take a lot of pride in making what we feel like is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;most realistic and best looking outside corner unit&lt;/a&gt; in the stone veneer industry and projects like this, which features prominent outside corners the entire length up the wall is a great example of how great a stone veneer panel system corner can look like.  Just like the corner units in our Standard Series and XL Series Rock Panels, every piece of the corner unit that faces outward is finished the same as the face of the panel, which for the Aksent 3D panels is a smooth honed surface.  If you ever want to know how good of a stone veneer product you’re looking at, always look for a corner and see if some of the outward facing edges aren’t finished, or  if a more basic dovetail style interlocking pattern is used and you’ll understand more about why we’re so proud of the corner unit we created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/07/Norstone 3D Aksent and Standard Rock Panels on Commercial Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smooth and naturally textured stone veneer used as part of a modern inspired commercial facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing that stands out to us about this project is cool color combinations used on the facade.  The Ebony Aksent 3D product is stylistically geared towards a more modern look and as such, works really well with the commercial black framed windows and doors as well as the brushed steel facade panels.  The Ebony color, which is a handful of shades darker than the more popular Ash Grey color in the Aksent 3D panel line, is a better pick for this project as it is very close in color to the window frames and has great contrast against the steel facade.  The great geometric shape and texture the Aksent 3D Panels create also works nicely with the clean lines and architectural accents on the facade as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we know for sure is that our natural stone veneer products will stand the test of time, even in the harsh realities of a commercial setting like this one, which make them an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/&quot;&gt;ideal choice for commercial developers and residential designers and homeowners alike looking for stylish modern products&lt;/a&gt; that are easy to install and maintain.  Call and speak with one of our in house design experts or drop us a line via email and let us show you how a cool product like Ebony Aksent 3D panels can be a great fit for your next modern stone veneer project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Even though this project is still under construction, we liked how our Ebony Aksent stone veneer panels were looking so much we wanted to share some photos we snapped during a recent site visit. Enjoy!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/07/Ebony%20Aksent%203D%20Stone%20Veneer%20Commercial%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Commercial%20Storefront%20with%20Ebony%20Aksent%203D%20Stone%20Panels%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Aksent%20Stone%20Panels%20surrounding%20large%20glass%20and%20metal%20entryway%20of%20a%20commercial%20shopping%20center%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Cut Stacked Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-cut-stacked-stone-veneer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Cut Stacked Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-01-28T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-28T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-cut-stacked-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-cut-stacked-stone-veneer/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;Installing stacked stone veneer&lt;/a&gt; is a challenging, but achievable project for most DIY’ers.  One of the first questions we get when talking with potential customers is “How do I cut it?”.  Stone is a new building product for most people, unlike more traditional mediums like wood, metal, concrete, and tile, so bridging that gap with easy to understand knowledge is something we know our customers appreciate.  The short answer is that stacked stone veneer panels are best cut using a combination of two tools – a wet saw designed to cut tile and stone, and a angle grinder for more precision and unique cuts.  Let’s take a look at each of these tools and some things a first time &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;stone veneer DIY installer&lt;/a&gt; will want to know about each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Tile Wet Saw with a continuous rim diamond blade is going to be your primary cutting tool for a stack stone veneer panel installation.  A wet saw works on the concept of water being applied to the blade and to the tile or stone to provide lubrication as the blade cuts through.  The water is typically recycled through a close loop system which allows for it to drain off the tile and into a reservoir where a small pump is located which cycles it back up to blade.  One of the most important things to remember when working with a wet saw is to constantly be refreshing the water, especially when cutting stone since the heavy sediment the saw creates when cutting the stone will start to diminish the water’s ability to lubricate the saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/29/Wet Saw Cutting Stacked Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tile Wet Saw being used to cut a stacked stone veneer panel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A continuous rim diamond blade sounds fancy, but its actually a fairly prevalent type of blade available at most hardware stores and certainly any tile and stone shop.  Diamonds are one of the hardest naturally occurring materials on earth and are exceptionally good with cutting through tile and stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tile wet saw will typically either have a stationary blade and a movable tray where the stacked stone veneer can be placed and then pushed through the blade.  Alternatively some saws have a fixed tray and a movable blade set up.  Depending on the complexity of the cuts you need to make, tile saws can also have a blade that can be tilted, or a mount that can be fixed to the tray to allow for inside and outside &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/miter-cut-vs-corner-unit/&quot;&gt;miter cuts on stone veneer&lt;/a&gt;.  Either way, stone should cut nice and easy on a wet saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/29/Norstone Installation with Tile Wet Saw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tile Wet saw being used to cut Norstone Stacked Stone panels for a fireplace project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most important thing to remember when cutting stacked stone veneer on a tile wet saw is safety.  Eye protection is a must, and ear protection is a good idea as most units can get loud.  Working with electricity and power in the same tool requires extra diligence as well, so be sure to read the instruction manual and plug the the saw into a grounded outlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a tile wet saw will account for probably 95% or more of the cuts on most stacked stone veneer jobs, a hand held angle grinder is the tool of choice for everything else.  Whether you’re cutting a curve to fit around a pipe, or cutting a rectangle out of the panel to go around a light switch or outlet, an angle grinder is the tool for the job.  Since angle grinders don’t use water as a lubricant like a wet saw, cutting stacked stone veneer takes a little bit longer, can be ear screechingly loud, and create a lot of dust.  Blades also will need replaced much more frequently as compared to the wet saw.  Besides wearing eye and ear protection, heavy gloves are a great idea to protect hands and fingers from  stone chunks and the blade itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/29/Angle Grinder Cutting Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Angle grinder used for off angle and specialty cuts on stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tile wet saws are very commonly available to rent at local hardware equipment rental locations at a reasonable charge.  Unless you’re getting ready to do a bunch of tile and stone work, it’s generally worth renting this equipment, where you’ll typically get a higher grade saw, than purchasing a lower end one.  Quality angle grinders are available at reasonable price points if you can’t borrow one from a neighbor or friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for learning more about the best ways to cut stacked stone veneer with us today!  We enjoy sharing the knowledge and passion we have about our products and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;how to install stacked stone correctly&lt;/a&gt; with our customers and anyone interested in knowing more.  Please don’t hesitate to contact any of our reps who are well versed in technical knowledge of the product with any questions that you might have about stacked stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Calling all you DIY'ers out there – ever wondered how to best cut stacked stone under different conditions? Ask and you shall receive with this week's blog focusing on how to cut stacked stone veneer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/29/Norstone%20Installation%20with%20Tile%20Wet%20Saw.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Tile%20Wet%20Saw%20for%20Cutting%20Stacked%20Stone%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22In%20process%20installation%20of%20stacked%20stone%20on%20a%20fireplace%20where%20a%20tile%20wet%20saw%20is%20being%20used%20to%20make%20the%20cuts%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Glass, Steel, and Stone Make a Very Modern Home</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glass, Steel, and Stone Make a Very Modern Home" /><published>2018-01-22T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-and-stone-make-a-very-modern-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/glass-steel-stone-for-modern-homes/">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to modern residential architecture and design, three of the most prominent surfaces that you’ll see on the exterior envelope is glass, steel, and stone.  We’re ecstatic that the design team of this week’s featured project choose to use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre XL stone veneer rock panels&lt;/a&gt; as part of the stone package on this amazing home.  Let’s take a walk around the exterior of this project and have a look at how glass, steel, and stone blend together nicely in this modern beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Stone Glass and Steel Residential Modern Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street View of a Modern Designed Home featuring lots of glass, steel, and stone on its exterior surfaces&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The street facing elevation of the home makes an immediate impact with an enormous amount of glass windows, doors, and multi partition sliders, as well as a safety glass railing for the forward facing second story patio.  The steel elements are a little more subtle and are mainly used as accents on the soffits, hand rail, and house numbers.  Our stacked stone panels bring a major dose of contrasting texture to the columns, second story facade, and even along the privacy wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Modern Architecture Stone and Glass Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front Elevation of Modern Designed Home with a prominent stacked stone and glass facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As viewed from inside the privacy wall, two separate outdoor seating / lounging areas are revealed.  While viewing the house head on, the glass tends to dominate our attention, especially the mammoth single fixed window on the upper right hand side.  However, subtle details abound like the use of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;stone veneer on the risers separating the patio areas&lt;/a&gt; which bring a sophisticated cohesiveness to the design and helps this project stand out from the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Modern Architecture Stone and Glass Corner Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side View of the corner of a home with a glass corner on the first floor and stone veneer on the second story&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One side view of the home again shows the commitment to glass with a super unique corner on the first floor made entirely of glass.  Other types of stone are introduced with the large format paver walkway set in pebbles, as well as the continuation of the stone veneer along the second story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Two Story Outdoor Stone Veneer Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A large two story outdoor fireplace clad with stone veneer and a stainless steel firebox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stone take center stage on the opposite side of the home which has a tucked away outdoor fireplace.  This large feature is clad entirely in our large format XL Series stone veneer, appropriate for this two story fireplace with the stone going all the way up.  A sleek stainless steel firebox keeps with the modern theme and ties this space together with the other metallic elements in the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/23/Norstone XL Series Outside Corner Unit Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Detail showing Norstone XL Series Corner Units used in a real life application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we’ve learned having worked on projects with our natural stone veneers and natural stone tile lines for over a dozen years is that details matter, which is why this last photo is a great example of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;what makes Norstone different than other stone veneer panels on the market&lt;/a&gt;.  This exceptional photo of our corner units used on the band between the first and second stories of the house shows just how great an outside corner of stone veneer should look.  Every piece of stone visible shows the natural cleft, there’s not discernible pattern as to how the pieces come together, and above all it looks natural and not fabricated.  This attention to detail, not just on our corner units but on all our products and our customer experience from start to finish, is what makes Norstone different than a panel you can pick up at your local big box home improvement or discount tile store, or order off a website with no pictures to back it up or consultation to answer your questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about working on a modern project in the future, glass, steel, and stone are great design materials to look to incorporate into the design.  Our more traditional stone veneer panels like the XL Series and Standard Series are a great way to incorporate a contrasting texture to the smoothness of glass and steel, while some of our other products like the smooth faced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Series&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/lynia-mosaic-tiles/&quot;&gt;Lynia Interlocking Tile Series&lt;/a&gt; are decidedly modern right out the box.  Contact our team today and speak with one of our in house designers to learn more about what natural stone veneer and tile products might be a great fit for your next project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We love the architecture of this modern home with its abundance of glass, steel, and stone throughout its design. Let's take a closer look in this week's blog on what makes this house so special.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/23/Stone%20Glass%20and%20Steel%20Residential%20Modern%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Glass,%20Steel%20and%20Stacked%20Stone%20for%20a%20Modern%20Residential%20Facade%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Exterior%20of%20a%20residential%20home%20with%20a%20modern%20design%20scheme%20prominently%20featuring%20glass,%20steel,%20and%20stone%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Freeze – Thaw Cycles Can Impact Stacked Stone Veneer</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/freeze-thaw-and-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Freeze – Thaw Cycles Can Impact Stacked Stone Veneer" /><published>2018-01-17T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-17T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-freeze-thaw-cycles-can-impact-stacked-stone-veneer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/freeze-thaw-and-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Looking outside our office window in sunny Florida its definitely a rare event to see a hard freeze covering the grass, plants, and roofs with frost, but that’s just what we’re dealing with on this cold January morning.  And while it doesn’t happen but maybe once or twice a winter here in Florida, freeze – thaw cycling is a daily occurrence for many parts of the country for most winter.  The impacts of freeze – thaw cycling can be huge on all sorts of building materials, but for purposes of this blog, we’re going to look at how freeze – thaw cycling can impact a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stone veneer installation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first questions we get when we present our stone veneer panels or natural stone tile products to architects and designers is whether or not they can be used for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exterior stone installations&lt;/a&gt;, and if they can be used outside, what about freeze – thaw areas?  It’s an on point question because any residual moisture in a stone installation will expand when frozen, with the big risk being that the expansion and contraction caused by freeze – thaw cycling ends up destabilizing the install, and maybe even going so far as to crack a stone or pop it off the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/18/Exterior Stone Vener Columns in Freeze Thaw Climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Exterior Stacked Stone Veneer Columns lakeside in Wisconsin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a particularly valid question with our stone veneer panels.  Since these veneers are installed in a “dry stack” fashion, meaning no mortar goes in between the individual pieces of stone, there is clearly ample cracks, crevices and fissures for water and moisture to travel through, water log the substrate and create significant expansion during a freeze cycle.  More traditional stone veneers, specifically applications where mortar is “pointed” after the stone is set to fill in all the gaps between stones in an installation are seemingly much closer to being “water tight” and preventing much, if any water from getting through the stone and into the substrate.  So what’s the answer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/18/Stacked Stone Veneer in Freeze Thaw Climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Rock Panels in Snowy New England Climate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to this freeze – thaw conundrum for dry stacked stone veneer lies in both the substrate and the stone itself.  From a substrate standpoint, installers should plan for water to pass through stone veneer and into the substrate, there’s simply no way to prevent that in a dry stacked stone installation.  However, by using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;waterproofing and crack isolation membrane&lt;/a&gt; over the substrate and a freeze – thaw stable thinset, not only can you install dry stacked stone veneer panels, but you can even install natural stone tiles requiring grout, like our Lynia IL tiles.  The crack isolation membrane is specifically designed to absorb the small stresses created by freeze – thaw cycling without destabilizing an installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a stone standpoint, you also have to make sure the stone itself is freeze thaw tested.  Even if the substrate its stuck to is stable in these changing conditions, the stone itself might still show signs of freeze – thaw cycling.  Part of the process we go through when evaluating new products is to have them tested according to the ASTM C67 test, which soaks the stone samples for 4.5 hours in room temperature water, then freezes them for 20 hours, and then repeats this cycle 50 times.  The samples are examined every 5 cycles under magnification to look for any signs of cracking or fissuring.  A stone type that can crack or fissure under this type of testing would not be suited for exterior use as a building material in a freeze – thaw climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/18/Exterior Stacked Stone in Freeze Thaw Climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dry stack stone veneer used exterior on a North Carolina Lake in a freeze thaw climate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these products and techniques are still fairly new, maybe 10-15 years old, so in an industry like stone masonry where knowledge has been accumulating for centuries, there can be a knowledge gap between an experienced installer who might be doing things the same way as they were taught 30 years ago, versus an installer that might be more up to date on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;latest products, tools, and techniques that are coming into the tile and stone industry&lt;/a&gt; and making their jobs easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you found this article informative, especially if you have questions about how stacked stone veneer can be used in freeze – thaw locations.  Feel free to speak with any of our reps who are very knowledgeable in the technical aspects of installing our products and find out how a Norstone natural stone veneer or tile product can be a great fit for your next project.  And for those of us experiencing this winter cold snap – stay warm!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Freeze – thaw cycles have the potential to really impact an exterior stacked stone installation if not done correctly. In this week's blog we learn why freeze – thaw is such a big deal and the best way to address it in on a stacked stone project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/18/Exterior%20Stacked%20Stone%20in%20Freeze%20Thaw%20Climate.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Dry%20Stacked%20Stone%20Veneer%20in%20Freeze%20Thaw%20Climate%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20XL%20Series%20Charcoal%20Rock%20Panels%20used%20in%20an%20exterior%20freeze%20thaw%20installation%20in%20North%20Carolina%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Contemporary Texas Kitchen with Stone Veneer Fireplace</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/texas-kitchen-stone-veneer-fireplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contemporary Texas Kitchen with Stone Veneer Fireplace" /><published>2018-01-15T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/contemporary-texas-kitchen-with-stone-veneer-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/texas-kitchen-stone-veneer-fireplace/">&lt;p&gt;Austin, TX is a beautiful city with a rich culture of locally sourced stone used for building materials.  Texas limestone is a beautiful stone that is primarily a very light cream color, but can occasionally dip into some of the darker yellow and gold tones as well, where it can start to sometimes resemble our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Quartz Stone Veneer&lt;/a&gt;.  Anyone that has gotten the opportunity to visit this city has certainly seen the stone, as it is used prominently on facade work throughout the area, and if you pay attention to stone veneer, you’ll likely have even seen some of this in your local area as its popularity has spread far and wide.  The popularity of Texas limestone is one of the things that make this week’s project profile so compelling, since right in the heart of limestone country, this homeowner decided to flip the script and go with a bold black and white color scheme and an accent wall of our quartz stone veneer.  Let’s take a closer look at some of the things which make this project so unique!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that sticks out to us in the space is the bold use of a black and white color scheme.  Starting wit the floors and ceiling and then continuing on through the cabinets, counter tops and lighting fixtures, the design of this space knew what it was going for from a color standpoint and executed on it.  While we really love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/two-toned-modern-fireplace-in-ft-collins-co/&quot;&gt;two tone color scheme&lt;/a&gt; of the kitchen island, especially the texture side of the cabinetry, the gorgeous stacked stone wall created using our charcoal rock panels stands out and introduces more of a texture element to the overall smooth aesthetic the other surfaces create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/16/Stone Veneer Accent Wall with Ventless Fireplace - Austin,TX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charcoal Stone Veneer Wall in Kitchen with a ventless gas fireplace and tree branch art&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the stone accent wall really special is the ventless gas fireplace.  These units are relatively easy to install making them a good option for a smaller scale remodel where they can make a big impact visually, but not over complicate a project like a traditional vented fireplace requiring exhaust.  Beyond the stunning visual impact of the long linear unit, what we really like about the fireplace is what it says about the space.  A flat screen television could easily have been hung in the same space on this stone accent wall, but by choosing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;stone veneer fireplace&lt;/a&gt; for this location the area encourages conversation or quite reflection, and provides a sense of calmness to the kitchen, which is often the central hub of a home before, during, and after meal times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really couldn’t get past talking about this wall without bringing up the unique tree branch art piece that gracefully sits atop the stone accent wall.  What exactly is it?  We’re not sure but its defiantly a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/&quot;&gt;unique pairing for a stone wal&lt;/a&gt;l, and we love the conversation starter aspect of it, the unique texture and natural feel that it brings the space.  Kudos to the installer for keeping us, and everyone else, guessing as to how it stays in place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/16/Kitchen Stone Veneer Accent Wall - Austin,TX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Window seat nook at the end of a long kitchen with a stone veneer accent wall in Austin, TX&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functional spaces and attention to detail are the hallmarks of good design, and this tiny space in the corner on the short end of a long kitchen is very well done.  Continuing the stone veneer accent wall over the hallway and into this little bench seat area creates continuity with the rest of the space, and the attention to detail as shown through the adjustable reading lamp and light switch add little bits of character to the stone accent wall and help break it up in much the same way the fireplace does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bold black and white design with varied textures and lots of things to look at is certain to make this Texas kitchen project standout, and while a big stone wall doesn’t work for every kitchen,  it certainly does for this space.  If you’re considering stone for your next kitchen project, talk to us today about how Norstone natural stone veneer and tile products can easily transform your space into something you love!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">There's so much to love about this kitchen recently completed in a re-developing area area of Texas' Capitol city of Austin, especially the super cool stone wall with a low maintenance but stylishly designed ventless fireplace. Let's take a look at all the things that make this project cool in this week's project profile!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/16/Stone%20Veneer%20Accent%20Wall%20with%20Ventless%20Fireplace%20-%20Austin,TX.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stone%20Veneer%20Accent%20Wall%20in%20Austin,%20TX%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20Stone%20Veneer%20Accent%20wall%20in%20modern%20black%20and%20white%20themed%20kitchen%20in%20Austin,%20TX%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2018 Resolutions in Stacked Stone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-resolutions-in-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 Resolutions in Stacked Stone" /><published>2018-01-02T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-02T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-resolutions-in-stacked-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/2018-resolutions-in-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Whether individually, or as a collective group like the team here at Norstone, the beginning of the year is always a great time to reflect back on the past year and put together some resolutions for the upcoming one.  We see a lot of great things on the horizon for Norstone and the decorative stone and tile industry as a whole, and look forward to turning this list of resolutions into reality for 2018 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #1 - Continue to Launch New and Exciting Stone Veneer Products&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the heels of our highly successful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lynia-and-aksent-launch/&quot;&gt;launch of the White Marble and Beige Marble products in the Lynia and Aksent series&lt;/a&gt; this past Fall, we are already preparing a slate of  new stone veneer products for the Spring and Summer of 2018.  Of all the new products which are being market tested by some of our global distributors right now, we are most excited about a new large format (up to 30+ inches) single unit smooth face stone planks made from both basalt and lavastone.  Being firmly planted in the light grey to black color palette, these products should be priced similarly to our stacked stone panel products and offer a very modern and architecturally bold look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone Planc Lavastone Stone Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large Format Stone Veneer Strips made of Lavastone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, a planned trip in the Spring to our production facility in Asia promises to set the course for the Fall and Winter of 2018 with products that are currently in the R&amp;amp;D process by our creative team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #2 – Continue to Improve our Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the addition of more product lines to show to our customers, we plan to make our website more user friendly and easier to navigate.  When we first laid down the architecture and theme for the current site we had three product series and eight total products.  With products now well into the 20s with the potential addition of many more in 2018, we’ll look to make navigating between products and galleries easier and more intuitive.  We also are hard at work beta testing a new order process which will allow customers to purchase samples directly from the website 24 hours a day / 7 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone Website Nav.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Norstone's website showing product navigation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #3 – Continue to blog every week and produce content valuable to our customers and the industry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January 20th of this year will mark one year where we’ve been producing, on average, one blog post per week.  We look forward to continuing to produce content for the Norstone line of stacked stone, stone veneer, and stone tile products and for the broader stone, tile, and wall coverings industry as a whole.  We’ll focus even more on our popular “how to” guides, which answer common questions people have about working with stone products, like our very popular post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/&quot;&gt;“How to Install a Flat Screen TV on a Stacked Stone Wall”&lt;/a&gt; as well as our technical posts, which cover a variety of important topics in the stone industry from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/sealing-natural-stone-veneer/&quot;&gt;“The Importance of Sealing Natural Stone Veneer&lt;/a&gt;” to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/waterproofing-membranes-for-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;“Using Waterpoofing Membranes in Exterior Stacked Stone Installations”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone Ivory Stacked Stone Residential Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ivory Stacked Stone Veneer used on Residential Facade project in SW Florida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution #4 - Get feedback and show appreciation to our customers and supporters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to hear from our customers, through email, social media, or any other way we can communicate to get feedback about our stone veneer products and their experiences and interactions with our company and reward loyal customers with return incentives, perks, and bonuses.  Be on the look out here and in our social media channels for updates, flash sales, and give aways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to making 2018 a special year and thank you for being a part of the Norstone stone veneer community!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The team at Norstone and the New Dimensions in Natural Stone blog hope you and yours had an amazing holiday season and very happy new year. In this week's blog we wanted to outline resolutions we've put together to make 2018 the best year for natural stone yet!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/01/03/Norstone%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Basalt%20Tile%20Rooftop%20Terrace.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Rooftop%20Lounge%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Lynia%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20used%20on%20a%20focal%20wall%20in%20an%20upscale%20rooftop%20lounge%20in%20Washington,%20D.C.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grey Aksent 3D Stone on a UK Modern Masterpiece</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-uk-modern-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grey Aksent 3D Stone on a UK Modern Masterpiece" /><published>2017-12-25T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-25T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-stone-on-a-uk-modern-masterpiece</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/grey-aksent-3d-uk-modern-home/">&lt;p&gt;One of the really amazing things about Norstone is our &lt;a href=&quot;http://norstone.global/&quot;&gt;worldwide distribution network&lt;/a&gt;.  With distributors in Australia, Asia, Europe, and the Middle East, we get to see and share the projects we are working on.  It’s cool to see the same stone veneer products get used in a vast range of projects and styles across the globe.  In certain instances, our preconceived notions about what architecture and design look like in a certain area are blown away, which was certainly the case with this project from Southern England.  Situated in an outer suburb of Poole, England, a major shipping lane across the English Channel from the UK to France, this fantastically modern design home which used our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/lynia-and-aksent-launch/&quot;&gt;Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Panels&lt;/a&gt; on the exterior looks like it could have been plucked from a California hillside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer - UK House Facade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer used on the exterior of a modern home in the UK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major things that stands about this project is the contrasting yet natural color range the design team employed throughout. White pavers and knee walls contrast the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/aksent-modern-tiles/grey/&quot;&gt;Grey Stone of the Aksent 3D Panels&lt;/a&gt;, which flow neatly into metal doors and accents, large sections of glass, and wood look large format composite siding.  Set in a heavily wooded area, all of the major colors in the design scheme can be found within a few feet of the buildings themselves.  The great contrast in colors keeps the buildings themselves clean and modern looking, but we’re glad the design team choose to a natural color pallet which will allow this project and design to age gracefully for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The side building in the photo above is a garage that is separated from the home.  What a detached garage might lack for in convenience, this particular one makes up for in design.  With a generous amount of the smooth stone veneer around the garage doors, this outer building compliments the architecture of the main building nicely.  Detaching the garage in this instance also allows for a more uninterrupted use of the property, which sits on a hillside with the rear of the property sitting lower than the front.  While a bunch of fill dirt could have undoubtedly been brought in to level off the lot and leave the rear of the property unusable, we applaud the designer’s choice of separating the buildings and working more within the confines of the lot.  The result – buildings that look amazing and fit nicely within the nicely wooded property and not another McMansion built after a developer knocks all the trees down and levels the ground for fast and easy construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer - UK House Patio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer creating lots of texture on a patio wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are a lot of great materials and products being used on the outer envelope of this home, we think the grey stone veneer has the most powerful impact owing to the abundance of texture the product creates.  With everything else smooth and flat, the Aksent 3D Panel allows for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;clean lined, smooth faced look&lt;/a&gt; to match the other materials, but also gives the walls that dimensional “pop” that comes with stone veneer.  The Aksent 3D panels come with about 1/2” of variation in depth, which is an important dimension to consider when trying to create a dimensional look on a vertical surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer - UK House Garden.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey Stone Veneer used on two buildings seperated by modern landscaping and hardscaping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another really cool design feature of this project is the landscaping / hardscaping.  We really love the large format smooth pebbles used around the house.  Color wise they do a great job tying together the pavers and other elements of the large driveway and create a nice contrast against the grey stone veneer panels.  Texture wise, the smoothness of the rocks parlays nicely with the overall smooth textures found throughout the rest of the exterior, while the semi circular / round shape is a nice foil to the block geometry of the Aksent 3D Panel they but up against.  Large format rectangular smooth concrete pavers form a nice outer ring to the pebble hardscape, reasserting a more traditional shape associated with modern design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking the time to tour this really cool project with us in Southern England.  We love how great our Grey Aksent 3D Stone Veneer Panels look and that our products get to be used on cool projects like this one.  We have a worldwide team of experts ready to answer your stone questions and show you how Norstone natural stone veneer products can work on your next project – rustic or modern, we have the stone to fit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Norstone Aksent 3D panels in Grey are a perfect fit for this modern home in the South of England. Let's take a look at some of what makes this project so special and a great use of this stone veneer project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/12/26/Aksent%203D%20Grey%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20UK%20House%20Facade.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Aksent%203D%20Grey%20Stone%20Veneer%20on%20UK%20Modern%20Home%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Norstone%20Aksent%203D%20Grey%20Stone%20used%20on%20exterior%20of%20modern%20home%20in%20Southern%20England%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Norstone’s Top 5 Stone Fireplaces of 2017</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-fireplaces-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone's Top 5 Stone Fireplaces of 2017" /><published>2017-12-18T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-s-top-5-stone-fireplaces-of-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/top-5-stone-fireplaces-2017/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a great year for the Norstone team and we hope it has been for you too.  In honor of the Christmas season, where the fireplace plays a critical conduit in getting Santa and his presents into our homes, we took a look back at the stone fireplaces we featured on our blog this year, voted on them and present to you Norstone’s top 5 stone fireplaces of 2017!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Two Tone Stacked Stone Fireplace Fort Collins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone fireplace with two types of stone used in an ornate living room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming in at number five on list is this super unique&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/two-toned-modern-fireplace-in-ft-collins-co/&quot;&gt; two toned stone fireplace&lt;/a&gt; in Fort Collins, Colorado.  We’ve seen a ton of stone fireplaces in our time and this is one of the few ones we’ve seen incorporate two different types of surfaces, both stone in this instance, and make it look good.  The blocky geometric look of our Aksent 3D Panels in Ash Grey flanks a vertical stripe of lighter greyish creamy colored stone.  The colors work well with the décor of this beautifully decorated space and the vertical nature of the stripe accentuates the already high ceiling in the room.  Bravo to the team at Springhaus Interiors out of Fort Collins on this great job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Grey Basalt Aksent Ledge Stone Fireplace Kansas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Aksent 3D Grey used on a fireplace with lots of detail including recessed tv, fireplace, and built in shelves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number four fireplace on our list is another cool &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/3d-ledge-stone-kansas/&quot;&gt;fireplace application of the Aksent 3D panels in Ash Grey&lt;/a&gt;, that just exudes detail.  With stone going wall to wall in the application, the recessed linear gas fireplace is almost lost a midst a recessed flat screen tv and built in shelves with under-mount lighting.  The one thing that really sets this project apart is actually the extensive use of our outside corner units which give a seamless look as the fireplace projects out from the wall and then turns back towards the recessed fireplace insert and tv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Modern Living Room with Lynia Tile Fireplace in Chicago.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large stone tile fireplace in modern designed living room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third on our list of the best stacked stone fireplaces is this cool &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stone-fireplace-chicago/&quot;&gt;Ebony Lynia IL Tile fireplace in Chicago&lt;/a&gt;.  Even though this is a really big fireplace with stone going floor to ceiling and probably close to 8 feet wide, the smooth texture of the Lynia tiles doesn’t over power the space and compliments the long linear nature of the gas insert as well.  The modern styled décor is perfectly matched to the dark ebony color of the stone and the smooth texture of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Ochre Stacked Stone Fireplace - Austin, TX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two way stacked stone fireplace that can be seen both inside and outside&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we certainly saw a surging trend towards stone with darker colors and smoother textures in 2017, we couldn’t help but admire this awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ochre-ochre-everywhere-in-this-magnificent-austin-tx-modern-home/&quot;&gt;stacked stone fireplace application in Austin, TX&lt;/a&gt;, which comes in at number two on our list.  Although not meant to be the focal point of this dining room, this pass through fireplace going from the inside to an exterior seating area is a super cool feature that we just couldn’t pass up giving some love to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/20/Ebony Basalt Lynia Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Bold Color Accents-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern basalt stone tile fireplace with large tv and bright color accents in the space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the top ranked stone fireplace of 2017, as voted on by the team here at Norstone, is this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge/&quot;&gt;super cool Ebony Lynia IL Stone Tile fireplace in Philadelphia&lt;/a&gt;.  The sheer size of the stone wall, the massive length of the fireplace, the cool cut outs, and funky accent color scheme all come together in this superb installation.  The durability of the stone is both practical and durable for this application in the common area of student housing at a local university, and cool enough to impress both prospective students and their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoyed our list of the top 5 stone fireplaces of 2017 and wish you and yours a tremendous holiday season and an awesome new year in 2018.  And no matter how great it might look, remember to turn off those fireplaces on December 24th so our friend in the red suit can make his annual visit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">In honor of Jolly Old St. Nick, who's made a name for himself coming through fireplaces, here are our top 5 stone fireplaces of 2017. Santa will be sure lucky if he gets to visit one of these houses in a few nights and might even pause to admire how great they look!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/12/20/Ebony%20Basalt%20Lynia%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Bold%20Color%20Accents.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Norstone's%20Top%205%20Stone%20Fireplaces%20of%202017%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22The%20top%205%20stone%20fireplaces%20of%202017%20as%20voted%20on%20by%20the%20team%20at%20Norstone%22%7D" /></entry></feed>